<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<timelineData>

    <links>
        <smallThumb url="http://www.thememoryproject.com/VeteranAssets/Artifact/Thumb_Small/" />
        <vetProfile url="http://www.thememoryproject.com/Stories/Veteran-Profile.aspx?itemid=" />
    </links>
    
    <events>

        <event date="08/05/1945" img="bcs.jpg">
            <text>Victory in Europe Day (VE-Day) is declared, ending the European portion of the Second World War</text>
            <vet id="1065">Helen Rochon</vet>
            <vet id="1096">Hubert Lalonde</vet>
            <vet id="1297">Norman Wrigglesworth</vet>
            <vet id="1368">Marguerite Plante</vet>
            <vet id="1738">Art Meyer</vet>
            <vet id="2313">Peggy Lee</vet>
            <vet id="1528">Bill Ramsbottom</vet>
            <vet id="1176">Rex Fendick</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="24/09/1940" img="axl.jpg">
            <text>Her Majesty's Canadian ships Annapolis, Columbia, Niagara, St. Clair, St. Croix and St. Francis, ex-American destroyers from the fifty given to Great Britain in exchange for bases, are commissioned into the Royal Canadian Navy</text>
            <vet id="1069">Tom Rappel</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="22/07/1940" img="3cg.jpg">
            <text>The British Commonwealth Air Training Plan begins operations when students began training at No. 1 Service Flying Training School at Camp Borden, Ontario</text>
            <vet id="1339">Russell Smith</vet>
            <vet id="1123">Bill Watterson</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="11/02/1944" img="3kh.jpg">
            <text>a Wellington bomber of No.407 Squadron, Royal Canadian Air Force, sinks the German submarine U-283 in the North Atlantic</text>
            <vet id="2288">Ross Hamilton</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/09/1939" img="lus.jpg">
            <text>the 1st and 2nd Canadian Divisions are authorized as the Canadian Active Service Force.  The Royal Canadian Navy, Royal Canadian Navy Reserve and Royal Canadian Navy Volunteer Reserve are placed on active service</text>
            <vet id="1452">Frank John Dion</vet>
            <vet id="2271">John A Cathie</vet>
            <vet id="2295">Rudy Deutsch</vet>
            <vet id="2270">John Bilyk</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="04/09/1939" img="cfc.jpg">
            <text>Pilot Officer S.R. Henderson, a Canadian serving in No.206 Squadron, Royal Air Force, becomes the first Canadian to participate in an operational sortie during the Second World War when he serves as the lead navigator in a bomber force attacking German warships</text>
            <vet id="1050">Malcolm Andrade</vet>
            <vet id="2190">Rodolphe Lavoie</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="10/09/1939" img="u1p.jpg">
            <text>Canada declares war on Germany</text>
            <vet id="1345">James Duncan Ritchie</vet>
            <vet id="2241">John Leach</vet>
            <vet id="2230">Joan Bennett Johnson, nee Cobb</vet>
            <vet id="1478">Geoffrey Alington</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="16/09/1939" img="blc.jpg">
            <text>convoy HX-1 sails from Halifax for Great Britain with a local escort including HMCS St. Laurent and HMCS Saguenay</text>
            <vet id="1154">John Covan</vet>
            <vet id="2137">Louis Henry Howard</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="19/09/1939" img="t0r.jpg">
            <text>the Honourable Norman McLeod Rogers is appointed Minister of National Defence</text>
            <vet id="1104">Mike Hawryliw</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="30/09/1939" img="xit.jpg">
            <text>S/L W.I. Clements, attached to No.53 (Blenheim) Squadron, Royal Air Force, becomes the first member of the Royal Canadian Air Force to fly over enemy territory when his squadron makes a long distance reconnaissance flight over Germany</text>
            <vet id="1307">Malcolm Maconnell</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="06/11/1939" img="d1r.jpg">
            <text>the formation of the Organization and Training Division at RCAF headquarters is authorized</text>
            <vet id="1102">Harold Emery Bronson</vet>
            <vet id="1059">Ernest Peter Bone</vet>
            <vet id="1108">Mervyn Couse</vet>
            <vet id="1111">Geraldine Muter</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="10/12/1939" img="vkc.jpg">
            <text>the first Canadian troop convoy sails for Britain escorted out of Halifax by HMC ships Ottawa, Restigouche, Fraser and St. Laurent</text>
            <vet id="1119">Donald McIntosh</vet>
            <vet id="1154">John Covan</vet>
            <vet id="1220">C. James Alward</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="17/12/1939" img="smf.jpg">
            <text>the first group of the 1st Canadian Infantry Division arrives in the United Kingdom</text>
            <vet id="2271">John A Cathie</vet>
            <vet id="1384">Gordon Bannerman</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="17/12/1939" img="qnp.jpg">
            <text>the governments of the United Kingdom, Canada, Australia and New Zealand sign an agreement to establish the British Commonwealth Air Training Plan under the supervision of the Royal Canadian Air Force</text>
            <vet id="1059">Ernest Peter Bone</vet>
            <vet id="1129">Cecil Edward Hancock</vet>
            <vet id="1118">Brian MacConnell</vet>
            <vet id="1226">Joseph Preston Hawkins</vet>
            <vet id="1386">Glennis Marie Boyce</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="31/12/1939" img="wup.jpg">
            <text>the second section of the 1st Canadian Infantry Division arrives in the United Kingdom</text>
            <vet id="1384">Gordon Bannerman</vet>
            <vet id="2271">John A Cathie</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="02/01/1940" img="q4m.jpg">
            <text>the awarding of Distinguished Flying Cross (each) to two Canadians serving in the Royal Air Force, Pilot-Officer S.R. Henderson and Wing-Commander J.F. Griffiths, is announced.  They are the first Canadians to be decorated during the Second World War</text>
            <vet id="1135">Norman Dawber</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="08/02/1940" img="hqp.jpg">
            <text>the third Canadian Contingent arrives in Great Britain</text>
            <vet id="2271">John Cathie</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="14/02/1940" img="ps4.jpg">
            <text>No.110 (Army Co-Operation) Squadron sails from Halifax for Britain where it arrives on 25 February, the first Canadian air force squadron to reach Great Britain</text>
            <vet id="1294">William Kondra</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="15/04/1940" img="5pw.jpg">
            <text>No. 1 Initial Training School is opened in Toronto to provide the first training for British Commonwealth Air Training Plan students</text>
            <vet id="1536">Eric Stanley Hawley</vet>
            <vet id="1102">Harold Emery Bronson</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="29/04/1940" img="cvb.jpg">
            <text>No. 1 Air Navigation School was formed at Trenton, Ontario, to provide navigation training for British Commonwealth Air Training Plan students</text>
            <vet id="1404">Donald Stevenson</vet>
            <vet id="1111">Geraldine Muter</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="21/05/1940" img="uya.jpg">
            <text>the first members of No. 112 (Army Co-Operation) Squadron, based in Winnipeg, sail from Canada for Liverpool where they arrive eight days later as the second Royal Canadian Air Force squadron overseas</text>
            <vet id="1315">William Gelineau</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="24/05/1940" img="lcf.jpg">
            <text>HMS ships St. Laurent, Restigouche and Skeena sail from Halifax for Britain to join the Allied naval defence forces</text>
            <vet id="1397">Jack Smallwood</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="27/05/1940" img="ped.jpg">
            <text>No. 1 Air Observer School is opened in Malton, Ontario, to train British Commonwealth Air Training Plan students in air observation duties</text>
            <vet id="1502">Ray Sowerby</vet>
            <vet id="1129">Cecil Edward Hancock</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="06/06/1940" img="nac.jpg">
            <text>Canadian warships come under fire for the first time when HMCS St. Laurent and HMCS Restigouche encounter German warships at St. Valery en Caux</text>
            <vet id="1325">Harold Harden</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="08/06/1940" img="tep.jpg">
            <text>No. 1 (Fighter) Squadron sails from Halifax for Great Britain</text>
            <vet id="2695">Lorne Yule</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="10/06/1940" img="qbl.jpg">
            <text>the Canadian government declares war on Italy</text>
            <vet id="1291">Paul-Emile Lamouche</vet>
            <vet id="1380">William Adelman</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="11/06/1940" img="2e1.jpg">
            <text>HMCS St. Laurent and HMCS Restigouche evacuate military personnel from Le Havre, France, exchanging gunfire with German artillery batteries in the process</text>
            <vet id="1477">Donald Green</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="16/06/1940" img="l2l.jpg">
            <text>Canadian troops board transport vessels in St. Malo and Brest to leave France for England after the aborted attempt to support the British and French armies</text>
            <vet id="1092">Edward Borland</vet>
            <vet id="2528">Victor Guerin</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="22/06/1940" img="3sg.jpg">
            <text>the last class of Royal Canadian Navy Volunteer Reserve officers graduate from HMCS Stone Frigate</text>
            <vet id="2529">Frederick Gray</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="25/06/1940" img="inm.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Fraser is lost after colliding with a British warship, HMS Calcutta in the Bay of Biscay</text>
            <vet id="1220">C James Alward</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="02/07/1940" img="2mp.jpg">
            <text>861 German and Italian prisoners of war are rescued by HMCS St. Laurent after their transport ship was torpedoed on its way to Canada</text>
            <vet id="1325">Harold Harden</vet>
            <vet id="1321">Robert Kerr</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="09/07/1940" img="2u4.jpg">
            <text>Les Fusiliers Mont-Royal and The Cameron Highlanders of Ottawa arrive in Iceland to complete the Canadian >Z= Force stationed there</text>
            <vet id="1317">Jean Marie Ademare Milot</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="17/07/1940" img="kgx.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Skeena rescues the crew of a torpedoed merchant ship, the SS Manipor, in the waters north of Scotland</text>
            <vet id="1397">Jack Smallwood</vet>
            <vet id="1070">Frank Aldred</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="13/08/1940" img="5vv.jpg">
            <text>the Canadian Armoured Corps is authorized</text>
            <vet id="1316">Robert Routledge</vet>
            <vet id="1345">James Duncan Ritchie</vet>
            <vet id="2298">Gordon Wright</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="20/10/1940" img="m5a.jpg">
            <text>HMS Windflower, the first corvette built in Canada, is commissioned into the Royal Navy with a Canadian crew.  She is turned over to the Royal Canadian Navy in 1941</text>
            <vet id="2525">Georges Charrier</vet>
            <vet id="1119">Donald McIntosh</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="22/10/1940" img="kzs.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Margaree is lost in a collision with SS Port Fairy in the North Atlantic</text>
            <vet id="1493">Ron Rhine</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="25/10/1940" img="vkc.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Bras D'Or founders in the North Atlantic</text>
            <vet id="1119">Donald McIntosh</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="31/10/1940" img="cyw.jpg">
            <text>AZ@ Force, with the exception of The Cameron Highlanders of Ottawa, sails from Iceland for Great Britain</text>
            <vet id="1141">Charles Scott</vet>
            <vet id="1139">John Rankin Stephens</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="09/11/1940" img="5ux.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Collingwood, the first corvette built in Canada for the RCN, is commissioned</text>
            <vet id="1077">Harvey Burns</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="24/11/1940" img="wxm.jpg">
            <text>the first draft of British Commonwealth Air Training Plan graduates arrive in England for service</text>
            <vet id="1111">Geraldine Muter</vet>
            <vet id="1798">David Macdonald</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="04/12/1940" img="cxs.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Prince Henry is commissioned as an Armed Merchant Cruiser</text>
            <vet id="1070">Frank Aldred</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="13/12/1940" img="mvi.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Royal Roads is commissioned as a training establishment for Probationary Sub-Lieutenants</text>
            <vet id="1418">Eric Gordon Jensen</vet>
            <vet id="2137">Louis Henry Howard</vet>
            <vet id="2248">Ruby Somers</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="25/12/1940" img="1ny.jpg">
            <text>1st Canadian Corps is formed in the United Kingdom under the command of Lieutenant-General A.G.L. McNaughton</text>
            <vet id="2193">Leslie Eugene Clarke</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="28/12/1940" img="qla.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Prince David is commissioned as an Armed Merchant Cruiser</text>
            <vet id="1324">Fred Linnington</vet>
            <vet id="1161">George Evans</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="07/01/1941" img="pkd.jpg">
            <text>a Commonwealth agreement of 17 December 1939 provides for the future establishment of purely Canadian air force units for newly-trained Canadians to join in Europe</text>
            <vet id="1118">Brian MacConnell</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="09/02/1941" img="3vi.jpg">
            <text>the 5th Canadian Motorcycle Regiment, CASF, (BCD) is converted and redesignated The British Columbia Dragoons</text>
            <vet id="1045">Helen Jean Crawley</vet>
            <vet id="1321">Robert Kerr</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="24/03/1941" img="0pv.jpg">
            <text>the Rush-Bagot Agreement of 1817, which restricted the number of naval vessels allowed on the Great Lakes, is modified to allow both American and Canadian naval vessels to operate on the Great Lakes in greater numbers</text>
            <vet id="2285">Warren Urquhart</vet>
            <vet id="2529">Frederick Lawrence Gray</vet>
            <vet id="1066">Carol Duffus</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="25/03/1941" img="i5y.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Otter burns and sinks in the approaches to Halifax</text>
            <vet id="1119">Donald McIntosh</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="25/05/1941" img="52k.jpg">
            <text>seven Royal Canadian Navy corvettes arrive in St. John's, Newfoundland, to begin operations as the Newfoundland Escort Force</text>
            <vet id="1216">Murray Copot</vet>
            <vet id="2387">Edwin Badger</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="13/06/1941" img="x51.jpg">
            <text>Newfoundland's sea defences are brought under Canadian control with the appointment of Commodore L.W. Murray, RCN, as the commander of Newfoundland Force</text>
            <vet id="2378">Lawrence Weldon</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="14/06/1941" img="mum.jpg">
            <text>warships of the Newfoundland Escort Force begin convoy escort operations in the North Atlantic Ocean</text>
            <vet id="1429">John Potter</vet>
            <vet id="1141">Charles Scott</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="26/06/1941" img="umr.jpg">
            <text>the Canadian government announces its intention to form a Canadian Women's Army Corps</text>
            <vet id="1074">Corinne Sevigny</vet>
            <vet id="1062">Elizabeth Dimock</vet>
            <vet id="2177">Alice Marie Samuel</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="30/06/1941" img="pvp.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Wasaga is commissioned, becoming the first Canadian-built Bangor-class minesweeper</text>
            <vet id="1341">Ralph Taylor</vet>
            <vet id="1495">Bruce Findlay</vet>
            <vet id="2436">Alfred Carpenter</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="02/07/1941" img="rra.jpg">
            <text>the Canadian Women's Auxiliary Air Force is authorized, later becoming the Royal Canadian Air Force (Women's Division)</text>
            <vet id="1163">Margaret Brownlee</vet>
            <vet id="1217">Ella Curtis</vet>
            <vet id="1386">Glennis Boyce</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="09/08/1941" img="gzu.jpg">
            <text>HMC Ships Assiniboine and Restigouche escort HMS Prince of Wales, with Prime Minister Winston Churchill aboard, into Placentia Bay, Newfoundland</text>
            <vet id="1821">Harold MacLauchlin</vet>
            <vet id="2137">Louis Henry Howard</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="13/08/1941" img="i5s.jpg">
            <text>the Canadian Women's Army Corps is authorized</text>
            <vet id="2177">Alice Marie Samuel</vet>
            <vet id="1298">Grace Breau-Theriault</vet>
            <vet id="1049">Olive Peat</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="10/09/1941" img="po5.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Chambly and HMCS Moose Jaw sink the German submarine U-501 off the coast of Greenland.  This is the first U-boat kill made by the Royal Canadian Navy</text>
            <vet id="1314">Jim Peters</vet>
            <vet id="1161">George Evans</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="19/09/1941" img="u5h.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Levis (a corvette) is torpedoed and sunk in the North Atlantic</text>
            <vet id="1119">Donald McIntosh</vet>
            <vet id="1161">George Evans</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="22/09/1941" img="i3z.jpg">
            <text>the University Air Training Squadrons are formed</text>
            <vet id="1118">Brian MacConnell</vet>
            <vet id="1059">Ernest Bone</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="27/10/1941" img="cxn.jpg">
            <text>AC@ Force (Canadian troops under the command of Brigadier J.K. Lawson) sails from Vancouver for Hong Kong</text>
            <vet id="2266">Clyde Bougie</vet>
            <vet id="1541">Arthur Gillan</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="10/11/1941" img="xrg.jpg">
            <text>the RCAF is awarded its first George Cross when LAC K.M. Gravell is posthumously awarded the decoration for the attempt to rescue his pilot from their crashed Tiger Moth aircraft</text>
            <vet id="1229">Douglas Drew</vet>
            <vet id="1102">Harold Bronson</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="13/11/1941" img="vgf.jpg">
            <text>the 1st Armoured Car Regiment (Royal Canadian Dragoons) sails from Canada for Britain as part of the 5th Canadian Armoured Division</text>
            <vet id="1517">Arthur Robert Henry Lyon</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="26/11/1941" img="nac.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Halifax is commissioned into the RCN</text>
            <vet id="1325">Harold Harden</vet>
            <vet id="1314">Jim Peters</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="07/12/1941" img="lmc.jpg">
            <text>Canada declares war on Romania, Hungary, Finland and Japan</text>
            <vet id="2291">Godfrey Schaupmeyer</vet>
            <vet id="1448">Otto Hemmerling</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="07/12/1941" img="ksu.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Windflower is lost after a collision with SS Zypenburg on the Grand Banks of Newfoundland</text>
            <vet id="1216">Murray Copot</vet>
            <vet id="1483">Henry Mason</vet>
            <vet id="1271">Leonard Whiffen</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="08/12/1941" img="0iw.jpg">
            <text>the United States, Great Britain and other nations declare war on Japan</text>
            <vet id="2310">Victor Wong</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="19/12/1941" img="euj.jpg">
            <text>gallantry shown by Company Sergeant-Major J.R. Osborn, Royal Winnipeg Grenadiers, in action against the Japanese at Hong Kong on this date led to the posthumous award of the Victoria Cross</text>
            <vet id="2270">John Bylik</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="25/12/1941" img="r04.jpg">
            <text>Hong Kong surrenders to the Japanese forces</text>
            <vet id="1049">Olive Peat</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="03/02/1942" img="l3r.jpg">
            <text>the Canadian Women's Auxiliary Air Force is renamed the Royal Canadian Air Force (Women's Division)</text>
            <vet id="1386">Glennis Boyce</vet>
            <vet id="2384">Catherine Anderson</vet>
            <vet id="1465">Ruby Foley</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="11/02/1942" img="wi1.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Spikenard is torpedoed and sunk in the North Atlantic</text>
            <vet id="1161">George Evans</vet>
            <vet id="1119">Donald McIntosh</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="12/02/1942" img="ewr.jpg">
            <text>nine Canadian squadrons (four bomber, four fighter and one coastal) take part in the chase of three German warships in the AChannel Dash@</text>
            <vet id="1070">Frank Aldred</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/03/1942" img="uak.jpg">
            <text>the Canadian Women's Army Corps is granted full Army status as "a Corps of the Active Militia of Canada"</text>
            <vet id="1224">Doris Wallace</vet>
            <vet id="2177">Alice Samuel</vet>
            <vet id="2499">Joan Manning</vet>
            <vet id="2211">Doreen Newton</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="04/03/1942" img="irh.jpg">
            <text>the first Canadian 'Cruiser' tanks arrive in England</text>
            <vet id="2241">John Leach</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="18/03/1942" img="1hw.jpg">
            <text>No.413 Squadron begins its transfer from the Shetland Isles to Ceylon to strengthen Allied air defences in the Pacific</text>
            <vet id="2395">Ian Herd</vet>
            <vet id="1068">Bob Farquharson</vet>
            <vet id="1125">Ed Pearson</vet>
            <vet id="1494">Lewis Chow</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="04/04/1942" img="mmk.jpg">
            <text>Squadron Leader L.J. Birchall and his crew, flying a PBY-5 flying boat, spot a Japanese naval force heading for the island of Ceylon.  Their warning allowed the island's defenders to prepare for the Japanese attempt to take the island, an attack which fails.  Birchall is later known as "The Saviour of Ceylon"</text>
            <vet id="2395">Ian Herd</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="05/04/1942" img="mlp.jpg">
            <text>at least fifteen Canadian members of the Royal Canadian Air Force and the Royal Air Force help the Ceylonese defend the island against the Japanese attempt to conquer it</text>
            <vet id="2395">Ian Herd</vet>
            <vet id="1125">Ed Pearson</vet>
            <vet id="2228">Donovan Woelfle</vet>
            <vet id="2193">Leslie Clarke</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="13/04/1942" img="qqs.jpg">
            <text>No. 417 (Spitfire) Squadron, Royal Canadian Air Force, is transferred from Great Britain to Egypt to support the Allied operations in the Middle East</text>
            <vet id="1229">Douglas Drew</vet>
            <vet id="1337">Geoffrey Jell</vet>
            <vet id="1067">Hubert Gray</vet>
            <vet id="2459">Oscar Fiteni</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="24/07/1942" img="myb.jpg">
            <text>HMCS St. Croix sinks the German submarine U-90 while on patrol in the North Atlantic Ocean</text>
            <vet id="1119">Donald McIntosh</vet>
            <vet id="2325">Leonard Bookbinder</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="31/07/1942" img="qpl.jpg">
            <text>the Women's Royal Canadian Naval Service is authorized</text>
            <vet id="1066">Carol Duffus</vet>
            <vet id="1327">Olive Henderson</vet>
            <vet id="2248">Ruby Somers</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="31/07/1942" img="ewr.jpg">
            <text>HMC Ships Wetaskiwin and Skeena sink the German submarine U-588 while on patrol in the North Atlantic Ocean</text>
            <vet id="1397">Jack Smallwood</vet>
            <vet id="1070">Frank Aldred</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="06/08/1942" img="4ly.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Assiniboine sinks the German submarine U-210 while on patrol in the North Atlantic Ocean</text>
            <vet id="1821">Harold MacLauchlin</vet>
            <vet id="2298">Gordon Wright</vet>
            <vet id="1312">Norman Silver</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="19/08/1942" img="opx.jpg">
            <text>a primarily Canadian force conducts a disastrous large-scale raid on the French coastal town of Dieppe</text>
            <vet id="1225">Douglas Warren</vet>
            <vet id="1423">Jacques Nadeau</vet>
            <vet id="1042">George Burrows</vet>
            <vet id="1085">Leonard Allbon</vet>
            <vet id="1231">Jean Marcel D'Aoust</vet>
            <vet id="1412">Armond Emond</vet>
            <vet id="2515">Roland Gravel</vet>
            <vet id="1058">Douglas Annis</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="20/08/1942" img="cxn.jpg">
            <text>HMC Ships Prince Robert, Prince Henry, Prince David, Dawson and Vancouver leave Esquimalt, British Columbia, to commence operations in the Bering Sea</text>
            <vet id="1070">Frank Aldred</vet>
            <vet id="2137">Louis Henry Howard</vet>
            <vet id="1541">Arthur Gillan</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="28/08/1942" img="5mb.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Oakville works with American aircraft to sink the German submarine U-94 in the Caribbean Sea</text>
            <vet id="1161">George Evans</vet>
            <vet id="1070">Frank Aldred</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="07/09/1942" img="mz2.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Raccoon (an armed yacht) is torpedoed and sunk, with the loss of all hands, in the Gulf of St. Lawrence</text>
            <vet id="1154">John Covan</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="11/09/1942" img="vkc.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Charlottetown (corvette) is torpedoed and sunk in the St. Lawrence</text>
            <vet id="1119">Donald McIntosh</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="13/09/1942" img="1ax.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Ottawa is torpedoed and sunk in the North Atlantic</text>
            <vet id="1138">Adeline Bowland</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="16/09/1942" img="5ux.jpg">
            <text>the first of sixteen Royal Canadian Navy corvettes sails for the Mediterranean Sea to take part in the North African landings (Operation Torch)</text>
            <vet id="1077">Harvey Burns</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="28/09/1942" img="hqt.jpg">
            <text>a No.111 Squadron aircraft, Royal Canadian Air Force, flown by S/L K.A. Boomer, destroys a Japanese ARufe@ seaplane over Kiska.  This is the only air combat fought by the RCAF in the North American theatre</text>
            <vet id="1135">Norman Dawber</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="15/10/1942" img="isp.jpg">
            <text>the Northwest Staging Route is formed as a unit to help connect Alaska and the Yukon by air with supply centres</text>
            <vet id="1506">Philip Zeman</vet>
            <vet id="1219">Bruce Agnew</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="21/10/1942" img="wow.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Royal Roads becomes the Royal Canadian Naval College and commences training cadets</text>
            <vet id="1066">Carol Duffus</vet>
            <vet id="1034">James Brown</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="29/10/1942" img="5rp.jpg">
            <text>the Canadian Intelligence Corps is authorized</text>
            <vet id="1082">Margarita Trull</vet>
            <vet id="1494">Lewis Chow</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="16/12/1942" img="qxx.jpg">
            <text>the active service battalion of the 12th Manitoba Dragoons is redesignated the "18th Armoured Car Regiment (12th Manitoba Dragoons)"</text>
            <vet id="1517">Arthur Robert Henry Lyon</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="29/12/1942" img="ksu.jpg">
            <text>HMC Ships St. Laurent, Chilliwack, Battleford and Napanee sink the German submarine U-356 in the mid-Atlantic</text>
            <vet id="1483">Henry Mason</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="04/01/1943" img="ylwfajesabcgzylkdrzp.jpg">
            <text>six bombers from No. 427 Squadron, Royal Canadian Air Force, carry out No.6 (RCAF) Bomber Group's first operation, laying mines near the Frisian Islands</text>
            <vet id="2212">Clinton Hayward</vet>
            <vet id="1102">Harold Bronson</vet>
            <vet id="2460">Weldon Moffatt</vet>
            <vet id="1067">Hubert Gray</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="04/01/1943" img="5tt.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Prince Henry is recommissioned as Landing Ship Infantry (Medium)</text>
            <vet id="1070">Frank Aldred</vet>
            <vet id="1080">Cyril Roach</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="05/01/1943" img="qfg.jpg">
            <text>a Canadian Army detachment arrives in North Africa</text>
            <vet id="1209">Lawrence Wagg</vet>
            <vet id="1062">Elizabeth Dimock</vet>
            <vet id="1337">Geoffrey Jell</vet>
            <vet id="1323">Andre-Paul Turin</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="13/01/1943" img="ekh.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Ville de Quebec sinks the German submarine U-224 in the western Mediterranean Sea</text>
            <vet id="1060">J.A. Rene Brunette</vet>
            <vet id="1154">John Covan</vet>
            <vet id="2387">Edwin Badger</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="19/01/1943" img="guf.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Port Arthur sinks the Italian Submarine Tritone in the Mediterranean Sea</text>
            <vet id="1077">Harvey Burns</vet>
            <vet id="2285">Warren Urquhart</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="02/02/1943" img="1xz.jpg">
            <text>the second group of Canadian troops arrive in North Africa</text>
            <vet id="1323">Andre-Paul Turin</vet>
            <vet id="2459">Oscar Fiteni</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="06/02/1943" img="gcq.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Louisbourg is torpedoed and sunk by enemy aircraft in an attack on a convoy in the Mediterranean Sea</text>
            <vet id="1138">Adeline Bowland</vet>
            <vet id="1161">George Evans</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="08/02/1943" img="mgf.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Regina sinks the Italian submarine Avorio in the Mediterranean Sea</text>
            <vet id="1119">Donald McIntosh</vet>
            <vet id="2529">Frederick Gray</vet>
            <vet id="1429">John Potter</vet>
            <vet id="1314">Jim Peters</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="22/02/1943" img="j2y.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Weyburn strikes a mine and sinks off Tangier</text>
            <vet id="2436">Alfred Carpenter</vet>
            <vet id="1398">James Smitherman</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="04/03/1943" img="w20.jpg">
            <text>HMC Ships Shediac and St. Croix sink the German submarine     U-87 in the North Atlantic</text>
            <vet id="1060">J.A. Brunette</vet>
            <vet id="1477">Donald Green</vet>
            <vet id="2298">Gordon Wright</vet>
            <vet id="2387">Edwin Badger</vet>
            <vet id="1320">Ernest Randle</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="22/04/1943" img="pkd.jpg">
            <text>the Air Cadet Corps is made a part of the Royal Canadian Air Force</text>
            <vet id="1225">Douglas Warren</vet>
            <vet id="1111">Geraldine Muter</vet>
            <vet id="1118">Brian MacConnell</vet>
            <vet id="2512">Romuald Pepin</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="30/04/1943" img="iep.jpg">
            <text>the Flag Officer Atlantic Coast, Royal Canadian Navy, takes over control of all shipping movements in the western North Atlantic under the title of Commander-in-Chief Canadian North West Atlantic</text>
            <vet id="2228">Donovan Woelfle</vet>
            <vet id="1139">John Stephen</vet>
            <vet id="1081">Jack Stapleton</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="13/05/1943" img="dez.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Drumheller, HMS Lagan and an aircraft from the Royal Canadian Air Force's 423 Squadron combine to sink the German submarine U-753 in the Atlantic Ocean</text>
            <vet id="2298">Gordon Wright</vet>
            <vet id="2387">Edwin Badger</vet>
            <vet id="1320">Ernest Randle</vet>
            <vet id="1811">Fraser Muir</vet>
            <vet id="2327">Robert O'Conner</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/06/1943" img="ybn.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Conestoga is commissioned in Galt, Ontario, as the Women's Royal Canadian Naval Service training establishment</text>
            <vet id="1066">Carol Duffus</vet>
            <vet id="1327">Olive Henderson</vet>
            <vet id="2248">Ruby Somers</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="06/06/1943" img="1il.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Prince Robert is recommissioned as an anti-aircraft cruiser</text>
            <vet id="1150">Thomas Atherton</vet>
            <vet id="1161">George Evans</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="16/06/1943" img="uqs.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Waskesiu is commissioned into the Royal Canadian Navy, becoming the first of sixty RCN frigates built in Canada</text>
            <vet id="2270">John Bilyk</vet>
            <vet id="1060">J.A Brunette</vet>
            <vet id="1452">Frank Dion</vet>
            <vet id="1527">Frank Moore</vet>
            <vet id="1821">Harold Maclauchlan</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="24/06/1943" img="j2y.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Sault Ste. Marie is commissioned as the first Algerine-class minesweeper produced for the Royal Canadian Navy</text>
            <vet id="1341">Ralph Taylor</vet>
            <vet id="1495">Bruce Findlay</vet>
            <vet id="2436">Alfred Carpenter</vet>
            <vet id="1398">James Smitherman</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="04/07/1943" img="nkr.jpg">
            <text>Canadian vessels of the 29th and 65th Motor Torpedo Boat Flotillas conduct raids on the French coast near Cherbourg</text>
            <vet id="1493">Ron Rhine</vet>
            <vet id="1398">James Smitherman</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="10/07/1943" img="smf.jpg">
            <text>Canadian landing craft drop soldiers of the 1st Canadian Division off on the coast of Sicily during the Allied invasion known as Operation Husky</text>
            <vet id="2271">John Cathie</vet>
            <vet id="2205">Leraine Munn</vet>
            <vet id="1371">Charles Ross</vet>
            <vet id="1466">Brian Murphy</vet>
            <vet id="2333">Maurice White</vet>
            <vet id="1322">Leonidas Lemaire</vet>
            <vet id="1058">Douglas Annis</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="12/07/1943" img="zey.jpg">
            <text>Flying Officer J.H. Turnbull, a No. 600 Royal Air Force Squadron Beaufighter pilot, shoots down three German Ju-88 bombers over Sicily</text>
            <vet id="1357">Alan Smith</vet>
            <vet id="2327">Robert O'Conner</vet>
            <vet id="2458">Wendell Harper</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="04/08/1943" img="53f.jpg">
            <text>a Sunderland flying boat from No. 423 Squadron, Royal Canadian Air Force, sinks the German submarine U-489</text>
            <vet id="1811">Fraser Muir</vet>
            <vet id="2327">Robert O'Conner</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="15/08/1943" img="i22.jpg">
            <text>American and Canadian forces occupy the island of Kiska in the Aleutians</text>
            <vet id="1201">Robert Atkins</vet>
            <vet id="1312">Norman Silver</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="17/08/1943" img="1t5.jpg">
            <text>the campaign in Sicily is successfully completed with the capture of the town of Messina</text>
            <vet id="1371">Charles Ross</vet>
            <vet id="2271">John Cathie</vet>
            <vet id="1322">Leonidas Lemaire</vet>
            <vet id="1058">Douglas Annis</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="03/09/1943" img="0nw.jpg">
            <text>Italy is invaded by Allied troops</text>
            <vet id="1466">Brian Murphy</vet>
            <vet id="2333">Maurice White</vet>
            <vet id="2205">Leraine Munn</vet>
            <vet id="1371">Charles Ross</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="06/09/1943" img="jxj.jpg">
            <text>beginning on this date and over the next four weeks Royal Canadian Air Force aircraft destroy four U-boats in the Atlantic Ocean</text>
            <vet id="2288">Ross Hamilton</vet>
            <vet id="2298">Gordon Wright</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="07/09/1943" img="vjf.jpg">
            <text>HMS Nabob (an aircraft carrier) is commissioned into the Royal Navy with a Canadian crew and a Royal Air Force complement</text>
            <vet id="1398">James Smitherman</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="20/09/1943" img="205.jpg">
            <text>HMCS St. Croix (a destroyer) is torpedoed and sunk south of Iceland, the first victim of an acoustic torpedo</text>
            <vet id="1220">C Alward</vet>
            <vet id="1070">Frank Aldred</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="21/10/1943" img="guf.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Chedabucto collides with the cable ship Lord Kelvin in the Gulf of St. Lawrence.  She is later beached and becomes a total loss</text>
            <vet id="2285">Warren Urquhart</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="20/11/1943" img="kgx.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Snowberry, Calgary and Nene sink U-536 in the North Atlantic</text>
            <vet id="1070">Frank Aldred</vet>
            <vet id="1161">George Evans</vet>
            <vet id="1397">Jack Smallwood</vet>
            <vet id="1060">J. A Brunette</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="20/12/1943" img="1kz.jpg">
            <text>Canadian troops begin their attack on the Italian town of Ortona, an attack successfully completed on 28 December</text>
            <vet id="1345">James Ritchie</vet>
            <vet id="1488">Arthur Brown</vet>
            <vet id="2333">Maurice White</vet>
            <vet id="1466">Brian Murphy</vet>
            <vet id="1515">Rod McNeill</vet>
            <vet id="2286">Bill Teleske</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="20/12/1943" img="gl4.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Prince David is recommissioned as a Landing Ship Infantry (Medium)</text>
            <vet id="1080">Cyril Roach</vet>
            <vet id="1070">Frank Aldred</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="23/12/1943" img="uqs.jpg">
            <text>the River Class frigate, HMCS New Glasgow, is commissioned into the Royal Canadian Navy</text>
            <vet id="1060">J.A. Brunette</vet>
            <vet id="1452">Frank Dion</vet>
            <vet id="1821">Harold MacLauchlan</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="04/01/1944" img="uho.jpg">
            <text>the Battle of the Moro River in Italy comes to an end</text>
            <vet id="2286">Bill Teleske</vet>
            <vet id="1466">Brian Murphy</vet>
            <vet id="1515">Rod McNeill</vet>
            <vet id="1488">Arthur Brown</vet>
            <vet id="2295">Rudy Deutsch</vet>
            <vet id="1071">Bernard Finestone</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="08/01/1944" img="lcf.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Camrose and HMS Bayntun sink the German submarine U-757 in the North Atlantic</text>
            <vet id="2288">Ross Hamilton</vet>
            <vet id="1161">George Evans</vet>
            <vet id="2325">Leonard Bookbinder</vet>
            <vet id="1397">Jack Smallwood</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/02/1944" img="f4s.jpg">
            <text>the Royal Canadian Electrical and Mechanical Engineers are authorized to form</text>
            <vet id="2317">Norm Jenkins</vet>
            <vet id="1527">Frank Moore</vet>
            <vet id="1532">James Fox</vet>
            <vet id="2371">Bill Baluk</vet>
            <vet id="1534">Stephen Bandurka</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="05/02/1944" img="qpk.jpg">
            <text>HMS Puncher, an aircraft carrier, is commissioned into the Royal Navy at Vancouver with a Canadian crew, but a British air complement</text>
            <vet id="1297">Norman Wrigglesworth</vet>
            <vet id="2449">Richard Clements</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="08/02/1944" img="w3y.jpg">
            <text>Canadian troops participate in Operation Veritable in the Reichswald Forest</text>
            <vet id="1702">Glenn Price</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="18/02/1944" img="2rp.jpg">
            <text>sixteen Canadian minesweepers, in four divisions of four ships, begin to leave St. John's for British waters to take part in the invasion of Normandy</text>
            <vet id="1341">Ralph Taylor</vet>
            <vet id="1495">Bruce Findlay</vet>
            <vet id="2436">Alfred Carpenter</vet>
            <vet id="1077">Harvey Burns</vet>
            <vet id="2449">Richard Clements</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="19/02/1944" img="5vv.jpg">
            <text>Motor Torpedo boats of the 29th and 65th (Canadian) Flotillas begin to be commissioned (continues until 31 March)</text>
            <vet id="1493">Ron Rhine</vet>
            <vet id="1398">James Smitherman</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="24/02/1944" img="ybi.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Waskesiu sinks the German submarine U-257 in the North Atlantic</text>
            <vet id="1161">George Evans</vet>
            <vet id="2325">Leonard Bookbinder</vet>
            <vet id="1397">Jack Smallwood</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="06/03/1944" img="myb.jpg">
            <text>HMC Ships St. Catharines, Chilliwack, Gatineau, Fennel and Chaudiere assist Royal Naval warships in the sinking of the German submarine U-744 in the North Atlantic</text>
            <vet id="1161">George Evans</vet>
            <vet id="2325">Leonard Bookbinder</vet>
            <vet id="1397">Jack Smallwood</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="10/03/1944" img="jxj.jpg">
            <text>a Sunderland aircraft from No.422 Squadron attacks and destroys the German submarine U-625</text>
            <vet id="2288">Ross Hamilton</vet>
            <vet id="2526">Mark Boivin</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="10/03/1944" img="2e1.jpg">
            <text>HMC Ships St. Laurent, Owen Sound and Swansea assist Royal Navy warships sink the German submarine U-845 in the North Atlantic</text>
            <vet id="1060">J.A. Brunette</vet>
            <vet id="1070">Frank Aldred</vet>
            <vet id="1477">Donald Green</vet>
            <vet id="2298">Gordon Wright</vet>
            <vet id="1176">Rex Fendick</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="22/03/1944" img="5ke.jpg">
            <text>the Canadian Army reaches a peak strength of 495,804 soldiers and support personnel</text>
            <vet id="2519">Marcel Caron</vet>
            <vet id="1074">Corinne Sevigney</vet>
            <vet id="1530">Eric Saunders</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="14/04/1944" img="khr.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Swansea and HMS Pelican combine to sink the German submarine U-448 in the North Atlantic</text>
            <vet id="1060">J.A Brunette</vet>
            <vet id="1314">Jim Peters</vet>
            <vet id="2387">Edwin Badger</vet>
            <vet id="1398">James Smitherman</vet>
            <vet id="2496">Clarence Sweeney</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="17/04/1944" img="fbs.jpg">
            <text>a Canso aircraft from No. 162 Squadron, Royal Canadian Air Force, sink the German submarine U-432 southwest of Iceland</text>
            <vet id="2526">Mark Boivin</vet>
            <vet id="2288">Ross Hamilton</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="29/04/1944" img="axl.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Athabaskan and Haida fight two German destroyers off Ile de Bas, France, and destroy one of them.  Athabaskan was torpedoed and sunk</text>
            <vet id="1483">Henry Mason</vet>
            <vet id="1069">Tom Rappel</vet>
            <vet id="1154">John Covan</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="07/05/1944" img="kbe.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Valleyfield, a frigate, is torpedoed and sunk by the German submarine U-548 in the Atlantic Ocean with a loss of 125 sailors</text>
            <vet id="1139">John Stephen</vet>
            <vet id="1095">Stirling Squarebriggs</vet>
            <vet id="2496">Clarence Sweeney</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="11/05/1944" img="rrj.jpg">
            <text>Allied troops make final push in Battle of Monte Cassino</text>
            <vet id="1291">Paul-Emile Lamouche</vet>
            <vet id="1380">William Adelman</vet>
            <vet id="1322">Leonidas Lemaire</vet>
            <vet id="2286">Bill Teleske</vet>
            <vet id="2686">Bruce Bullock</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="24/05/1944" img="2ah.jpg">
            <text>1st Canadian Division breaks through the Hitler Line</text>
            <vet id="1515">Rod McNeill</vet>
            <vet id="1473">Nigel Taylor</vet>
            <vet id="2286">Bill Teleske</vet>
            <vet id="2356">Roy Page</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="05/06/1944" img="j2y.jpg">
            <text>sixteen Royal Canadian Navy minesweepers help clear the English Channel in preparation for the D-Day landings</text>
            <vet id="1341">Ralph Taylor</vet>
            <vet id="1495">Bruce Findlay</vet>
            <vet id="2436">Alfred Carpenter</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="06/06/1944" img="hwp.jpg">
            <text>approximately one hundred and ten Canadian warships participate in the Allied landings in Normandy</text>
            <vet id="1375">Okill Stuart</vet>
            <vet id="1043">Jan de Vries</vet>
            <vet id="1226">Joseph Hawkins</vet>
            <vet id="1376">George Mann</vet>
            <vet id="1371">Charles Ross</vet>
            <vet id="2169">Leo Pikulski</vet>
            <vet id="2318">Joseph Sullivan</vet>
            <vet id="2384">Catherine Anderson</vet>
            <vet id="1252">Charles Owens</vet>
            <vet id="2381">Alfred Warford</vet>
            <vet id="1199">Fred Allison</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="09/06/1944" img="uqs.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Haida, HMCS Huron and other destroyers from the 10th Destroyer Flotilla sink the German destroyers ZH1 and Z32 in the English Channel</text>
            <vet id="1069">Tom Rappel</vet>
            <vet id="1060">J.A Brunette</vet>
            <vet id="2298">Gordon Wright</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="24/06/1944" img="gnj.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Haida, HMS Eskimo and a Royal Air Force patrol aircraft sink the German submarine U-971 in the English Channel</text>
            <vet id="1069">Tom Rappel</vet>
            <vet id="2526">Mark Boivin</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="24/06/1944" img="ndumhotsllqeheidlvhc.jpg">
            <text>Flight Lieutenant David Hornell, a Canso pilot with 162 Squadron, Royal Canadian Air Force, sinks the German submarine U-1225.  Hornell's aircraft is also brought down and Hornell dies as a result of his injuries.  He is awarded a posthumous Victoria Cross</text>
            <vet id="2526">Mark Boivin</vet>
            <vet id="2288">Ross Hamilton</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="27/06/1944" img="rjn.jpg">
            <text>No. 143 (Typhoon) Wing aircraft, while still based in England, begin using new airstrips in Normandy to rearm and refuel</text>
            <vet id="1135">Norman Dawber</vet>
            <vet id="1147">John Slater</vet>
            <vet id="2369">Archie Stover</vet>
            <vet id="1176">Rex Fendick</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="06/07/1944" img="ees.jpg">
            <text>HMC Ships Ottawa and Kootenay, along with HMS Statice, sink the German submarine U-678 while on patrol in the English Channel</text>
            <vet id="2298">Gordon Wright</vet>
            <vet id="1314">Jim Peters</vet>
            <vet id="1320">Ernest Randle</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="18/07/1944" img="lg2.jpg">
            <text>Canadian 3rd Division advances through the city of Caen as part of Operation Greenwood</text>
            <vet id="2243">Fred Bryant</vet>
            <vet id="2220">Allan MacDonald</vet>
            <vet id="2318">Joseph Sullivan</vet>
            <vet id="2381">Alfred Warford</vet>
            <vet id="1252">Charles Owens</vet>
            <vet id="2273">Sol Zulauf</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="19/07/1944" img="xjo.jpg">
            <text>Canadian troops begin engagements on Verrieres Ridge, suffering large casualties</text>
            <vet id="1142">Kenneth Wootton</vet>
            <vet id="2220">Allan MacDonald</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="08/08/1944" img="mum.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Regina is torpedoed and sunk by the German submarine U-667 off the coast of France</text>
            <vet id="1429">John Potter</vet>
            <vet id="1314">Jim Peters</vet>
            <vet id="1119">Donald MacIntosh</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="15/08/1944" img="w3u.jpg">
            <text>HMC Ships Prince David and Prince Henry participate in the Allied landing in southern France, codenamed Operation Dragoon</text>
            <vet id="1070">Frank Aldred</vet>
            <vet id="2333">Maurice White</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="18/08/1944" img="pct.jpg">
            <text>HMC Ships Ottawa, Kootenay and Chaudiere sink the German submarine U-621 while on patrol in the Bay of Biscay</text>
            <vet id="1314">Jim Peters</vet>
            <vet id="2496">Clarence Sweeney</vet>
            <vet id="1060">J.A Brunette</vet>
            <vet id="1220">C Alward</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="18/08/1944" img="t2r.jpg">
            <text>Major David V. Currie, with the 29th Armoured Reconnaissance Regiment (South Alberta Regiment), is awarded the Victoria Cross for his work in the Falaise Pocket</text>
            <vet id="1142">Kenneth Wootton</vet>
            <vet id="1501">Douglas Storey</vet>
            <vet id="2220">Allan MacDonald</vet>
            <vet id="2169">Leo Pikulski</vet>
            <vet id="2318">Jospeh Sullivan</vet>
            <vet id="1252">Charles Owens</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="20/08/1944" img="bzt.jpg">
            <text>HMC Ships Ottawa, Kootenay and Chaudiere sink the German submarine U-984 while on patrol in the English Channel B their second combined victory in three days</text>
            <vet id="2601">John Kubis</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="21/08/1944" img="5r0.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Alberni is torpedoed and sunk by the German submarine U-480 in the English Channel</text>
            <vet id="1216">Murray Copot</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="22/08/1944" img="3cg.jpg">
            <text>HMS Nabob, a British aircraft carrier with a Royal Canadian Navy crew, is torpedoed in the North Sea and severely damaged</text>
            <vet id="1138">Adeline Bowland</vet>
            <vet id="1119">Donald MacIntosh</vet>
            <vet id="1297">Norman Wrigglesworth</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/09/1944" img="sqb.jpg">
            <text>Dieppe is occupied by Canadian troops</text>
            <vet id="1092">Edward Borland</vet>
            <vet id="2374">Vernon Barr</vet>
            <vet id="2329">William Rawluk</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/09/1944" img="dez.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Saint John and HMCS Swansea sink the German submarine U-247 off Land's End, England</text>
            <vet id="1320">Ernest Randle</vet>
            <vet id="1527">Frank Moore</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="09/09/1944" img="lus.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Dunver and HMCS Hespeler sink the German submarine U-484 in Hebridean waters</text>
            <vet id="1452">Frank Dion</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="17/09/1944" img="azu.jpg">
            <text>No.437 (Dakota) Squadron participates in Operation Market Garden, the airborne landings at Eindhoven, by towing gliders and dropping supplies</text>
            <vet id="1145">Anatole Cote</vet>
            <vet id="1158">Walter Haydon</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="30/09/1944" img="5ry.jpg">
            <text>Calais is captured by Canadian forces</text>
            <vet id="1797">John Charlwood</vet>
            <vet id="2173">Herb Harris</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="05/10/1944" img="pkd.jpg">
            <text>pilots from No.401 Squadron, RCAF, destroy a German Me-262, becoming the first jet-propelled aircraft shot down by the Royal Air Force or the Royal Canadian Air Force</text>
            <vet id="1118">Brian MacConnell</vet>
            <vet id="1165">Ed Green</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="06/10/1944" img="ps4.jpg">
            <text>No.6 (RCAF) Group, Bomber Command, deploys its largest sortie of the war with 523 aircraft involved</text>
            <vet id="1307">Malcolm MacConnell</vet>
            <vet id="1294">William Kondra</vet>
            <vet id="1481">Kenneth France</vet>
            <vet id="2319">Fred Guest</vet>
            <vet id="1357">Allan Smith</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="08/10/1944" img="wi1.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Mulgrave strikes a mine off Le Havre, is beached and becomes a total loss</text>
            <vet id="1483">Henry Mason</vet>
            <vet id="1161">George Evans</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="14/10/1944" img="31q.jpg">
            <text>within a period of sixteen hours No.6 (RCAF) Group, Bomber Command, flies a total of 501 Lancaster and Halifax bombers against targets in Duisburg, Germany</text>
            <vet id="2293">Steve Boczar</vet>
            <vet id="2371">Bill Baluk</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="16/10/1944" img="vjf.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Annan sinks the German submarine U-1006 south of the Faeroes</text>
            <vet id="2387">Edwin Badger</vet>
            <vet id="1398">James Smitherman</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="18/10/1944" img="vdq.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Prince Henry and HMCS Prince David engage in landing liberation forces in Greece</text>
            <vet id="1477">Donald Green</vet>
            <vet id="1070">Frank Aldred</vet>
            <vet id="2356">Roy Page</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="25/10/1944" img="m5a.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Skeena becomes stranded near Reykjavik, Iceland, becoming a total loss</text>
            <vet id="2525">George Charrier</vet>
            <vet id="1397">Jack Smallwood</vet>
            <vet id="1070">Frank Aldred</vet>
            <vet id="2193">Leslie Clarke</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="08/11/1944" img="dwt.jpg">
            <text>end of the Battle of the Scheldt</text>
            <vet id="1061">Bill Davis</vet>
            <vet id="1107">Arthur Webster</vet>
            <vet id="1270">David Havard</vet>
            <vet id="1371">Charles Ross</vet>
            <vet id="2374">Vernon Barr</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="15/11/1944" img="tl0.jpg">
            <text>the Aircraft Detection Corps of civilian volunteer observers is disbanded</text>
            <vet id="1158">Walter Hayman</vet>
            <vet id="2480">Cyril Hammond</vet>
            <vet id="1340">Gordon Partridge</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="25/11/1944" img="uqs.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Shawinigan is torpedoed by a German submarine in Cabot Strait and sunk with all hands</text>
            <vet id="1060">J.A Brunette</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="10/12/1944" img="ivhukbgzvslsoplcttex.jpg">
            <text>Canadian troops storm the Lamone River defences in Italy</text>
            <vet id="1333">Raymond Lewis</vet>
            <vet id="1515">Rod McNeill</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="24/12/1944" img="w20.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Clayoquot is torpedoed by a U-boat and sinks in the Halifax approaches</text>
            <vet id="1060">J.A Brunette</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="27/12/1944" img="a42.jpg">
            <text>HMCS St. Thomas sinks the German submarine U-877 in the North Atlantic</text>
            <vet id="2298">Gordon Wright</vet>
            <vet id="1452">Frank Dion</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="29/12/1944" img="3bx.jpg">
            <text>Flight-Lieutenant R.J. Audet, No.411 Squadron, Royal Canadian Air Force, shoots down five German fighters during a patrol in the Rhine area</text>
            <vet id="2681">Gordon Redcliffe</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="30/12/1944" img="uhd.jpg">
            <text>Second-Lieutenant C.J.W. Taylor, No.407 Squadron, Royal Canadian Air Force, sinks the German submarine U-772 with depth charges</text>
            <vet id="1500">Albert Sanderson</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="09/01/1945" img="qpk.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Ehkoli, a former Royal Canadian Navy patrol boat, is recommissioned in the RCN as a survey vessel</text>
            <vet id="2449">Richard Clements?</vet>
            <vet id="1081">Jack Stapleton</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="15/01/1945" img="evb.jpg">
            <text>Nos.1 and 3 Training Commands, Royal Canadian Air Force, are disbanded and replaced by No.1 Air Command with headquarters at Trenton, Ontario</text>
            <vet id="1226">Joseph Hawkins</vet>
            <vet id="1465">Ruby Foley</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="05/02/1945" img="2ck.jpg">
            <text>No.9 (Transport) Group, Royal Canadian Air Force, is formed to control air transport within the air force</text>
            <vet id="2366">Harold Ward</vet>
            <vet id="2359">Jim Venables</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="08/02/1945" img="e2a.jpg">
            <text>First Canadian Army opens an offensive at the north end of the German Siegfried Line southeast of Nijmegen in order to clear the area between the Maas and Rhine rivers</text>
            <vet id="1073">John Forbes</vet>
            <vet id="1838">Bruce Cox</vet>
            <vet id="1062">Elizabeth Dimock</vet>
            <vet id="1256">Wilbergt Prentice</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="13/02/1945" img="fiykluaiakfpkuxzffbv.jpg">
            <text>Canadian troops capture the town of Cleve in Germany</text>
            <vet id="2513">Emile Turcot</vet>
            <vet id="2533">Gerald Derick</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="14/02/1945" img="wi1.jpg">
            <text>five Motor Torpedo Boats of the Canadian 29th Flotilla burn in Ostende harbour</text>
            <vet id="1161">George Evans</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="16/02/1945" img="jsj.jpg">
            <text>HMCS St. John sinks the German submarine U-309 off the northeast coast of Scotland</text>
            <vet id="1320">Ernest Randle</vet>
            <vet id="1527">Frank Moore</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="22/02/1945" img="ksu.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Trentonian is torpedoed and sunk by a German submarine in the English Channel</text>
            <vet id="1139">John Stephen</vet>
            <vet id="1483">Henry Mason</vet>
            <vet id="1070">Frank Aldred</vet>
            <vet id="2298">Gordon Wright</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="09/03/1945" img="ibt.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Uganda arrives in Sydney, Australia, to join the British Pacific Fleet</text>
            <vet id="2137">Louis Howard</vet>
            <vet id="2737">Terence Elworthy</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="15/03/1945" img="213.jpg">
            <text>the First Canadian Corps takes over the sector along the Waal River in Holland upon its arrival from the Italian theatre of war.  As a result, both Canadian corps now form part of the First Canadian Army</text>
            <vet id="1384">Gordon Bannerman</vet>
            <vet id="2271">John Cathie</vet>
            <vet id="2499">Joan Manning</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="17/03/1945" img="ewr.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Guysborough is torpedoed and sunk by a German U-boat off Ushant</text>
            <vet id="1070">Frank Aldred</vet>
            <vet id="1483">Henry Mason</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="20/03/1945" img="ees.jpg">
            <text>HMCS New Glasgow sinks the German submarine U-1003 off Lough Foyle, Northern Ireland</text>
            <vet id="2298">Gordon Wright</vet>
            <vet id="1452">Frank Dion</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="24/03/1945" img="zim.jpg">
            <text>Corporal F.G. Topham, Royal Canadian Army Medical Corps, is awarded the Victoria Cross for his actions in support of 1st Canadian Parachute Battalion east of the Rhine River, Germany</text>
            <vet id="2369">Archie Stover</vet>
            <vet id="2160">Hewitt Quick</vet>
            <vet id="2230">Joan Johnson nee Cobb</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="31/03/1945" img="wow.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Conestoga, the Women's Royal Canadian Naval Service training establishment, is paid off</text>
            <vet id="1066">Carol Duffus</vet>
            <vet id="1327">Olive Henderson</vet>
            <vet id="2248">Ruby Somers</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="03/04/1945" img="2u4.jpg">
            <text>the First Canadian Army crosses the Rhine and captures the town of Zevenaar, and reaches the town of Zutphen</text>
            <vet id="1317">Jean Marie Milot</vet>
            <vet id="1079">John Springer</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="04/04/1945" img="lls.jpg">
            <text>the First Canadian Army clears out the town of Almelo</text>
            <vet id="1096">Hubert Lalonde</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="15/04/1945" img="b0i.jpg">
            <text>the First Canadian Army reaches the Dutch coast near Leeuwarden</text>
            <vet id="1517">Arthur Lyon</vet>
            <vet id="1043">Jan de Vries</vet>
            <vet id="1224">Doris Wallace</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="16/04/1945" img="4zr.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Esquimalt is torpoeded and sunk in the waters off of Halifax</text>
            <vet id="2137">Louis Howard</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="26/04/1945" img="ycn.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Ontario, a cruiser, is commissioned</text>
            <vet id="1216">Murray Copot</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="04/05/1945" img="usj.jpg">
            <text>the cruiser HMCS Uganda sails with an American task force to bombard Japanese airfields as part of the Okinawa campaign</text>
            <vet id="2520">Geoffrey Knowles</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="05/05/1945" img="wwd.jpg">
            <text>units of the First Canadian Army accept the surrender of German forces at Bad Zwischenahn, Germany</text>
            <vet id="2523">Jean-Paul Bertrand</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="07/05/1945" img="wak.jpg">
            <text>All German military forces surrender to the Allied Forces in Europe</text>
            <vet id="2374">Vernon Barr</vet>
            <vet id="1515">Rod McNeill</vet>
            <vet id="1735">Rex Rose</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="02/08/1945" img="wgx.jpg">
            <text>the prefix 'Royal' is granted for the Canadian Armoured Corps by the King</text>
            <vet id="1092">Edward Borland</vet>
            <vet id="1473">Nigel Taylor</vet>
        </event>
        
        <event date="01/05/1945" img="2im.jpg">
            <text>James Brown, a gunner in the Murmansk Run, informs others the war is over</text>
            <vet id="1034">James Brown</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="19/08/1942" img="ez0.jpg">
            <text>David Peat enlists in the Army</text>
            <vet id="1035">David Peat</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="19/08/1942" img="p1m.jpg">
            <text>George Burrows loses his close friend in the Battle of Dieppe</text>
            <vet id="1042">George Burrows</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="05/06/1944" img="z2q.jpg">
            <text>Jan de Vries prepares as a bombardier for the D-Day battles in Normandy</text>
            <vet id="1043">Jan de Vries</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/02/1942" img="3vi.jpg">
            <text>Helen Crawley enlists and eventually becomes a motorcycle dispatch rider</text>
            <vet id="1045">Helen Crawley</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/12/1939" img="xzw.jpg">
            <text>Robert Guy enlists in the Army and volunteers for Royal Fusiliers' Parachute Regiment</text>
            <vet id="1046">Robert Guy</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/10/1944" img="r04.jpg">
            <text>Olive Peat is sent over to London as a clerk at the Canada House, the Canadian Military Headquarters.</text>
            <vet id="1049">Olive Peat (nÈe Mattews)</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/09/1943" img="mbs.jpg">
            <text>Malcolm Andrade enlists in the Air Force as a bomber</text>
            <vet id="1050">Malcolm Andrade</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/10/1940" img="yjz.jpg">
            <text>Douglas Annis joins the Army as a lineman</text>
            <vet id="1058">Douglas Annis</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/06/1943" img="33s.jpg">
            <text>Ernest Bone crosses the Atlantic to train at the Winnipeg Air Force Base</text>
            <vet id="1059">Ernest Bone</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="07/03/1945" img="w20.jpg">
            <text>J.A. Brunette's crew on HMCS La Hulloise sink a U-1302 submarine</text>
            <vet id="1060">J.A. RenÈ Brunette</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="13/10/1944" img="2xh.jpg">
            <text>Bill Davis participates in the Battle of the Scheldt</text>
            <vet id="1061">Bill Davis</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="28/04/1942" img="qfg.jpg">
            <text>Elizabeth Dimock travels to South Africa as part of the South African Medical Nursing Service</text>
            <vet id="1062">Elizabeth (Betty) Dimock</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="15/06/1944" img="u3v.jpg">
            <text>Helen Rochon experiences an air raid while stationed in London, England</text>
            <vet id="1065">Helen Rochon</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/03/1943" img="wow.jpg">
            <text>Carol Duffus enlists in the Womens Royal Canadian Naval Service (WRCNS) and becomes a staff training officer</text>
            <vet id="1066">Carol Duffus</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/07/1942" img="4qd.jpg">
            <text>Hubert Gray participates as an Allied bomber in the Battle of El Alamein in Egypt</text>
            <vet id="1067">Hubert Gray</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/02/1945" img="idt.jpg">
            <text>Bob Farquharson flies in supplies to Allied troops in Burma</text>
            <vet id="1068">Bob Farquharson</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="29/04/1944" img="axl.jpg">
            <text>Tom Rappel and crew on HMCS Haida battle two German destroyers off the Ile de Bas, France</text>
            <vet id="1069">Tom Rappel</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="02/03/1941" img="ewr.jpg">
            <text>Frank Aldred crosses the equator on HMS Prince Henry</text>
            <vet id="1070">Frank Aldred</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/12/1943" img="kx5.jpg">
            <text>Bernard Finestone and troops from the British Colombia Dragoons cross the Moro River in Italy</text>
            <vet id="1071">Bernard Finestone</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="07/03/1945" img="p5c.jpg">
            <text>John Forbes is wounded in battle in Nijmegen, Holland</text>
            <vet id="1073">John Forbes</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/01/1941" img="2w0.jpg">
            <text>Corinne Sévigny joins the Canadian Womens Army Corps (CWAC) in Quebec City</text>
            <vet id="1074">Corinne SÈvigny</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/10/1939" img="njd.jpg">
            <text>Anthony Slugoski joins the Air Force and begins training</text>
            <vet id="1075">Anthony Slugoski</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/09/1942" img="5ux.jpg">
            <text>Harvey Burns trains as part of the Royal Canadian Navy in Cornwallis, Nova Scotia</text>
            <vet id="1077">Harvey Burns</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="25/04/1945" img="gyf.jpg">
            <text>John Springer is wounded near the border of Holland and Germany</text>
            <vet id="1079">John Springer</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="05/06/1944" img="rc2.jpg">
            <text>Cyril Roach and crew leave the Isle of Wight to participate in D-Day landings</text>
            <vet id="1080">Cyril Roach</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/01/1943" img="h4z.jpg">
            <text>Jack Stapleton joins the Merchant Navy and is eventually deployed to Calcutta, India</text>
            <vet id="1081">Jack Stapleton</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/01/1943" img="5rp.jpg">
            <text>Margarita Trull joins the Women Royal Naval Service (WRENS) and becomes a cryptologist (secret agent).</text>
            <vet id="1082">Margarita Trull</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/09/1940" img="xhv.jpg">
            <text>Leonard Allbon is stationed in England just as the Battle of Britain commences</text>
            <vet id="1085">Leonard Allbon</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/06/1943" img="sqt.jpg">
            <text>Marie Duchesnay joins the Women Royal Naval Service (WRENS) and begins training in coding and de-coding</text>
            <vet id="1086">Marie Duchesnay</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="06/06/1944" img="v1w.jpg">
            <text>John Honsberger watches troops land on D-Day</text>
            <vet id="1087">John Honsberger</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="16/09/1944" img="0b1.jpg">
            <text>Hugh Bartley crashes his Mosquito aircraft in Belgium</text>
            <vet id="1088">Hugh Bartley</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="05/01/1945" img="zoi.jpg">
            <text>Jean Cauchy performs his last air raid over Hannover</text>
            <vet id="1089">Jean Cauchy</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="24/12/1944" img="3ob.jpg">
            <text>Edward Beaven serves in Bethlehem on Christmas Eve</text>
            <vet id="1091">Edward Beaven</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/09/1944" img="wgx.jpg">
            <text>Edward Borland celebrates with Canadian troops and French civilians after the liberation of Dieppe</text>
            <vet id="1092">Edward Borland</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="05/03/1945" img="xvd.jpg">
            <text>Robert Lundmark trains as a motor mechanic in Saskatoon</text>
            <vet id="1094">Robert Lundmark</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="30/11/1945" img="vcn.jpg">
            <text>Stirling Squarebriggs is discharged from the Army</text>
            <vet id="1095">Stirling Squarebriggs</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="08/05/1945" img="lls.jpg">
            <text>Hubert Lalonde was stationed in Woerdon when the war ends</text>
            <vet id="1096">Hubert Lalonde</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="20/12/1942" img="wzh.jpg">
            <text>Leonard Link goes to Alberta to undergo poisonous gas testing</text>
            <vet id="1099">Leonard Link</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="10/09/1942" img="vmy.jpg">
            <text>Harold Bronson qualifies as an air navigator with the Royal Canadian Air Force (RCAF)</text>
            <vet id="1102">Harold Bronson</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="12/09/1939" img="004.jpg">
            <text>Philip Kazimir enlists as a driver for the Argyles D Company</text>
            <vet id="1103">Philip Kazimir</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/09/1941" img="fod.jpg">
            <text>Mike Hawryliw participates in experimental gas testing in Suffield, Alberta</text>
            <vet id="1104">Mike Hawryliw</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="30/06/1942" img="gaq.jpg">
            <text>Roy Heron enlists in the Canadian Army</text>
            <vet id="1106">Roy Heron</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="06/11/1943" img="dwt.jpg">
            <text>Arhtur Webster gets married before being stationed overseas</text>
            <vet id="1107">Arthur Webster</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="13/02/1945" img="011.jpg">
            <text>Mervyn Couse serves as a pilot during the Bombing of Dresden</text>
            <vet id="1108">Mervyn Couse</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="17/04/1942" img="wxm.jpg">
            <text>Geraldine Muter is called up to serve in the British Commonwealth Air Training Program</text>
            <vet id="1111">Geraldine Muter</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="08/08/1944" img="phg.jpg">
            <text>Charles Kewen takes a two week leave while stationed in India</text>
            <vet id="1113">Charles Kewen</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="19/12/1944" img="pmv.jpg">
            <text>Melbourne Le Marquand is awarded a Military Medal for his actions in Bruuk, Holland</text>
            <vet id="1115">Melbourne Le Marquand</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/01/1942" img="usr.jpg">
            <text>Alexander Scott enlists in the Air Force</text>
            <vet id="1116">Alexander Scott</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="27/08/1942" img="klh.jpg">
            <text>Edith Middleton enlists and works as a "Lumber Jill" in Scotland</text>
            <vet id="1117">Edith Middleton</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="18/04/1945" img="pkd.jpg">
            <text>Brian MacConnell shoots down a German Arado aircraft</text>
            <vet id="1118">Brian MacConnell</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/09/1945" img="vkc.jpg">
            <text>Donald McIntosh rides on HMS Queen Mary with Sir Winston Churchill</text>
            <vet id="1119">Donald McIntosh</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="15/09/1944" img="gy2.jpg">
            <text>Donald Racicot serves in the military as a mechanic</text>
            <vet id="1121">Donald Racicot</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="03/01/1942" img="zfewbxlgjikcqjcsxvkh.jpg">
            <text>Bill Watterson enlists in the Army</text>
            <vet id="1123">Bill Watterson</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="20/08/1942" img="eue.jpg">
            <text>Murray Ginsberg joins the Royal Canadian Ordinance Corps band</text>
            <vet id="1124">Murray Ginsberg</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/01/1945" img="mlp.jpg">
            <text>Ed Pearson is assigned to Special Operations Executive (SOE), flying to Sri Lanka (then Ceylon)</text>
            <vet id="1125">Ed Pearson</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/06/1942" img="vjm.jpg">
            <text>Cecil Hancock enlists in the Air Force and trains in the praries</text>
            <vet id="1129">Cecil Hancock</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="08/05/1945" img="pga.jpg">
            <text>Louis Curran was stationed in the trenches in Holland when the war ends</text>
            <vet id="1130">Louis Curran</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="07/09/1940" img="guj.jpg">
            <text>May Gillman serves as a nurse while London is bombed</text>
            <vet id="1133">May Gillman</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="30/09/1944" img="mnv.jpg">
            <text>John McCarst boards HMCS Midland, his first time on a ranger ship</text>
            <vet id="1134">John McCarst</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="23/06/1944" img="hqt.jpg">
            <text>Norman Dawber flies in France as part of the Royal Canadian Air Force (RCAF) 438 Squadron</text>
            <vet id="1135">Norman Dawber</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/02/1940" img="hqi.jpg">
            <text>Howard Love's squadron is re-equipped with Liberator aircrafts</text>
            <vet id="1136">Howard Love</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="06/11/1940" img="1ax.jpg">
            <text>Adeline Bowland is torpedoed en route to Europe</text>
            <vet id="1138">Adeline Bowland</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/12/1940" img="fbr.jpg">
            <text>John Stephen serves on HMS Majola</text>
            <vet id="1139">John Stephen</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="25/11/1943" img="cvn.jpg">
            <text>Pierre Bauset is shot down returning from Frankfurt</text>
            <vet id="1140">Pierre Bauset</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="18/11/1944" img="nkr.jpg">
            <text>Charles Scott serves on HMCS Fergus</text>
            <vet id="1141">Charles Scott</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="19/07/1944" img="53c.jpg">
            <text>Kenneth Wootton participates in the Battle of Verrieres Ridge</text>
            <vet id="1142">Kenneth Wootton</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/04/1945" img="qyp.jpg">
            <text>Anatole Cote crashes in Holland and stays hidden thanks to a Dutchman</text>
            <vet id="1145">Anatole CÙtÈ</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/01/1942" img="ptz.jpg">
            <text>John Slater joins the Royal Canadian Corps of Sgnals</text>
            <vet id="1147">John Slater</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/07/1943" img="glb.jpg">
            <text>Thomas Atherton joins the Merchant Navy and sails to India</text>
            <vet id="1150">Thomas Atherton</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/12/1943" img="aqt.jpg">
            <text>John Covan and crew on the SS Green Gables Park avoid a Japanese submarine attack</text>
            <vet id="1154">John Covan</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/02/1945" img="4ks.jpg">
            <text>Walter Hayden completes his tour with 432 Squadron</text>
            <vet id="1158">Walter Hayden</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="21/05/1942" img="gcq.jpg">
            <text>George Evans and crew on the SS Pieter de Hoogh are attacked departing Iceland</text>
            <vet id="1161">George Evans</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/01/1944" img="rra.jpg">
            <text>Margaret Brownlee is stationed in England as a driver</text>
            <vet id="1163">Margaret Brownlee</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="20/01/1944" img="npo.jpg">
            <text>Robert Govan prepares for battle in Dunkirk, France</text>
            <vet id="1164">Robert Govan</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="23/10/1944" img="j3j.jpg">
            <text>Ed Green carries out an airraid over the city of Essen</text>
            <vet id="1165">Ed Green</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/02/1941" img="kod.jpg">
            <text>Bruce Little survives German submarine attacks while crossing the Atlantic</text>
            <vet id="1167">Bruce Little</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/04/1945" img="0ma.jpg">
            <text>Robert Rodgers guards German Prisoners of War (POWs) in Quebec</text>
            <vet id="1173">Robert Rodgers</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="06/06/1944" img="xp1.jpg">
            <text>Rex Fendick lands on Sword Beach as part of D-Day operations</text>
            <vet id="1176">Rex Fendick</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="25/12/1943" img="tpo.jpg">
            <text>Alec MacInnis spends his fourth consecutive Christmas away from his family</text>
            <vet id="1178">Alec MacInnis</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="09/07/1944" img="ndy.jpg">
            <text>Allan Backman participates in the Battle for Caen</text>
            <vet id="1181">Allan Backman</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/10/1943" img="a1b.jpg">
            <text>Lewis Billard begins training as part of the Royal canadian Air Force (RCAF)</text>
            <vet id="1185">Lewis Billard</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/01/1945" img="gob.jpg">
            <text>Jean Carroll is stationed in a Scottish hospital as a nurse</text>
            <vet id="1189">Jean Carroll</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="16/12/1944" img="ecv.jpg">
            <text>Fred Allison participates in the Battle of the Bulge</text>
            <vet id="1199">Fred Allison</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/07/1943" img="i22.jpg">
            <text>Robert Atkins serves in the Aleutian Islands</text>
            <vet id="1201">Robert Atkins</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/11/1944" img="cnh.jpg">
            <text>Lawrence Wagg travels from North Africa to Italy</text>
            <vet id="1209">Lawrence Wagg</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="19/10/1941" img="soqqgurfufezsnkczlgv.jpg">
            <text>Mavis Butlin enlists in the Womens Canadian Royal Naval Service (WCRNS)</text>
            <vet id="1213">Mavis Butlin</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/03/1942" img="5r0.jpg">
            <text>Murray Copot begins acitve service on HMCS Chippewa</text>
            <vet id="1216">Murray Copot</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="30/03/1944" img="yum.jpg">
            <text>Ella Curtis meets Princess Alice on her visit to the Royal Canadian Air Force (RCAF) Women's Division in Canada</text>
            <vet id="1217">Ella Curtis</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="22/08/1942" img="jxo.jpg">
            <text>Bruce Agnew joins the Royal Canadian Air Force (RCAF)</text>
            <vet id="1219">Bruce Agnew</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/09/1943" img="205.jpg">
            <text>Mr. Alward survives German submarine attacks in the Atlantic</text>
            <vet id="1220">C. Alward</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="07/05/1945" img="n4z.jpg">
            <text>Doris Wallace plays in the Canadian Women's Army Corps (CWAC) Pipe Band for soldiers waiting to return home</text>
            <vet id="1224">Doris Wallace</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="19/08/1942" img="pnl.jpg">
            <text>Douglas Warren participates in the air battle in Dieppe</text>
            <vet id="1225">Douglas Warren</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="06/06/1944" img="evb.jpg">
            <text>Jospeh Hawkins serves as an air bomber during D-Day</text>
            <vet id="1226">Joseph Hawkins</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="27/10/1944" img="qqs.jpg">
            <text>Douglas Drew serves as a Royal Air Force (RAF) mechanic in North Africa</text>
            <vet id="1229">Douglas Drew</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="19/08/1942" img="i1g.jpg">
            <text>Jean-Marcel D'Aoust fights in the doomed battle of Dieppe</text>
            <vet id="1231">Jean-Marcel D'Aoust</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="06/06/1944" img="csh.jpg">
            <text>George McLean and crew land a mobile hospital on Omaha Beach in Normandy</text>
            <vet id="1244">George McLean</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="25/03/1945" img="qnk.jpg">
            <text>James Moffat experiences a mid-air collision and lands safely in a small Belgian town</text>
            <vet id="1249">James Moffat</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="21/08/1944" img="lnq.jpg">
            <text>Charles Owens is stationed in Antwerp after breaking through the Falaise Gap</text>
            <vet id="1252">Charles Owens</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="02/10/1944" img="mjc.jpg">
            <text>Wilbert Prentice participates in a transport platoon during the Battle of the Scheldt</text>
            <vet id="1256">Wilbert Prentice</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/01/1944" img="vgq.jpg">
            <text>David Seagar undergoes jungle training in India before being stationed in Burma</text>
            <vet id="1260">David Seager</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/04/1945" img="yjh.jpg">
            <text>Emile Thibault is released from a German Prisoner of War (POW) camp</text>
            <vet id="1263">Emile Thibault</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="02/10/1944" img="s3o.jpg">
            <text>David Havard crews a Bren Gun Carrier during the Battle of the Schedlt</text>
            <vet id="1270">David Havard</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="25/05/1942" img="4ly.jpg">
            <text>Leonard Whiffen, aboard HMS Menestheus, aids in sinking German bismark</text>
            <vet id="1271">Leonard Whiffen</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="06/06/1944" img="oeeydwngbjgkttgpttlm.jpg">
            <text>Francis Godon lands in Juno Beach on D-Day and is captured by the Germans</text>
            <vet id="1280">Francis Godon</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="19/06/1944" img="3n1.jpg">
            <text>Bill Hembroff begins active service on HMCS Chippewa</text>
            <vet id="1290">Bill Hembroff</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="19/05/1944" img="v2n.jpg">
            <text>Paul-Emile Lamouche is captured as a Prisoner of War (POW) in Cassino, Italy</text>
            <vet id="1291">Paul-…mile Lamouche</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="16/12/1944" img="3gq.jpg">
            <text>Malcolm McLeod and Canadian troops support the British army in the Battle of the Bulge</text>
            <vet id="1293">Malcolm McLeod</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="23/10/1941" img="ps4.jpg">
            <text>William Kondra enlists in the Royal Canadian Air Force (RCAF) and eventually earns numerous war medals</text>
            <vet id="1294">William Kondra</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/01/1944" img="ksy.jpg">
            <text>Grace Breau-Theriault works as a nurse in Pinewood, England</text>
            <vet id="1298">Grace Breau-Theriault</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/12/1944" img="wbb.jpg">
            <text>Joseph Friedman is shot down during a bombing raid of the town Witten</text>
            <vet id="1299">Joseph Friedman</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="14/06/1944" img="xit.jpg">
            <text>Malcolm MacConnell flies 21 operations with the 50 RAF Squadron</text>
            <vet id="1307">Malcolm MacConnell</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="24/05/1941" img="ddk.jpg">
            <text>Malcolm Lunan repairs some of the convoy ships sunk with HMS Hood</text>
            <vet id="1310">Malcom Lunan</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/06/1940" img="tl4.jpg">
            <text>Joseph Rivard enlists in the Army</text>
            <vet id="1311">Joseph Rivard</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="24/12/1943" img="xlo.jpg">
            <text>Norman Silver and crew aboard HMCS Quatsino avoid German submarines</text>
            <vet id="1312">Norman Silver</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/08/1944" img="f0v.jpg">
            <text>Peter Van Breevoort is detained in Vught concentration camp with his brother</text>
            <vet id="1313">Peter Van Breevoort</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/01/1943" img="kds.jpg">
            <text>Jim Peters and crew take Italian prisoners aboard HMCS Regina</text>
            <vet id="1314">Jim Peters</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/01/1942" img="rhh.jpg">
            <text>William Gelineau joins the Royal Canadian Air Force (RCAF) as a bomber</text>
            <vet id="1315">William GÈlineau</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/10/1940" img="e1d.jpg">
            <text>Robert Routledge is called for active duty with the Army</text>
            <vet id="1316">Robert Routledge</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="17/08/1945" img="2u4.jpg">
            <text>Jean Marie Milot completes Infantry training</text>
            <vet id="1317">Jean Marie Milot</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/01/1943" img="yjb.jpg">
            <text>Jean Clermont and his squadron are attacked by Germans in Canterbury</text>
            <vet id="1319">Jean Clermont</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="23/01/1942" img="dez.jpg">
            <text>Ernest Randle enlists in the Navy</text>
            <vet id="1320">Ernest Randle</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/03/1945" img="yyo.jpg">
            <text>Robert Kerr is captured and serves as a driver for a German Prisoner of War (POW) camp</text>
            <vet id="1321">Robert Kerr</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="17/01/1944" img="d1y.jpg">
            <text>Leonidas Lemaire participates in the Battle of Monte Cassino</text>
            <vet id="1322">Leonidas Lemaire</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="15/11/1942" img="z2i.jpg">
            <text>Andre-Paul Turin is stationed in Algeria with the French Army</text>
            <vet id="1323">AndrÈ-Paul Turin</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/11/1940" img="uh5.jpg">
            <text>Fred Linnington sails from Montreal to the Caribbean with the Merchant Navy</text>
            <vet id="1324">Fred Linnington</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/01/1942" img="0d3.jpg">
            <text>Harold Harden begins sailing the Atlantic as part of the Murmansk Run</text>
            <vet id="1325">Harold Harden</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/01/1941" img="si1.jpg">
            <text>Malcolm Young begins service with the 8th Reconnaisance Regiment</text>
            <vet id="1326">Malcolm Young</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/11/1942" img="ifw.jpg">
            <text>Olive Henderson begins training as a coder for the Women's Canadian Royal Navy Service (WCRNS)</text>
            <vet id="1327">Olive Henderson</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="19/08/1942" img="3gc.jpg">
            <text>Arthur Fraser is captured as a Prisoner of War (POW) during the Battle of Dieppe</text>
            <vet id="1331">Arthur Fraser</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="24/05/1942" img="ivhukbgzvslsoplcttex.jpg">
            <text>Raymond Lewis serves as a Bren Gun Carrier at the Hitler Line</text>
            <vet id="1333">Raymond "Ray" Lewis</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="20/12/1942" img="2gr.jpg">
            <text>Geoffrey Jell arrives in Egypt in advance of the Battle of El Alamein</text>
            <vet id="1337">Geoffrey Jell</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="06/06/1944" img="s5n.jpg">
            <text>Earl Stiles works as a Medical Officer during the Normany Invasion on D-Day</text>
            <vet id="1338">Earl Stiles</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="08/05/1943" img="bzq.jpg">
            <text>Russell Smith trains at Camp Borden, Ontario</text>
            <vet id="1339">Russell Smith</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="24/12/1942" img="gof.jpg">
            <text>Gordon Partridge trains as a navigator with the Royal Canadian Air Force (RCAF)</text>
            <vet id="1340">Gordon Partridge</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/07/1942" img="pvp.jpg">
            <text>Raplh taylor serves aboard a minesweeper</text>
            <vet id="1341">Ralph Taylor</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/05/1943" img="r4u.jpg">
            <text>Al Wallace is captured and is sent to a Prisoner of War (POW) camp</text>
            <vet id="1342">Al Wallace</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/04/1941" img="u1p.jpg">
            <text>James Ritchie serves in the Royal Canadian Corps of Signals</text>
            <vet id="1345">James Ritchie</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="10/06/1944" img="hll.jpg">
            <text>Len Van Roon sends a note to his family after D-Day letting them know he's all right</text>
            <vet id="1350">Len Van Roon</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/04/1942" img="zap.jpg">
            <text>Edison Yeadon's merchant ship is attacked and he is sent to a Japanese Prisoner of war (POW) camp</text>
            <vet id="1351">Edison Yeadon</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="20/10/1944" img="zey.jpg">
            <text>Allan Smith is transferred from the Buchenwald concentration camp to a Prisoner of War (POW) camp</text>
            <vet id="1357">Allan Smith</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/01/1945" img="hbxaawrrjxpjwvqwstex.jpg">
            <text>Herb Pragnell is stationed in Italy near the Gothic Line</text>
            <vet id="1362">Herb Pragnell</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="12/12/1944" img="ock.jpg">
            <text>Marguerite Plante's brother is killed in action in Italy</text>
            <vet id="1368">Marguerite Plante</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/01/1944" img="cgprglqmnzrymbzzltlo.jpg">
            <text>Charles Ross joins the Canadian Film and Photo Unit</text>
            <vet id="1371">Charles Ross</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="06/06/1944" img="hwp.jpg">
            <text>Okill Stuart participates in D-Day as part of the 3rd Canadian Infantry Division</text>
            <vet id="1375">Okill Stuart</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="06/06/1944" img="eoi.jpg">
            <text>George Mann capsizes his first truck in the landings on Normandy</text>
            <vet id="1376">George Mann</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="10/01/1945" img="rrj.jpg">
            <text>William Adelman is shot and injured while stationed in Italy</text>
            <vet id="1380">William Adelman</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/07/1944" img="wup.jpg">
            <text>Gordon Bannerman sees the Vatican while stationed in Italy</text>
            <vet id="1384">Gordon Bannerman</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="17/09/1943" img="l3r.jpg">
            <text>Glennis Boyce enlists in the Royal Canadian Air Force (RCAF) Women's Division</text>
            <vet id="1386">Glennis Boyce</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/01/1943" img="yklvrfphumjzeuxrnqxs.jpg">
            <text>Helen Arbuthnot serves in the Royal Canadian Medical Army Corps</text>
            <vet id="1391">Helen Arbuthnot</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/11/1940" img="lcf.jpg">
            <text>Jack Smallwood begins serving on HMCS Skeena</text>
            <vet id="1397">Jack Smallwood</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/01/1944" img="vjf.jpg">
            <text>James Smitherman crosses the Atlantic on  HMCS Bittersweet</text>
            <vet id="1398">James Smitherman</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/07/1942" img="e0w.jpg">
            <text>Donald Stevenson begins service in theRoyal canadian Air Force (RCAF)</text>
            <vet id="1404">Donald Stevenson</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="19/08/1942" img="opx.jpg">
            <text>Armond Emond fights with the 14th Army Tank Regiment in Dieppe</text>
            <vet id="1412">Armand Emond</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="19/02/1944" img="mvi.jpg">
            <text>Eric Jensen serves as a cook aboard  HMCS Haida</text>
            <vet id="1418">Eric Jensen</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/09/1942" img="i10.jpg">
            <text>Jacques Nadeau is sent to a Prisoner of War (POW) camp and makes several unsuccessful attempts at escape</text>
            <vet id="1423">Jacques Nadeau</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="07/09/1944" img="ypc.jpg">
            <text>Sidney Appleyard enlists and serves as a guard at a Prisoner of War (POW) camp</text>
            <vet id="1427">Sidney Appleyard</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="25/05/1943" img="mgf.jpg">
            <text>John Potter and crew aboard HMCS Regina sink an Italian submarine</text>
            <vet id="1429">John Potter</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="30/09/1943" img="mms.jpg">
            <text>Otto Hemmerling is posted at a radar station in Queen Charlotte Islands</text>
            <vet id="1448">Otto Hemmerling</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="09/09/1939" img="5g1.jpg">
            <text>Andrew Miller enlists in the Army</text>
            <vet id="1450">Andrew Miller</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="15/10/1942" img="lus.jpg">
            <text>Frank Dion enlists in the Navy</text>
            <vet id="1452">Frank Dion</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/01/1942" img="egl.jpg">
            <text>Borden Tymchuk serves as a fireman on the homefront</text>
            <vet id="1456">Borden Tymchuk</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/01/1942" img="ya1.jpg">
            <text>Douglas Smith begins training as a pilot with the Royal Canadian Air Force (RCAF)</text>
            <vet id="1457">Douglas Smith</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/06/1943" img="gdf.jpg">
            <text>Nellie Rettenbacher enlists in the Canadian Army</text>
            <vet id="1458">Nellie Rettenbacher</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="20/12/1943" img="n30.jpg">
            <text>Fred Maiden is stationed in Italy during the Battle of Ortona</text>
            <vet id="1460">Fred Maiden</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/01/1941" img="5ib.jpg">
            <text>Gertrude Luscombe enlists in Vancouver and serves in an Army mess hall</text>
            <vet id="1463">Gertrude Luscombe nÈe Lovgren</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="15/08/1945" img="l5z.jpg">
            <text>Ruby Foley travels with others from the Royal Canadian Air Force (RCAF) to begin shutting down the eastern stations</text>
            <vet id="1465">Ruby Foley</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="05/06/1944" img="qy4.jpg">
            <text>Brian Murphy and troops enter Rome</text>
            <vet id="1466">Brian Murphy</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="13/10/1943" img="bcs.jpg">
            <text>Alan Cameron enlists in the Army</text>
            <vet id="1469">Alan Cameron</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/12/1943" img="xqkjitlpsqcnepogbdwg.jpg">
            <text>Eugenie Turner is posted overseas with the Royal Canadian Air Force (RCAF) bomber command</text>
            <vet id="1470">Eugenie Turner</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="24/05/1944" img="2ah.jpg">
            <text>Nigel Taylor is wounded advancing on the Hitler Line</text>
            <vet id="1473">Nigel Taylor</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="12/04/1942" img="lkg.jpg">
            <text>Michael Faryna is stationed as an air mechanic in Brandon, Manitoba</text>
            <vet id="1474">Michael Faryna</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="20/02/1940" img="2e1.jpg">
            <text>Donald Green enlists in the Navy</text>
            <vet id="1477">Donald Green</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="03/09/1941" img="n32.jpg">
            <text>Geoffry Arlington serves as a flying Instructor for the Royal Canadian Air Force (RCAF)</text>
            <vet id="1478">Geoffrey Alington</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/07/1941" img="4fj.jpg">
            <text>Steve Lubky serves as a driver mechanic for the Army</text>
            <vet id="1479">Steve Lubky</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/01/1941" img="teh.jpg">
            <text>Harold Walton enlists in the Army</text>
            <vet id="1480">Harold Walton</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="07/01/1944" img="cfu.jpg">
            <text>Kenneth France serves in the Royal Canadian Air Force (RCAF) Bomber Command</text>
            <vet id="1481">Kenneth France</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="06/06/1944" img="tlmfujmukxxkqszoqtan.jpg">
            <text>Doris Mitchell watches the planes fly over Sussex en route to Normandy</text>
            <vet id="1482">Doris Mitchell</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/08/1941" img="ksu.jpg">
            <text>Henry Mason enlists in the Navy</text>
            <vet id="1483">Henry Mason</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/04/1945" img="je1.jpg">
            <text>Gerald James is liberated from a Prisoner of War (POW) camp</text>
            <vet id="1486">Gerald James</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/01/1942" img="jul.jpg">
            <text>Robert Roth enlists in the Army</text>
            <vet id="1487">Robert Roth</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="18/09/1942" img="sx3.jpg">
            <text>Arthur Brown enlists and eventually fights in the Battle of Monte Cassino</text>
            <vet id="1488">Arthur Brown</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="16/05/1945" img="5vv.jpg">
            <text>Ron Rhine returns home after his vessel, HMCS Niobe, is decommissioned</text>
            <vet id="1493">Ron Rhine</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/01/1940" img="524.jpg">
            <text>Lewis Chow enlists and serves as a spy</text>
            <vet id="1494">Lewis Chow</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="06/08/1945" img="y3d.jpg">
            <text>Bruce Findley ends his tour of the Pacific as the first atomic bomb is dropped on Hiroshima</text>
            <vet id="1495">Bruce Findlay</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="26/05/1940" img="mkh.jpg">
            <text>Harry Ramsey is ordered to retreat in the evacuation of Dunkirk, France</text>
            <vet id="1498">Harry Ramsey</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="26/06/1941" img="e2z.jpg">
            <text>Winifred Sirois joins the Army and trains in Morse Code signalling</text>
            <vet id="1499">Winifred Sirois</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="20/06/1941" img="uvz.jpg">
            <text>Albert Sanderson enlists in the Air Force</text>
            <vet id="1500">Albert Sanderson</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="12/08/1944" img="0r0.jpg">
            <text>Douglas Storey participates in the battle of the Falaise Pocket</text>
            <vet id="1501">Douglas Storey</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/09/1943" img="ped.jpg">
            <text>Ray Sowerby enlists in the Army</text>
            <vet id="1502">Ray Sowerby</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/04/1945" img="a0h.jpg">
            <text>Clifford Hobbs serves in the Army in Holland</text>
            <vet id="1504">Clifford Hobbis</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/04/1944" img="oad.jpg">
            <text>John Pavey enlists as a Boy Seaman in the Royal Navy</text>
            <vet id="1505">John Pavey</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="20/07/1940" img="13o.jpg">
            <text>Philip Zeman enlists in the Royal Canadian Air Force (RCAF)</text>
            <vet id="1506">Philip Zeman</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/03/1945" img="n2k.jpg">
            <text>Robert Mason is permitted compassionate leave to visit his sick mother</text>
            <vet id="1511">Robert Mason</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="10/05/1945" img="kxm.jpg">
            <text>Rod McNeill and a German soldier inform German snipers the war has ended</text>
            <vet id="1515">Rod McNeill</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="08/05/1945" img="b0i.jpg">
            <text>Arthur Lyon is stationed in Germany when the war ends</text>
            <vet id="1517">Arthur Lyon</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/01/1942" img="t4f.jpg">
            <text>Herbert Shillington is stationed in North Africa in Tunis, Tunisia</text>
            <vet id="1518">Herbert Shillington</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="16/01/1943" img="0gx.jpg">
            <text>John Marchand enlists in the Army</text>
            <vet id="1521">John Marchand</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="24/02/1942" img="ajv.jpg">
            <text>John Penner enlists in the Air Force</text>
            <vet id="1524">John Penner</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="20/05/1942" img="s0y.jpg">
            <text>Frank Moore enlists in the Navy and serves as a 2nd Class Stoker</text>
            <vet id="1527">Frank Moore</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="08/05/1945" img="jb0.jpg">
            <text>Bill Ramsbottom celebrates VE Day in Camp Shilo</text>
            <vet id="1528">Bill Ramsbottom</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="09/07/1943" img="h0w.jpg">
            <text>Eric Saunders participates in the Allied invasion on Sicily</text>
            <vet id="1530">Eric Saunders</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/07/1943" img="xsw.jpg">
            <text>Stuart Richardson enlists in the Royal Canadian Air Force (RCAF)</text>
            <vet id="1531">Stuart Richardson</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/01/1941" img="i5j.jpg">
            <text>James Fox is sent to the UK as an engineer for the Army</text>
            <vet id="1532">James Fox</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="10/09/1945" img="fpenageilrxhpggaxzdv.jpg">
            <text>Stephen Bandurka ends his service with the Army</text>
            <vet id="1534">Stephen Bandurka</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="05/05/1944" img="w0m.jpg">
            <text>Jack Williams is certified as a Flying Instructor with the Royal Canadian Air Force (RCAF)</text>
            <vet id="1535">Jack Williams</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/12/1943" img="5pw.jpg">
            <text>Eric Hawley joins the Air Force</text>
            <vet id="1536">Eric Hawley</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="11/11/1945" img="ooa.jpg">
            <text>Michael Sich visits the Vimy Ridge Memorial in France</text>
            <vet id="1538">Michael Sich</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/04/1943" img="m1k.jpg">
            <text>Edgar Branch helps a British pilot after a crash</text>
            <vet id="1539">Edgar Branch</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/01/1940" img="cxn.jpg">
            <text>Arthur Gillan enlists in the Navy</text>
            <vet id="1541">Arthur Gillan</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/06/1944" img="tq4.jpg">
            <text>Joan Brownson enlists in the Army</text>
            <vet id="1680">Joan Brownson, nÈe Roberts</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="08/05/1945" img="5el.jpg">
            <text>Glenn Price and troops prepare vehicles for a victory parade in Holland</text>
            <vet id="1702">Glenn Price</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="08/05/1945" img="wak.jpg">
            <text>Rex Fendick is stationed in the English Channel when Victory in Europe is announced</text>
            <vet id="1735">Rex Rose</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="03/01/1942" img="ojzgufyvlxhuuglskrxq.jpg">
            <text>Art Meyer sails for England as part of the Royal Canadian Electrical and Mechanical Engineers Corps</text>
            <vet id="1738">Art Meyer</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="06/06/1944" img="5ry.jpg">
            <text>John Charlwood lands on Juno Beach for D-Day</text>
            <vet id="1797">John Charlwood</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/03/1943" img="g5v.jpg">
            <text>David Macdonald serves as an Air Force mechanic overseas</text>
            <vet id="1798">David MacDonald</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/10/1942" img="leibymwvvguepmwzypnt.jpg">
            <text>Sam Garnet joins the Royal Canadian Air Force (RCAF)</text>
            <vet id="1802">Sam Garnet</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="25/12/1944" img="lzuhdhbmraxnbcktezad.jpg">
            <text>Joseph Gautreau serves with the Army in Belgium</text>
            <vet id="1804">Joseph Gautreau</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/09/1944" img="53f.jpg">
            <text>Fraser Muir completes his first trip as part of the Bomber Command</text>
            <vet id="1811">Fraser Muir</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/01/1942" img="4ly.jpg">
            <text>Harold MacLauchlan serves in the Navy</text>
            <vet id="1821">Harold MacLauchlan</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="17/09/1944" img="bwumxdzeypfgwkkdcefp.jpg">
            <text>Bruce Cox serves as a paratrooper during the Battle of Arnhem</text>
            <vet id="1838">Bruce Cox</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="06/11/1943" img="sputvfzjcgqjkeylpcsq.jpg">
            <text>Pauline Cox Walker's ship is torpedoed</text>
            <vet id="1840">Pauline Cox Walker</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="08/08/1942" img="jyl.jpg">
            <text>Murray Whetung enlists in the Army</text>
            <vet id="1901">Murray Whetung</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/01/1943" img="ybi.jpg">
            <text>William Jepps enlists in the Navy and participates in the Murmansk Run</text>
            <vet id="1903">William Jepps</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/09/1944" img="hrgwdawqtctjlxmgjplv.jpg">
            <text>John Neville is deployed to France</text>
            <vet id="1920">John Neville</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="16/04/1945" img="ibt.jpg">
            <text>Louis Howard and crew aboard HMCS Sarnia fail to make contact with HMCS Esquimalt</text>
            <vet id="2137">Louis Howard</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="25/12/1944" img="ztp.jpg">
            <text>Hewitt Quick is deployed to Europe as a paratrooper</text>
            <vet id="2160">Hewitt Quick</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="21/06/1940" img="3ik.jpg">
            <text>Wladyslaw Pasaj, after hiding from the Germans, boards a train for Scotland</text>
            <vet id="2165">Wladyslaw Pasaj</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="20/08/1944" img="t2r.jpg">
            <text>Leo Pikulski takes part in the battle for Mont Ormel Ridge</text>
            <vet id="2169">Leo Pikulski</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/01/1943" img="z1l.jpg">
            <text>Marie Venne serves in the Royal Canadian Air Force (RCAF) - Women's Division</text>
            <vet id="2172">Marie Venne</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="15/07/1943" img="d23.jpg">
            <text>Art Lang is deployed overseas as part of the Army</text>
            <vet id="2176">Art Lang</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="17/12/1943" img="uak.jpg">
            <text>Alice Samuels trains in Vermilion with the Canadian Women's Army Corpy (CWAC)</text>
            <vet id="2177">Alice Samuel</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="30/11/1942" img="eem.jpg">
            <text>Daniel Lee enlists in the Army</text>
            <vet id="2178">Daniel Lee</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="12/06/1939" img="gqw.jpg">
            <text>Jospeh Forest enlists in the Army</text>
            <vet id="2188">Joseph Forest</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="21/02/1945" img="bgi.jpg">
            <text>Rodolophe Lavoie completes his first tour with the Royal Canadian Air Force (RCAF)</text>
            <vet id="2190">Rodolophe Lavoie</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="12/09/1944" img="lmc.jpg">
            <text>John Deluca participates in a raid of Wanne-Eckel in Germany</text>
            <vet id="2191">John Deluca</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="29/06/1942" img="wgq.jpg">
            <text>Gerald Connick sends birthday wishes home to his wife</text>
            <vet id="2192">Gerald Connick</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="04/07/1944" img="1ny.jpg">
            <text>Leslie Clarke is wounded while fighting in Carpiquet</text>
            <vet id="2193">Leslie Clarke</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="18/12/1942" img="z5l.jpg">
            <text>Kenneth Richardson is en route to serve in Europe when his son is born</text>
            <vet id="2195">Kenneth Richardson</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="09/05/1943" img="pg2.jpg">
            <text>Bob Worrell is promoted to Corporal in the Army</text>
            <vet id="2198">Bob Worrell</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/07/1942" img="rwh.jpg">
            <text>Horace Hetherington trains in England with the Canadian Army</text>
            <vet id="2202">Horace Hetherington</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="20/12/1943" img="elo.jpg">
            <text>Leraine Munn serves as an Infantry Signaler in the Battle of Ortona</text>
            <vet id="2205">Leraine Munn</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/11/1942" img="uby.jpg">
            <text>Giles Doucet and crew run into a pack of submarines on the Atlantic</text>
            <vet id="2206">Giles Doucet</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="08/05/1945" img="zueocfqhvbloctyfgwxp.jpg">
            <text>Ivan Killam serves as a guard in York when the war ends</text>
            <vet id="2210">Ivan Killam</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="11/10/1943" img="glu.jpg">
            <text>Doreen Newton joins the Canadian Women's Army Corps (CWAC)</text>
            <vet id="2211">Doreen Newton</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="20/06/1945" img="kxw.jpg">
            <text>Clinton Hayward returns home on SS Ile de France</text>
            <vet id="2212">Clinton Hayward</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/03/1943" img="2se.jpg">
            <text>Robert Breau continues Army training in Greenock, Scotland</text>
            <vet id="2214">Robert Breau</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/01/1940" img="2vz.jpg">
            <text>Fred Kirkpatrick enters the Air Force and serves at the Chatham base</text>
            <vet id="2216">Fred Kirkpatrick</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="15/06/1940" img="wua.jpg">
            <text>Mark Macdonald enlists in the Army and serves in the North Shore Regiment</text>
            <vet id="2219">Mark MacDonald</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="08/08/1944" img="ggd.jpg">
            <text>Allan MacDonald sees action in the Battle of Verrieres Ridge</text>
            <vet id="2220">Allan MacDonald</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/06/1944" img="ib1.jpg">
            <text>John Everard MacLean is housed with fellow recruits in Ditchling, UK</text>
            <vet id="2223">John Everard MacLean</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="28/05/1944" img="esk.jpg">
            <text>Bob Phair is wounded while fighting in Sicily</text>
            <vet id="2226">Bob Phair</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="26/05/1943" img="jsa.jpg">
            <text>Donovan Woelfle enlists in the Merchant Navy</text>
            <vet id="2228">Donovan Woelfle</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="15/08/1945" img="vff.jpg">
            <text>Joan Johnson goes to Trafalgar Square to celebrate VJ-Day</text>
            <vet id="2230">Joan Johnson, nÈe Cobb</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/01/1942" img="kmd.jpg">
            <text>Gordon Waters leaves the Air Force to join the Army</text>
            <vet id="2231">Gordon Waters</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/01/1942" img="s4j.jpg">
            <text>Benjamin Kenny joins theRoyal Canadian Air Force (RCAF)</text>
            <vet id="2234">Benjamin Kenny</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="07/06/1944" img="rd2.jpg">
            <text>John Leach lands additional tanks on the shores of Normandy</text>
            <vet id="2241">John Leach</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="06/07/1944" img="lro.jpg">
            <text>Fred Bryant serves in France as a medical officer</text>
            <vet id="2243">Fred Bryant</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/07/1944" img="cey.jpg">
            <text>Owen Lockyer and the 4th Canadian Armoured Regiment arrive in Normandy</text>
            <vet id="2247">Owen Lockyer</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/01/1943" img="uio.jpg">
            <text>Ruby Somers becomes a Women's Royal Navy (WRN) and is stationed in Newfoundland</text>
            <vet id="2248">Ruby Somers</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="17/02/1945" img="um1.jpg">
            <text>Henry Masters enlists in the Army</text>
            <vet id="2250">Henry Masters</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="13/01/1940" img="2ln.jpg">
            <text>Eileen Green is married to Tom Green while serving as a Women's Royal Navy Service (WRNS)</text>
            <vet id="2256">Eileen Green, nÈe Short</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/01/1941" img="nuk.jpg">
            <text>Molly Campbell serves as a nursery nurse in England</text>
            <vet id="2257">Molly Campbell</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="06/06/1944" img="g3m.jpg">
            <text>Belmont Shannon participates in D-Day landings</text>
            <vet id="2261">Belmont Shannon</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/07/1943" img="ddo.jpg">
            <text>William Hitchon serves as protection for the Royal family in England</text>
            <vet id="2262">William Hitchon</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/09/1945" img="fxf.jpg">
            <text>Clyde Bougie travels to Hong Kong to free prisoners of war</text>
            <vet id="2266">Clyde Bougie</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="06/07/1943" img="qwuipvcvisuoipqvbfig.jpg">
            <text>Audrey Detheridge is called to duty in Toronto for the Canaadian Woman's Army Core (CWAC)</text>
            <vet id="2267">Audrey Detheridge</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="08/03/1945" img="gm1.jpg">
            <text>Edward Jesseman is wounded in Germany</text>
            <vet id="2269">Edward Jesseman</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="19/07/1942" img="gts.jpg">
            <text>John Bylik enlists in the Navy</text>
            <vet id="2270">John Bilyk</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/09/1943" img="smf.jpg">
            <text>John Cathie and troops land in Italy</text>
            <vet id="2271">John Cathie</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="28/06/1941" img="hxr.jpg">
            <text>Harold Shaw and his twin brother enlist in the Air Force</text>
            <vet id="2272">Harold Shaw</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="02/07/1941" img="ejqwxlepaniwdiukwbso.jpg">
            <text>Sol Zulauf enlists in the Army</text>
            <vet id="2273">Sol Zulauf</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="24/12/1943" img="bfasuqyvnfmsgbtegtnr.jpg">
            <text>Mendel Thresher is interrogated by Germans on induction to a Prisoners of War (POW) camp</text>
            <vet id="2274">Mendel Thrasher</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="30/06/1940" img="wzv.jpg">
            <text>Jan Szklarz is serving in the Polish Army when he is captured by Germans</text>
            <vet id="2276">Jan Szklarz</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="10/01/1940" img="qouycgfyyhxdglnefqjp.jpg">
            <text>Harold Hall enlists in the Army</text>
            <vet id="2277">Harold Hall</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="13/07/1943" img="ov0.jpg">
            <text>Frederick Chapman and his regiment land in Sicily</text>
            <vet id="2280">Frederick Chapman</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="13/08/1944" img="gvv.jpg">
            <text>Joe Bill is wounded while fighting in France</text>
            <vet id="2282">Joe Bill</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="29/07/1941" img="0pv.jpg">
            <text>Warren Urquhart enlists in the Navy</text>
            <vet id="2285">Warren Urquhart</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="24/12/1943" img="uho.jpg">
            <text>Bill Teleske is stationed in the trenches in Ortona, Italy on Christmas Eve</text>
            <vet id="2286">Bill Teleske</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/10/1944" img="zwe.jpg">
            <text>Ross Hamilton serves in the Royal Canadian Air Force (RCAF) 407 Squadron in Sussex</text>
            <vet id="2288">Ross Hamilton</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/06/1940" img="aqv.jpg">
            <text>Roman Zaraza serves in the Polish Army in Lithuania</text>
            <vet id="2289">Roman Zaraza</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="21/08/1944" img="lmc.jpg">
            <text>Godfrey Schaupmeyer and his division serve in the Falaise Gap</text>
            <vet id="2291">Godfrey Schaupmeyer</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/03/1943" img="sf3.jpg">
            <text>Stephen Boczar and his squadron complete air raids on Berlin</text>
            <vet id="2293">Stephen Boczar</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="04/01/1943" img="vij.jpg">
            <text>Rudy Deutsch enlists as a stretcher bearer in the Army</text>
            <vet id="2295">Rudy Deutsch</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="15/05/1944" img="a42.jpg">
            <text>Gordon Wright participates in the English Channel blackade leading up to D-Day</text>
            <vet id="2298">Gordon Wright</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="09/07/1944" img="uzl.jpg">
            <text>Frank Wong serves in the 2nd National Workshop Unit in Caen, France</text>
            <vet id="2299">Frank Wong</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="16/01/1944" img="sdj.jpg">
            <text>Victor Wong serves as a "Zombie" for the Canadian Army</text>
            <vet id="2310">Victor Wong</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/01/1942" img="0q3.jpg">
            <text>Peggy Lee serves in the St. John's Ambulance Corps</text>
            <vet id="2313">Peggy Lee</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/01/1942" img="3yh.jpg">
            <text>Norm Jenkins enlists in the Royal Canadian Air Force (RCAF) and oversees engine and propellor manufacturing</text>
            <vet id="2317">Norm Jenkins</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="06/06/1944" img="weu.jpg">
            <text>Joseph Sullivan serves in the 3rd Canadian Infantry Division during D-Day</text>
            <vet id="2318">Joseph Sullivan</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="25/12/1944" img="gjl.jpg">
            <text>Fred Guest finishes his tour with Bomber Command during the Battle of the Bulge</text>
            <vet id="2319">Fred Guest</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="07/06/1944" img="lm3.jpg">
            <text>Gordon Ritchie and 429 Royal Canadian Air Force (RCAF) Squadron are attacked while on mission in France</text>
            <vet id="2320">Gordon Ritchie</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="20/12/1943" img="fenyfizggokwhpedgmrj.jpg">
            <text>Gordon MacKenzie partcipates in the Battle of Ortona</text>
            <vet id="2321">Gordon MacKenzie</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/12/1944" img="myb.jpg">
            <text>Leonard Bookbinder serves in the navy on HMCS New Liskeard</text>
            <vet id="2325">Leonard Bookbinder</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="29/12/1942" img="wgi.jpg">
            <text>Robert O'Conner enlists in the Air Force</text>
            <vet id="2327">Robert O'Connor</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="04/07/1944" img="1pl.jpg">
            <text>William Rawluk and the Calgary Highlanders land in France</text>
            <vet id="2329">William Rawluk</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/02/1944" img="42z.jpg">
            <text>Jean Holmes enlists as a nurse with the Army and serves in England</text>
            <vet id="2331">Jean Holmes</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="10/07/1943" img="wmi.jpg">
            <text>Maurice White lands in Sicily, Italy</text>
            <vet id="2333">Maurice White</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="23/07/1940" img="m55.jpg">
            <text>Roy Page lies about his age and enters the Army</text>
            <vet id="2356">Roy Page</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="25/12/1944" img="551.jpg">
            <text>Doug Dickson proposes to his future wife with the ring he paid for by flying under a bridge in Lethridge, AB</text>
            <vet id="2357">Doug Dickson</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/01/1943" img="jt5.jpg">
            <text>George Ens enlists and trains in Camp Borden, Ontario</text>
            <vet id="2358">George Ens</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="29/04/1943" img="lry.jpg">
            <text>Jim Venables serves in the 435 Squadron making runs in Burma</text>
            <vet id="2359">Jim Venables</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="25/09/1944" img="vfv.jpg">
            <text>Russell Earl completes a bombing raid in Calais, France</text>
            <vet id="2360">Russell Earl</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/06/1944" img="oif.jpg">
            <text>Paul Bentley is stationed in Shaftesbury, England before D-Day</text>
            <vet id="2362">Paul Bentley</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/08/1941" img="2ck.jpg">
            <text>Harold ward transfers over to the Royal Canadian Air Force (RCAF)</text>
            <vet id="2366">Harold Ward</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="10/08/1943" img="i5d.jpg">
            <text>Arthur Dean participates as an Air Bomber in a raid on Nuremburg, Germany</text>
            <vet id="2367">Arthur Dean</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/12/1944" img="uh1.jpg">
            <text>Archie Stover is part of Canadian reinforcements in France</text>
            <vet id="2369">Archie Stover</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="25/12/1944" img="ovj.jpg">
            <text>George Ufnal and troops spend Christmas in Ortona, Italy</text>
            <vet id="2370">George Ufnal</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="15/12/1944" img="0zu.jpg">
            <text>Bill Baluk has his first mission in Bomber Command over Ludwickshaven, Germany</text>
            <vet id="2371">Bill Baluk</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/09/1942" img="fpoaiapokxmndmvntfpm.jpg">
            <text>Joe Hickson enlists in the Air Force</text>
            <vet id="2372">Joe Hickson</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="07/09/1940" img="bvq.jpg">
            <text>Diane Hawthorne serves in the army during the London Blitz</text>
            <vet id="2373">Diane Hawthorne</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="06/06/1944" img="fh3.jpg">
            <text>Vernon Barr participates in D-day</text>
            <vet id="2374">Vernon Barr</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/01/1944" img="cdz.jpg">
            <text>Alexander Bramson begins service on HMCS Ettrick</text>
            <vet id="2376">Alexander Bramson</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="03/05/1944" img="qzq.jpg">
            <text>Lawrence Weldon completes his Navy training in Toronto, Ontario</text>
            <vet id="2378">Lawrence Weldon</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/01/1943" img="mkr.jpg">
            <text>Beryl Howe enlists with the Women's Royal Navy Service (WRNS) as a cryptologist</text>
            <vet id="2380">Beryl Howe, nÈe Howard</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="09/07/1944" img="lg2.jpg">
            <text>Alfred Warford serves in the army during the Battle for Caen</text>
            <vet id="2381">Alfred Warford</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/01/1944" img="oam.jpg">
            <text>John Wasilenchuk and crew are torpedoed off the coast of North Africa</text>
            <vet id="2382">John Wasilenchuk</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="20/10/1940" img="4d3.jpg">
            <text>Catherine Anderson is called to duty for the Royal Canadian Air Force (RCAF)</text>
            <vet id="2384">Catherine Anderson</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="11/08/1940" img="ekh.jpg">
            <text>Edwin Badger enlists in the Navy</text>
            <vet id="2387">Edwin Badger</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="09/09/1939" img="umo.jpg">
            <text>Edward Plummer enlists in the Royal Canadian Air Force (RCAF)</text>
            <vet id="2393">Edward Plummer</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="28/05/1945" img="mmk.jpg">
            <text>Ian Herd's fellow navigators die in a crash off the coast of Sri Lanka</text>
            <vet id="2395">Ian Herd</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="11/01/1943" img="ajirtqehzgygloassalq.jpg">
            <text>Eugene Steeves enlists in the Air Force</text>
            <vet id="2423">Eugene Steeves</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="10/11/1943" img="xrdqrkhzjtmlkjnepahw.jpg">
            <text>Richard Dutka is captured by Germans after his plane is shot down after a bombing raid</text>
            <vet id="2427">Richard Dutka</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="24/10/1943" img="zmh.jpg">
            <text>Kenneth Marchant finishes his basic training and is shipped to BC</text>
            <vet id="2428">Kenneth Marchant</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="12/06/1944" img="3zr.jpg">
            <text>George Heron and crew support troops already in Normandy</text>
            <vet id="2432">George Heron</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="27/06/1944" img="tde.jpg">
            <text>Herbert Britton and crew arrive in France</text>
            <vet id="2434">Herbert Britton</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/12/1942" img="1ww.jpg">
            <text>Hugh Kidney enlists in the Army and serves as a dispatch rider</text>
            <vet id="2435">Hugh Kidney</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/01/1943" img="0ei.jpg">
            <text>Aldfred Carpenter serves as in the Navy doing minesweeping</text>
            <vet id="2436">Alfred Carpenter</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/07/1943" img="szuhdamubnocajzryvsz.jpg">
            <text>Harry Inns and the 621 Strike Squadron make their way up the eastern coast of Africa</text>
            <vet id="2438">Harry Inns</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/04/1945" img="z3l.jpg">
            <text>Robert Yule boards RMS Aquitania to serve in Europe</text>
            <vet id="2440">Robert Yule</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="11/09/1939" img="fa3.jpg">
            <text>Albert Hogg enlists as a medic for the Army</text>
            <vet id="2441">Albert Hogg</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/02/1943" img="ecf.jpg">
            <text>Blanche Lund performs as a dancer for troops with the Navy Special Service</text>
            <vet id="2446">Blanche Lund</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="19/09/1944" img="orn.jpg">
            <text>Richard Clements is called to serve in the Army</text>
            <vet id="2449">Richard Clements</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/01/1944" img="sdn.jpg">
            <text>Paul Chan and troops are deployed to Sri Lanka</text>
            <vet id="2454">Paul Chan</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="07/03/1945" img="fi0.jpg">
            <text>Wendell Harper gets a surprise attack by a German air fighter</text>
            <vet id="2458">Wendell Harper</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="09/01/1940" img="p4d.jpg">
            <text>Oscar Fetini joins the Army in his native Egypt</text>
            <vet id="2459">Oscar Fiteni</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/01/1945" img="ylwfajesabcgzylkdrzp.jpg">
            <text>Weldon Moffatt performs his first mission for the Royal Canadian Air Force (RCAF)</text>
            <vet id="2460">Weldon Moffatt</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="25/12/1944" img="inhjrhnyuslwcgkeyxjj.jpg">
            <text>Stanley Creelman spends Christmas fighting in Ortona, Italy</text>
            <vet id="2462">Stanley Creelman</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="11/02/1940" img="1nk.jpg">
            <text>Daniel Goniea is called to serve in the Navy</text>
            <vet id="2463">Daniel Goniea</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="15/07/1944" img="lr2.jpg">
            <text>William Sheppard arrives in Normandy</text>
            <vet id="2466">William Sheppard</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="08/06/1944" img="cvr.jpg">
            <text>Lloyd Queen and reinforcements arrive on Juno Beach</text>
            <vet id="2478">Lloyd Queen</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/07/1944" img="gxo.jpg">
            <text>Herbert Heron gets married in Canada</text>
            <vet id="2479">Herbert Heron</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/01/1943" img="tl0.jpg">
            <text>Cyril Hammond trains with the Royal Canadian Air Force (RCAF)</text>
            <vet id="2480">Cyril Hammond</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="28/08/1942" img="3pr.jpg">
            <text>Frank Reneau begins serving in the Navy</text>
            <vet id="2485">Frank Reneau</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="07/09/1942" img="4x3.jpg">
            <text>Robert McGirr enlists in the Army</text>
            <vet id="2489">Robert McGirr</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="22/07/1944" img="qrarbvnvfwezelaldckd.jpg">
            <text>Stanley Anderson is wounded in battle</text>
            <vet id="2491">Stanley Anderson</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="15/03/1940" img="lgk.jpg">
            <text>William Elliot joins the Army as a driver</text>
            <vet id="2493">William Elliott</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="12/04/1943" img="wre.jpg">
            <text>Clarence Sweeney enlists in the Navy</text>
            <vet id="2496">Clarence Sweeney</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="03/04/1945" img="exlraecgldrgmarvoncn.jpg">
            <text>Joan Manning runs into her childhood friend before he is sent back into battle</text>
            <vet id="2499">Joan Manning</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/01/1942" img="yac.jpg">
            <text>Raymond Lefrancois joins the navy over the Army</text>
            <vet id="2509">Raymond Lefrancois</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="02/09/1940" img="n5f.jpg">
            <text>Leo Fortin begins primary training in Quebec</text>
            <vet id="2510">LÈo Fortin</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="24/03/1944" img="351.jpg">
            <text>Clifford Mizzen qualifies as an air gunner</text>
            <vet id="2511">Clifford Mizzen</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="17/09/1943" img="ugf.jpg">
            <text>Romuald Pepin is certified as a gunner with the Royal Canadian Air Force (RCAF)</text>
            <vet id="2512">Romuald Pepin</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="08/05/1945" img="xdcrizpwnlzbnudizoqd.jpg">
            <text>Emile Turcot and troops take the city of Oldenburg, Germany before the war ends</text>
            <vet id="2513">Emile Turcot</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="19/08/1942" img="jxq.jpg">
            <text>Roland Gravel survives the raid on Dieppe</text>
            <vet id="2515">Roland Gravel</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="15/08/1945" img="lzn.jpg">
            <text>Jacques Catudel is stationed in Vancouver during Victory in Japan Day</text>
            <vet id="2516">Jacques Catudal</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/01/1945" img="3bt.jpg">
            <text>Léon DesLauriers enlists in the Army</text>
            <vet id="2517">LÈon DesLauriers</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="08/05/1945" img="q3k.jpg">
            <text>Percy Jackson decides to stay and serve in Germany for another year</text>
            <vet id="2518">Percy Jackson</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="23/01/1941" img="xrf.jpg">
            <text>Marcel Caron is called to serve in the Army</text>
            <vet id="2519">Marcel Caron</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="22/01/1945" img="rps.jpg">
            <text>Geoffrey Knowles participates in the Battle for Kangaw in Burma</text>
            <vet id="2520">Geoffrey Knowles</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/06/1943" img="2gp.jpg">
            <text>Farnand Giguere is wounded while training in Farnham, Quebec</text>
            <vet id="2521">Fernand Giguere</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="19/02/1941" img="tdy.jpg">
            <text>Charles Marinier enlists in the Royal Canadian Air Force (RCAF)</text>
            <vet id="2522">Charles Marinier</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/05/1945" img="wwd.jpg">
            <text>Jean-Paul Bertrand and the 2nd Division hold a number of surrendered Germany troops</text>
            <vet id="2523">Jean-Paul Bertrand</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/01/1940" img="xyh.jpg">
            <text>Henri Botham enlists in the Air Force</text>
            <vet id="2524">Henri Botham</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="07/12/1941" img="m5a.jpg">
            <text>Georges Charrier is aboard HMCS Windflower when it collides with a cargo ship</text>
            <vet id="2525">Georges Charrier</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="15/08/1945" img="fbs.jpg">
            <text>Marc Boivin trains with the Royal Canadian Air Force (RCAF) Alouettes Squadron when the war ends in Japan</text>
            <vet id="2526">Marc Boivin</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="20/12/1943" img="nse.jpg">
            <text>Victor Guérin is stationed with D Company, Royal 22nd Regiment, during the Battle for Ortona</text>
            <vet id="2528">Victor GuÈrin</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="08/05/1945" img="rvj.jpg">
            <text>Frederick Gray serves with the Royal Canadian Air Force (RCAF) in Madras, India, during VE-Day</text>
            <vet id="2529">Frederick Gray</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/05/1942" img="kst.jpg">
            <text>Rena Chaplin begins training in the Royal Canadian Air Force (RCAF) - Women's Division</text>
            <vet id="2530">Rena Chaplin</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/09/1944" img="3bh.jpg">
            <text>Gerald Derick travels to Europe to fight in the trenches</text>
            <vet id="2533">Gerald Derick</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="06/06/1944" img="4cv.jpg">
            <text>Norma Dillon is on night duty in Toronto during the Normandy Invasions</text>
            <vet id="2536">Norma Dillon</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/05/1940" img="t33.jpg">
            <text>Jerry O'Conner is captured as a German Prisoners of War (POW)</text>
            <vet id="2539">Jerry O'Connor</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="08/05/1945" img="u5w.jpg">
            <text>Harry Fogel celebrates in London during VE-Day</text>
            <vet id="2541">Harry Fogel</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/04/1944" img="ms2.jpg">
            <text>Joseph Abramovitch lands in Italy</text>
            <vet id="2542">Joseph Abramovitch</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="19/04/1941" img="rcj.jpg">
            <text>Hyman Sazant enlists in the Special Forces</text>
            <vet id="2543">Hyman Sazant</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="30/01/1943" img="i1i.jpg">
            <text>Doug Mullen is transferred to British Columbia as part of the Air Force</text>
            <vet id="2544">Doug Mullen</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="07/03/1941" img="kdmtogbemwbyrewfkjgu.jpg">
            <text>Robert Perry enlists in the Royal Canadian Air Force (RCAF) as an air bomber</text>
            <vet id="2550">Robert Perry</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="19/01/1943" img="kdw.jpg">
            <text>John Mornan is sworn into the Royal Canadian Air Force (RCAF)</text>
            <vet id="2551">John Mornan</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="11/06/1944" img="qhs.jpg">
            <text>Alexander Paton and troops land in France to capture the Carpiquet airport</text>
            <vet id="2552">Alexander Paton</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/07/1945" img="hkh.jpg">
            <text>James Lovie finishes his tour and returns to Britain</text>
            <vet id="2553">James Lovie</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="06/06/1944" img="oan.jpg">
            <text>Gillis Mackinnon serves in a hospital for Allied troops</text>
            <vet id="2556">Gillis Mackinnon</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="28/04/1943" img="gah.jpg">
            <text>George Kehl begins active service with the Navy</text>
            <vet id="2579">George Kehl</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/01/1945" img="xka.jpg">
            <text>June Melton transfers to a hospital in Dartmouth, Nova Scotia</text>
            <vet id="2580">June Melton</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="15/06/1945" img="pns.jpg">
            <text>Lorna Collacott gets married on her Friday off in England</text>
            <vet id="2583">Lorna Collacott</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/04/1942" img="rawaduhbwjhrrjmfwsqk.jpg">
            <text>Selwyn Stephens begins service with the Air Force</text>
            <vet id="2584">Selwyn Stephens</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="12/02/1943" img="n0v.jpg">
            <text>Bert Barker tries to join the Air Force 3 months too young</text>
            <vet id="2590">Bert Barker</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="19/08/1942" img="k1r.jpg">
            <text>Arthur Drake participates in the raid on Dieppe</text>
            <vet id="2593">Arthur Drake</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="10/05/1945" img="yr1.jpg">
            <text>John Kubis and crew of HMCS Rockcliffe capture a German submarine</text>
            <vet id="2601">John Kubis</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="05/06/1944" img="qqy.jpg">
            <text>John O'Neill and troops sail to Normandy, only to be recalled and invade the next day</text>
            <vet id="2603">John O'Neill</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="09/09/1939" img="b0f.jpg">
            <text>Kenneth McKenzie enlists in the Army</text>
            <vet id="2606">Kenneth McKenzie</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="09/07/1944" img="o2s.jpg">
            <text>John Anderson performs a bomb sweep in Bethune, France</text>
            <vet id="2610">John Anderson</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="09/08/1944" img="rhwbtecfjxokvjiucxgc.jpg">
            <text>Orille Hogue participates in the "big push" to close the Falaise Gap in France</text>
            <vet id="2616">Orille Hogue</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/04/1945" img="4y4.jpg">
            <text>John Harmer sees Japanese kamikaze pilots attack HMS Victorious</text>
            <vet id="2619">John Harmer</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="09/07/1943" img="pcb.jpg">
            <text>Sheridan Atkinson participates in the Allied landing of Sicily</text>
            <vet id="2620">Sheridan Atkinson</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/01/1943" img="who.jpg">
            <text>Joan Dowe serves in the Women's Army Corps (WAC) with the coastal defense of Britain</text>
            <vet id="2623">Joan Dowe</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/01/1941" img="1gl.jpg">
            <text>Howard O'Conner serves as bomber pilot in the Royal Air Force (RAF)</text>
            <vet id="2624">Howard O'Connor</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="15/08/1945" img="dfp.jpg">
            <text>Kent Ford is training for Pacific bombing operations when Victory in Japan is declared</text>
            <vet id="2625">Kent Ford</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="06/06/1944" img="4ws.jpg">
            <text>Elisabeth Wallis serves in a naval hospital during D-Day</text>
            <vet id="2626">Elisabeth Wallis</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/06/1944" img="5er.jpg">
            <text>Roderick White begins service in England</text>
            <vet id="2627">Roderick White</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/09/1941" img="zjj.jpg">
            <text>Peter Chance is stationed in Malaysia with the Navy</text>
            <vet id="2628">Peter Chance</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/10/1940" img="k4n.jpg">
            <text>Cyril Yarnell enlists in the Air Force and tours with the 403 Squadron</text>
            <vet id="2630">Cyril Yarnell</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/05/1943" img="yvb.jpg">
            <text>Agnes Ward and fellow Women Division (WDs) depart for England</text>
            <vet id="2631">Agnes Ward</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="03/07/1941" img="pjr.jpg">
            <text>Valerie Simmons survives a bombing in a London nightclub</text>
            <vet id="2633">Valerie Simmons</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/08/1943" img="fyp.jpg">
            <text>Frank Round and troops fight their way up the Liri Valley in Italy</text>
            <vet id="2636">Frank Round</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/07/1943" img="muvkjzjgvapuomzdlzzt.jpg">
            <text>John Beach finishes his medical training early and serves in the Royal Canadian Army Medical Corps (RCAMC)</text>
            <vet id="2637">John Beach</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/01/1942" img="vdq.jpg">
            <text>Allen Lucas enlists as a soldier in the Army</text>
            <vet id="2638">Allen Lucas</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/11/1944" img="5p5.jpg">
            <text>Jim Caird operates as a tank driver in the town of Rijssen, Holland</text>
            <vet id="2639">Jim Caird</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/01/1940" img="mx5.jpg">
            <text>Margaret Duff is stationed in Scotland with the Air Force</text>
            <vet id="2655">Margaret Duff</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="18/12/1942" img="b20.jpg">
            <text>Robert Fletcher is commisioned into the Air Force and serves in North Africa</text>
            <vet id="2656">Robert Fletcher</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="17/03/1944" img="twz.jpg">
            <text>Bill Hoag is bombed while stationed in Burma</text>
            <vet id="2662">Bill Hoag</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/11/1942" img="eoz.jpg">
            <text>Frank Boyd enlists in the 101 RAF Squadron</text>
            <vet id="2667">Frank Boyd</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="25/12/1944" img="hbxrbfemnfxexyzxjmxb.jpg">
            <text>Frederick Nash and crew crash into a German submarine</text>
            <vet id="2668">Frederick Nash</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/10/1939" img="1lp.jpg">
            <text>Dietrich Puetter enlists in the German Air Force</text>
            <vet id="2679">Dietrich Puetter</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/01/1941" img="w53.jpg">
            <text>Gordon Redcliffe joins the Air Force as a mechanic</text>
            <vet id="2681">Gordon Redcliffe</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="25/04/1944" img="r3k.jpg">
            <text>William Husson bombs the Obersaltzburg, Hitler's hideaway in the Swiss Alps</text>
            <vet id="2685">William Husson</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="17/01/1944" img="idpgjyttggmzforuwzen.jpg">
            <text>Bruce Bullock is injured while fighting in the Battle for Monte Cassino</text>
            <vet id="2686">Bruce Bullock</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/01/1942" img="tep.jpg">
            <text>Lorne Yule enlists in the Air Force as a mechanic</text>
            <vet id="2695">Lorne Yule</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/10/1944" img="3gm.jpg">
            <text>Maurice Hundleby is sent to the European front</text>
            <vet id="2696">Maurice Hundleby</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="09/07/1944" img="ecixezknlotgvuxfostx.jpg">
            <text>Margaret Fletcher tends to troops injured in the Battle of Caen</text>
            <vet id="2698">Margaret Fletcher</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/01/1943" img="2qp.jpg">
            <text>Lillian Wylie serves in the British Women's Land Army working in agriculture</text>
            <vet id="2705">Lillian Wylie (nÈe Warren)</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/09/1942" img="hzgntfpaeoavakmmyezr.jpg">
            <text>Nora Oliver joins the WRENS and works for Lord Mountbatten's headquarters</text>
            <vet id="2706">Nora Oliver (nÈe Carrington)</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/01/1940" img="ghn.jpg">
            <text>Isobel Smith joins the air force first as a cook, then as a nurse's aid</text>
            <vet id="2709">Isobel Smith</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="16/10/1940" img="mfljrgceicqygnaujfbr.jpg">
            <text>Charles Lepine enlists in the Royal Canadian Air Force (RCAF)</text>
            <vet id="2714">Charles Lepine</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="29/12/1942" img="nia.jpg">
            <text>Fred Russell enlists in the Air Force as a musician</text>
            <vet id="2715">Fred Russell</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/01/1942" img="0fa.jpg">
            <text>Daisy Bird enlists in the Women's Auxiliary Air Force</text>
            <vet id="2716">Daisy Bird</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="22/02/1944" img="loz.jpg">
            <text>Fred Coonstable begins service in the Navy</text>
            <vet id="2717">Fred Constable</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="20/12/1945" img="cyfvlqdelfcuqmfiyyqx.jpg">
            <text>John Kirk returns home to Victoria, British Columbia</text>
            <vet id="2720">John Kirk</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="07/11/1944" img="cfqybhwblurgfalxzrff.jpg">
            <text>Philip Bissell enlists in the Navy</text>
            <vet id="2723">Philip Bissell</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/10/1939" img="y2f.jpg">
            <text>Terence Elworthy is a cadet when he is called to service in Hong Kong</text>
            <vet id="2737">Terence Elworthy</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/03/1943" img="lbucpjbqnddqjnzsflht.jpg">
            <text>Pater Thomas and crew are attacked by a German submarine in the Bay of Biscay</text>
            <vet id="2740">Peter Thomas</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/05/1941" img="nvqqtvzmbgdvndawjggt.jpg">
            <text>Kenneth Pask enlists in the Air Force and serves in the South Pacific</text>
            <vet id="2741">Kenneth Pask</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/01/1941" img="w42.jpg">
            <text>Norma Curry joins the Women's Auxiliary Air Force</text>
            <vet id="2742">Norma Curry</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="15/01/1945" img="sgsbdvalyylggowjukpx.jpg">
            <text>Mr. Richards arrives in Horsham, England</text>
            <vet id="2743">C Richards</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/01/1943" img="icskgmzsyutxermkwyry.jpg">
            <text>Albert Walsh enlists in the Army</text>
            <vet id="2744">Albert Walsh</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="19/01/1945" img="bnzkyukbuqxyxivwukoo.jpg">
            <text>Arthur Anderson is relocated in a Prisoner of War (POW) camp</text>
            <vet id="2756">Arthur Anderson</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="19/08/1942" img="050.jpg">
            <text>Wilson Large fights in the Battle of Dieppe</text>
            <vet id="2777">Wilson Large</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="06/09/1943" img="zlnuohjgrtptabcicbin.jpg">
            <text>Henry Seewald joins the Air Force and builds radios</text>
            <vet id="2800">Henry Seewald</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/05/1943" img="03w.jpg">
            <text>Wilma Cooke travels to European Front as a nurse</text>
            <vet id="2816">Wilma Cooke</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/05/1943" img="uw5.jpg">
            <text>Hilda Senter serves is Egypt with the Air Force</text>
            <vet id="2818">Hilda Senter</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="30/06/1943" img="mddvhwcuhrlkvnjmhbxs.jpg">
            <text>Joyce Mullen finishes her training with the Royal Canadian Air Force Women's Division</text>
            <vet id="2837">Joyce Mullen</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="06/04/1944" img="qydxnraltcqpnonoetyh.jpg">
            <text>John Shaw completes his Engine Room Artificer Apprenticeship with the Navy</text>
            <vet id="2850">John Shaw</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/02/1945" img="ubgcyufzvvliypxgwndk.jpg">
            <text>Walter Weir joins The Royal Regina Rifles Regiment in the Army</text>
            <vet id="2851">Walter Weir</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="03/09/1943" img="dunuxkuayfrhvteqfjgz.jpg">
            <text>Henry Love and troops cross the Straits of Messina in Italy</text>
            <vet id="2853">Howard Love</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="22/02/1942" img="bwlvamovbrmpjjoffxfy.jpg">
            <text>John Yeomans is shot down while returning from air raid over Germany</text>
            <vet id="2855">John Yeomans</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="27/12/1944" img="fmixzgnxdtmxccaatshe.jpg">
            <text>Donald Bowman and crew on HMSC Edmunston sink a German submarine</text>
            <vet id="2863">Donald Bowman</vet>
        </event>

    </events>
    
</timelineData>