<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<timelineData>

	<links>
		<smallThumb url="http://www.thememoryproject.com/VeteranAssets/Artifact/Thumb_Small/" />
		<vetProfile url="http://www.thememoryproject.com/Stories/Veteran-Profile.aspx?itemid=" />
	</links>
	
	<events>
	
		<event date="1945-05-08" imgID="bcs">
			<text>Victory in Europe Day (VE-Day) is declared, ending the European portion of the Second World War</text>
			<vets>1065 1096 1297</vets>
		</event>
			
		<event date="1940-09-24" imgID="axl">
			<text>Her Majesty's Canadian ships Annapolis, Columbia, Niagara, St. Clair, St. Croix and St. Francis, ex-American destroyers from the fifty given to Great Britain in exchange for bases, are commissioned into the Royal Canadian Navy</text>
			<vets>1069</vets>
		</event>
		
		<event date="1940-07-22" imgID="3cg">
			<text>The British Commonwealth Air Training Plan begins operations when students began training at No. 1 Service Flying Training School at Camp Borden, Ontario</text>
			<vets>1339 1123</vets>
		</event>

		<event date="1944-02-11" imgID="3kh">
			<text>a Wellington bomber of No.407 Squadron, Royal Canadian Air Force, sinks the German submarine U-283 in the North Atlantic</text>
			<vets>2288</vets>
		</event>

		<event date="1939-09-01" imgID="lus">
			<text>the 1st and 2nd Canadian Divisions are authorized as the Canadian Active Service Force.  The Royal Canadian Navy, Royal Canadian Navy Reserve and Royal Canadian Navy Volunteer Reserve are placed on active service</text>
			<vets>1452 2271 2295 2270</vets>
		</event>
	
		<event date="1939-09-04" imgID="cfc">
			<text>Pilot Officer S.R. Henderson, a Canadian serving in No.206 Squadron, Royal Air Force, becomes the first Canadian to participate in an operational sortie during the Second World War when he serves as the lead navigator in a bomber force attacking German warships</text>
			<vets>1050</vets>
		</event>
		
		<event date="1939-09-10" imgID="u1p">
			<text>Canada declares war on Germany</text>
			<vets>1345 2241 2230 1478</vets>
		</event>

		<event date="1939-09-16" imgID="blc">
			<text>convoy HX-1 sails from Halifax for Great Britain with a local escort including HMCS St. Laurent and HMCS Saguenay</text>
			<vets>1154 2137</vets>
		</event>

		<event date="1939-09-19" imgID="t0r">
			<text>the Honourable Norman McLeod Rogers is appointed Minister of National Defence</text>
			<vets>1104</vets>
		</event>

		<event date="1939-09-29" imgID="xit">
			<text>S/L W.I. Clements, attached to No.53 (Blenheim) Squadron, Royal Air Force, becomes the first member of the Royal Canadian Air Force to fly over enemy territory when his squadron makes a long distance reconnaissance flight over Germany</text>
			<vets>1307</vets>
		</event>

		<event date="1939-11-06" imgID="d1r">
			<text>the formation of the Organization and Training Division at RCAF headquarters is authorized</text>
			<vets>1102 1059 1108 1111</vets>
		</event>

		<event date="1939-12-10" imgID="vkc">
			<text>the first Canadian troop convoy sails for Britain escorted out of Halifax by HMC ships Ottawa, Restigouche, Fraser and St. Laurent</text>
			<vets>1119 1154 1220</vets>
		</event>

		<event date="1939-12-17" imgID="smf">
			<text>the first group of the 1st Canadian Infantry Division arrives in the United Kingdom</text>
			<vets>2271 1384</vets>
		</event>

		<event date="1939-12-17" imgID="qnp">
			<text>the governments of the United Kingdom, Canada, Australia and New Zealand sign an agreement to establish the British Commonwealth Air Training Plan under the supervision of the Royal Canadian Air Force</text>
			<vets>1059 1129 1118 1226 1386</vets>
		</event>

		<event date="1939-12-31" imgID="wup">
			<text>the second section of the 1st Canadian Infantry Division arrives in the United Kingdom</text>
			<vets>1384 2271</vets>
		</event>

		<event date="1940-01-02" imgID="q4m">
			<text>the awarding of Distinguished Flying Cross (each) to two Canadians serving in the Royal Air Force, Pilot-Officer S.R. Henderson and Wing-Commander J.F. Griffiths, is announced.  They are the first Canadians to be decorated during the Second World War</text>
			<vets>1135</vets>
		</event>

		<event date="1940-02-08" imgID="">
			<text>the third Canadian Contingent arrives in Great Britain</text>
		</event>

		<event date="1940-02-14" imgID="">
			<text>No.110 (Army Co-Operation) Squadron sails from Halifax for Britain where it arrives on 25 February, the first Canadian air force squadron to reach Great Britain</text>
		</event>

		<event date="1940-04-15" imgID="5pw">
			<text>No. 1 Initial Training School is opened in Toronto to provide the first training for British Commonwealth Air Training Plan students</text>
			<vets>1536 1102</vets>
		</event>
		
		<event date="1940-04-29" imgID="cvb">
			<text>No. 1 Air Navigation School was formed at Trenton, Ontario, to provide navigation training for British Commonwealth Air Training Plan students</text>
			<vets>1404 1111</vets>
		</event>

		<event date="1940-05-21" imgID="uya">
			<text>the first members of No. 112 (Army Co-Operation) Squadron, based in Winnipeg, sail from Canada for Liverpool where they arrive eight days later as the second Royal Canadian Air Force squadron overseas</text>
			<vets>1315</vets>
		</event>

		<event date="1940-05-23" imgID="">
			<text>the Honourable Charles G. Power is appointed Minister of National Defence for Air</text>
		</event>

		<event date="1940-05-24" imgID="lcf">
			<text>HMS ships St. Laurent, Restigouche and Skeena sail from Halifax for Britain to join the Allied naval defence forces</text>
			<vets>1397</vets>
		</event>

		<event date="1940-05-27" imgID="ped">
			<text>No. 1 Air Observer School is opened in Malton, Ontario, to train British Commonwealth Air Training Plan students in air observation duties</text>
			<vets>1502 1129</vets>
		</event>

		<event date="1940-06-06" imgID="">
			<text>Canadian warships come under fire for the first time when HMCS St. Laurent and HMCS Restigouche encounter German warships at St. Valery en Caux,nac,Harold Harden,1325,No HMCS Restigouche or St. Laurent - general about germans in atlantic</text>
		</event>

		<event date="1940-06-08" imgID="">
			<text>No. 1 (Fighter) Squadron sails from Halifax for Great Britain</text>
		</event>

		<event date="1940-06-10" imgID="qbl">
			<text>the Canadian government declares war on Italy</text>
			<vets>1291 1380</vets>
		</event>

		<event date="1940-06-11" imgID="">
			<text>HMCS St. Laurent and HMCS Restigouche evacuate military personnel from Le Havre, France, exchanging gunfire with German artillery batteries in the process</text>
		</event>

		<event date="1940-06-13" imgID="">
			<text>The Honourable Charles Gavan Power is appointed Minister of Department of National Defence</text>
		</event>

		<event date="1940-06-16" imgID="l2l">
			<text>Canadian troops board transport vessels in St. Malo and Brest to leave France for England after the aborted attempt to support the British and French armies</text>
			<vets>1092</vets>
		</event>

		<event date="1940-06-21" imgID="">
			<text>HMCS Fraser evacuates Free French troops and future Canadian Governor-General, Lieutenant-Colonel G.P. Vanier, from France</text>
		</event>

		<event date="1940-06-22" imgID="">
			<text>the last class of Royal Canadian Navy Volunteer Reserve officers graduate from HMCS Stone Frigate</text>
			<vets>2529</vets>
		</event>

		<event date="1940-06-25" imgID="inm">
			<text>HMCS Fraser is lost after colliding with a British warship, HMS Calcutta in the Bay of Biscay</text>
			<vets>1220</vets>
		</event>

		<event date="1940-07-02" imgID="2mp">
			<text>861 German and Italian prisoners of war are rescued by HMCS St. Laurent after their transport ship was torpedoed on its way to Canada</text>
			<vets>1325 1321</vets>
		</event>

		<event date="1940-07-05" imgID="">
			<text>the Honourable James Layton Ralston is appointed Minister of National Defence</text>
		</event>

		<event date="1940-07-09" imgID="2u4">
			<text>Les Fusiliers Mont-Royal and The Cameron Highlanders of Ottawa arrive in Iceland to complete the Canadian >Z= Force stationed there</text>
			<vets>1317</vets>
		</event>
		
		<event date="1940-07-17" imgID="kgx">
			<text>HMCS Skeena rescues the crew of a torpedoed merchant ship, the SS Manipor, in the waters north of Scotland</text>
			<vets>1397 1070</vets>
		</event>
		
		<event date="1940-07-31" imgID="">
			<text>HMCS Prince Robert, after conversion from a merchant vessel, is commissioned as an armed merchant cruiser</text>
			<vets>2137</vets>
		</event>

		<event date="1940-08-13" imgID="5vv">
			<text>the Canadian Armoured Corps is authorized</text>
			<vets>1316 1345 2298</vets>
		</event>

		<event date="1940-10-20" imgID="asw">
			<text>"HMS Windflower, the first corvette built in Canada, is commissioned into the Royal Navy with a Canadian crew.  She is turned over to the Royal Canadian Navy in 1941</text>
			<vets>1077 1119</vets>
		</event>

		<event date="1940-10-22" imgID="kzs">
			<text>HMCS Margaree is lost in a collision with SS Port Fairy in the North Atlantic</text>
			<vets>1493</vets>
		</event>


		<event date="1940-10-25" imgID="">
			<text>HMCS Bras D'Or founders in the North Atlantic</text>
		</event>

		<event date="1940-10-31" imgID="cyw">
			<text>AZ@ Force, with the exception of The Cameron Highlanders of Ottawa, sails from Iceland for Great Britain</text>
			<vets>1141 1139</vets>
		</event>

		<event date="1940-11-09" imgID="5ux">
			<text>HMCS Collingwood, the first corvette built in Canada for the RCN, is commissioned</text>
			<vets>1077</vets>
		</event>

		<event date="1940-11-24" imgID="wxm">
			<text>the first draft of British Commonwealth Air Training Plan graduates arrive in England for service</text>
			<vets>1111 1798</vets>
		</event>

		<event date="1940-12-04" imgID="cxs">
			<text>HMCS Prince Henry is commissioned as an Armed Merchant Cruiser</text>
			<vets>1070</vets>
		</event>
		
		<event date="1940-12-13" imgID="mvi">
			<text>HMCS Royal Roads is commissioned as a training establishment for Probationary Sub-Lieutenants</text>
			<vets>1418 2137 2248</vets>
		</event>

		<event date="1940-12-25" imgID="1ny">
			<text>1st Canadian Corps is formed in the United Kingdom under the command of Lieutenant-General A.G.L. McNaughton</text>
			<vets>2193</vets>
		</event>

		<event date="1940-12-28" imgID="qla">
			<text>HMCS Prince David is commissioned as an Armed Merchant Cruiser</text>
			<vets>1324 1161</vets>
		</event>

		<event date="1941-01-07" imgID="">
			<text>a Commonwealth agreement of 17 December 1939 provides for the future establishment of purely Canadian air force units for newly-trained Canadians to join in Europe</text>
		</event>

		<event date="1941-02-09" imgID="3vi">
			<text>the 5th Canadian Motorcycle Regiment, CASF, (BCD) is converted and redesignated The British Columbia Dragoons</text>
			<vets>1045 1321</vets>
		</event>

		<event date="1941-03-24" imgID="0pv">
			<text>the Rush-Bagot Agreement of 1817, which restricted the number of naval vessels allowed on the Great Lakes, is modified to allow both American and Canadian naval vessels to operate on the Great Lakes in greater numbers</text>
			<vets>2285 2529 1066</vets>
		</event>

		<event date="1941-03-25" imgID="i5y">
			<text>HMCS Otter burns and sinks in the approaches to Halifax</text>
			<vets>1119</vets>
		</event>

		<event date="1941-05-25" imgID="52k">
			<text>seven Royal Canadian Navy corvettes arrive in St. John's, Newfoundland, to begin operations as the Newfoundland Escort Force</text>
			<vets>1216 2387</vets>
		</event>

		<event date="1941-06-13" imgID="x51">
			<text>Newfoundland's sea defences are brought under Canadian control with the appointment of Commodore L.W. Murray, RCN, as the commander of Newfoundland Force</text>
			<vets>2378</vets>
		</event>

		<event date="1941-06-14" imgID="mum">
			<text>warships of the Newfoundland Escort Force begin convoy escort operations in the North Atlantic Ocean</text>
			<vets>1429 1141</vets>
		</event>

		<event date="1941-06-26" imgID="umr">
			<text>the Canadian government announces its intention to form a Canadian Women's Army Corps</text>
			<vets>1074 1062 2177</vets>
		</event>

		<event date="1941-06-30" imgID="pvp">
			<text>HMCS Wasaga is commissioned, becoming the first Canadian-built Bangor-class minesweeper</text>
			<vets>1341 1495 2436</vets>
		</event>

		<event date="1941-07-02" imgID="rra">
			<text>the Canadian Women's Auxiliary Air Force is authorized, later becoming the Royal Canadian Air Force (Women’s Division)</text>
			<vets>1163 1217 1386</vets>
		</event>

		<event date="1941-08-09" imgID="">
			<text>HMC Ships Assiniboine and Restigouche escort HMS Prince of Wales, with Prime Minister Winston Churchill aboard, into Placentia Bay, Newfoundland</text>
			<vets>1821 2137</vets>
		</event>

		<event date="1941-08-13" imgID="i5s">
			<text>the Canadian Women’s Army Corps is authorized</text>
			<vets>2177 1298 1049</vets>
		</event>
		
		<event date="1941-09-10" imgID="po5">
			<text>HMCS Chambly and HMCS Moose Jaw sink the German submarine U-501 off the coast of Greenland.  This is the first U-boat kill made by the Royal Canadian Navy</text>
			<vets>1314 1161</vets>
		</event>

		<event date="1941-09-19" imgID="u5h">
			<text>HMCS Levis (a corvette) is torpedoed and sunk in the North Atlantic</text>
			<vets>1119 1161</vets>
		</event>
	
		<event date="1941-09-22" imgID="i3z">
			<text>the University Air Training Squadrons are formed</text>
			<vets>1118 1059</vets>
		</event>

		<event date="1941-10-27" imgID="cxn">
			<text>AC@ Force (Canadian troops under the command of Brigadier J.K. Lawson) sails from Vancouver for Hong Kong</text>
			<vets>1541</vets>
		</event>

		<event date="1941-11-10" imgID="xrg">
			<text>the RCAF is awarded its first George Cross when LAC K.M. Gravell is posthumously awarded the decoration for the attempt to rescue his pilot from their crashed Tiger Moth aircraft</text>
			<vets>1229 1102</vets>
		</event>

		<event date="1941-11-13" imgID="vgf">
			<text>the 1st Armoured Car Regiment (Royal Canadian Dragoons) sails from Canada for Britain as part of the 5th Canadian Armoured Division</text>
			<vets>1517</vets>
		</event>
		
		<event date="1941-11-26" imgID="nac">
			<text>HMCS Halifax is commissioned into the RCN</text>
			<vets>1325 1314</vets>
		</event>

		<event date="1941-12-07" imgID="lmc">
			<text>Canada declares war on Romania, Hungary, Finland and Japan"</text>
			<vets>2291 1448</vets>
		</event>

		<event date="1941-12-07" imgID="ksu">
			<text>HMCS Windflower is lost after a collision with SS Zypenburg on the Grand Banks of Newfoundland</text>
			<vets>1216 1483 1271</vets>
		</event>

		<event date="1941-12-08" imgID="0iw">
			<text>the United States, Great Britain and other nations declare war on Japan</text>
			<vets>2310</vets>
		</event>

		<event date="1941-12-19" imgID="euj">
			<text>gallantry shown by Company Sergeant-Major J.R. Osborn, Royal Winnipeg Grenadiers, in action against the Japanese at Hong Kong on this date led to the posthumous award of the Victoria Cross</text>
			<vets>2270</vets>
		</event>

		<event date="1941-12-25" imgID="r04">
			<text>Hong Kong surrenders to the Japanese forces</text>
			<vets>1049</vets>
		</event>

		<event date="1942-01-22" imgID="">
			<text>the Canadian Naval Board is established</text>
		</event>

		<event date="1942-02-03" imgID="l3r">
			<text>the Canadian Women's Auxiliary Air Force is renamed the Royal Canadian Air Force (Women's Division)</text>
			<vets>1386 2384 1465</vets>
		</event>

		<event date="1942-02-11" imgID="wi1">
			<text>HMCS Spikenard is torpedoed and sunk in the North Atlantic</text>
			<vets>1161 1119</vets>
		</event>
		
		<event date="1942-02-12" imgID="ewr">
			<text>nine Canadian squadrons (four bomber, four fighter and one coastal) take part in the chase of three German warships in the AChannel Dash@</text>
			<vets>1070</vets>
		</event>

		<event date="1942-03-01" imgID="uak">
			<text>the Canadian Women's Army Corps is granted full Army status as ""a Corps of the Active Militia of Canada</text>
			<vets>1224 2177 2499 2211</vets>
		</event>

		<event date="1942-03-04" imgID="irh">
			<text>the first Canadian 'Cruiser' tanks arrive in England</text>
			<vets>2241</vets>
		</event>

		<event date="1942-03-18" imgID="1hw">
			<text>No.413 Squadron begins its transfer from the Shetland Isles to Ceylon to strengthen Allied air defences in the Pacific</text>
			<vets>2395 1068 1125 1494</vets>
		</event>

		<event date="1942-03-23" imgID="">
			<text>Air Vice-Marshal E.W. Stedman is appointed the first Director General of Air Research for the Royal Canadian Air Force</text>
		</event>

		<event date="1942-04-04" imgID="mmk">
			<text>Squadron Leader L.J. Birchall and his crew, flying a PBY-5 flying boat, spot a Japanese naval force heading for the island of Ceylon.  Their warning allowed the island's defenders to prepare for the Japanese attempt to take the island, an attack which fails.  Birchall is later known as "The Saviour of Ceylon</text>
			<vets>2395</vets>
		</event>

		<event date="1942-04-05" imgID="mlp">
			<text>at least fifteen Canadian members of the Royal Canadian Air Force and the Royal Air Force help the Ceylonese defend the island against the Japanese attempt to conquer it</text>
			<vets>2395 1125 2228</vets>
		</event>

		<event date="1942-04-06" imgID="">
			<text>the First Canadian Army formed in the United Kingdom under the command of Lieutenant-General A.G.L. McNaughton</text>
			<vets>2193</vets>
		</event>

		<event date="1942-04-13" imgID="qqs">
			<text>No. 417 (Spitfire) Squadron, Royal Canadian Air Force, is transferred from Great Britain to Egypt to support the Allied operations in the Middle East</text>
			<vets>1229 1337 1067 2459</vets>
		</event>
		
	</events>
		<vetrans>
			<vet id="1065">Helen Rochon</vet>
			<vet id="1096">Hubert Lalonde</vet>
			<vet id="1297">Norman Wrigglesworth</vet>
			<vet id="1069">Tom Rappel</vet>
			<vet id="1339">Russell Smith</vet>
			<vet id="1123">Bill Watterson</vet>
			<vet id="2288">Ross Hamilton</vet>
			<vet id="1452">Frank John Dion</vet>
			<vet id="2271">John A Cathie</vet>
			<vet id="2295">Rudy Deutsch</vet>
			<vet id="2270">John Bilyk</vet>
			<vet id="1050">Malcolm Andrade</vet>
			<vet id="1345">James Duncan Ritchie</vet>
			<vet id="2241">John Leach</vet>
			<vet id="2230">Joan Bennett Johnson, nee Cobb</vet>
			<vet id="1478">Geoffrey Alington</vet>
			<vet id="1154">John Covan</vet>
			<vet id="2137">Louis Henry Howard</vet>
			<vet id="1104">Mike Hawryliw</vet>
			<vet id="1307">Malcolm Maconnell</vet>
			<vet id="1102">Harold Emery Bronson</vet>
			<vet id="1059">Ernest Peter Bone</vet>
			<vet id="1108">Mervyn Couse</vet>
			<vet id="1111">Geraldine Muter</vet>
			<vet id="1119">Donald McIntosh</vet>
			<vet id="1220">C. James Alward</vet>
			<vet id="1384">Gordon Bannerman</vet>
			<vet id="1129">Cecil Edward Hancock</vet>
			<vet id="1118">Brian MacConnell</vet>
			<vet id="1226">Joseph Preston Hawkins</vet>
			<vet id="1386">Glennis Marie Boyce</vet>
			<vet id="1135">Norman Dawber</vet>
			<vet id="1536">Eric Stanley Hawley</vet>
			<vet id="1404">Donald Stevenson</vet>
			<vet id="1315">William Gelineau</vet>
			<vet id="1397">Jack Smallwood</vet>
			<vet id="1502">Ray Sowerby</vet>
			<vet id="1291">Paul-Emile Lamouche</vet>
			<vet id="1380">William Adelman</vet>
			<vet id="1092">Edward Borland</vet>
			<vet id="2529">Frederick Gray</vet>
			<vet id="1220">C James Alward</vet>
			<vet id="1325">Harold Harden</vet>
			<vet id="1321">Robert Kerr</vet>
			<vet id="1317">Jean Marie Ademare Milot</vet>
			<vet id="1070">Frank Aldred</vet>
			<vet id="1316">Robert Routledge</vet>
			<vet id="2298">Gordon Wright</vet>
			<vet id="1077">Harvey Burns</vet>
			<vet id="1493">Ron Rhine</vet>
			<vet id="1141">Charles Scott</vet>
			<vet id="1139">John Rankin Stephens</vet>
			<vet id="1798">David Macdonald</vet>
			<vet id="1418">Eric Gordon Jensen</vet>
			<vet id="2248">Ruby Somers</vet>
			<vet id="2193">Leslie Eugene Clarke</vet>
			<vet id="1324">Fred Linnington</vet>
			<vet id="1161">George Evans</vet>
			<vet id="1045">Helen Jean Crawley</vet>
			<vet id="2285">Warren Urquhart</vet>
			<vet id="2529">Frederick Lawrence Gray</vet>
			<vet id="1066">Carol Duffus</vet>
			<vet id="1216">Murray Copot</vet>
			<vet id="2387">Edwin Badger</vet>
			<vet id="2378">Lawrence Weldon</vet>
			<vet id="1429">John Potter</vet>
			<vet id="1074">Corinne Sevigny</vet>
			<vet id="1062">Elizabeth Dimock</vet>
			<vet id="2177">Alice Marie Samuel</vet>
			<vet id="1341">Ralph Taylor</vet>
			<vet id="1495">Bruce Findlay</vet>
			<vet id="2436">Alfred Carpenter</vet>
			<vet id="1163">Margaret Brownlee</vet>
			<vet id="1217">Ella Curtis</vet>
			<vet id="1386">Glennis Boyce</vet>
			<vet id="1821">Harold MacLauchlin</vet>
			<vet id="1298">Grace Breau-Theriault</vet>
			<vet id="1049">Olive Peat</vet>
			<vet id="1314">Jim Peters</vet>
			<vet id="1059">Ernest Bone</vet>
			<vet id="1541">Arthur Gillan</vet>
			<vet id="1229">Douglas Drew</vet>
			<vet id="1102">Harold Bronson</vet>
			<vet id="1517">Arthur Robert Henry Lyon</vet>
			<vet id="2291">Godfrey Schaupmeyer</vet>
			<vet id="1448">Otto Hemmerling</vet>
			<vet id="1483">Henry Mason</vet>
			<vet id="1271">Leonard Whiffen</vet>
			<vet id="2310">Victor Wong</vet>
			<vet id="2270">John Bylik</vet>
			<vet id="2384">Catherine Anderson</vet>
			<vet id="1465">Ruby Foley</vet>
			<vet id="1224">Doris Wallace</vet>
			<vet id="2177">Alice Samuel</vet>
			<vet id="2499">Joan Manning</vet>
			<vet id="2211">Doreen Newton</vet>
			<vet id="2395">Ian Herd</vet>
			<vet id="1068">Bob Farquharson</vet>
			<vet id="1125">Ed Pearson</vet>
			<vet id="1494">Lewis Chow</vet>
			<vet id="2228">Donovan Woelfle</vet>
			<vet id="2193">Leslie Clarke</vet>
			<vet id="1337">Geoffrey Jell</vet>
			<vet id="1067">Hubert Gray</vet>
			<vet id="2459">Oscar Fiteni</vet>
		</vetrans>	
</timelineData>