<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<timelineData>

    <links>
        <smallThumb url="http://www.thememoryproject.com/VeteranAssets/Artifact/Thumb_Small/" />
        <vetProfile url="http://www.thememoryproject.com/Stories/Veteran-Profile.aspx?itemid=" />
    </links>
    
    <events>

        <event date="08/05/1945" img="bcs.jpg">
            <text>Victory in Europe Day (VE-Day) is declared, ending the European portion of the Second World War</text>
            <vet id="1065">Helen Rochon</vet>
            <vet id="1096">Hubert Lalonde</vet>
            <vet id="1297">Norman Wrigglesworth</vet>
            <vet id="1368">Marguerite Plante</vet>
            <vet id="1738">Art Meyer</vet>
            <vet id="2313">Peggy Lee</vet>
            <vet id="1528">Bill Ramsbottom</vet>
            <vet id="1176">Rex Fendick</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="24/09/1940" img="axl.jpg">
            <text>Her Majesty's Canadian ships Annapolis, Columbia, Niagara, St. Clair, St. Croix and St. Francis, ex-American destroyers from the fifty given to Great Britain in exchange for bases, are commissioned into the Royal Canadian Navy</text>
            <vet id="1069">Tom Rappel</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="22/07/1940" img="3cg.jpg">
            <text>The British Commonwealth Air Training Plan begins operations when students began training at No. 1 Service Flying Training School at Camp Borden, Ontario</text>
            <vet id="1339">Russell Smith</vet>
            <vet id="1123">Bill Watterson</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="11/02/1944" img="3kh.jpg">
            <text>a Wellington bomber of No.407 Squadron, Royal Canadian Air Force, sinks the German submarine U-283 in the North Atlantic</text>
            <vet id="2288">Ross Hamilton</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/09/1939" img="lus.jpg">
            <text>the 1st and 2nd Canadian Divisions are authorized as the Canadian Active Service Force.  The Royal Canadian Navy, Royal Canadian Navy Reserve and Royal Canadian Navy Volunteer Reserve are placed on active service</text>
            <vet id="1452">Frank John Dion</vet>
            <vet id="2271">John A Cathie</vet>
            <vet id="2295">Rudy Deutsch</vet>
            <vet id="2270">John Bilyk</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="04/09/1939" img="cfc.jpg">
            <text>Pilot Officer S.R. Henderson, a Canadian serving in No.206 Squadron, Royal Air Force, becomes the first Canadian to participate in an operational sortie during the Second World War when he serves as the lead navigator in a bomber force attacking German warships</text>
            <vet id="1050">Malcolm Andrade</vet>
            <vet id="2190">Rodolphe Lavoie</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="10/09/1939" img="u1p.jpg">
            <text>Canada declares war on Germany</text>
            <vet id="1345">James Duncan Ritchie</vet>
            <vet id="2241">John Leach</vet>
            <vet id="2230">Joan Bennett Johnson, nee Cobb</vet>
            <vet id="1478">Geoffrey Alington</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="16/09/1939" img="blc.jpg">
            <text>convoy HX-1 sails from Halifax for Great Britain with a local escort including HMCS St. Laurent and HMCS Saguenay</text>
            <vet id="1154">John Covan</vet>
            <vet id="2137">Louis Henry Howard</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="19/09/1939" img="t0r.jpg">
            <text>the Honourable Norman McLeod Rogers is appointed Minister of National Defence</text>
            <vet id="1104">Mike Hawryliw</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="29-30-Sep-39" img="xit.jpg">
            <text>S/L W.I. Clements, attached to No.53 (Blenheim) Squadron, Royal Air Force, becomes the first member of the Royal Canadian Air Force to fly over enemy territory when his squadron makes a long distance reconnaissance flight over Germany</text>
            <vet id="1307">Malcolm Maconnell</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="06/11/1939" img="d1r.jpg">
            <text>the formation of the Organization and Training Division at RCAF headquarters is authorized</text>
            <vet id="1102">Harold Emery Bronson</vet>
            <vet id="1059">Ernest Peter Bone</vet>
            <vet id="1108">Mervyn Couse</vet>
            <vet id="1111">Geraldine Muter</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="10/12/1939" img="vkc.jpg">
            <text>the first Canadian troop convoy sails for Britain escorted out of Halifax by HMC ships Ottawa, Restigouche, Fraser and St. Laurent</text>
            <vet id="1119">Donald McIntosh</vet>
            <vet id="1154">John Covan</vet>
            <vet id="1220">C. James Alward</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="17/12/1939" img="smf.jpg">
            <text>the first group of the 1st Canadian Infantry Division arrives in the United Kingdom</text>
            <vet id="2271">John A Cathie</vet>
            <vet id="1384">Gordon Bannerman</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="17/12/1939" img="qnp.jpg">
            <text>the governments of the United Kingdom, Canada, Australia and New Zealand sign an agreement to establish the British Commonwealth Air Training Plan under the supervision of the Royal Canadian Air Force</text>
            <vet id="1059">Ernest Peter Bone</vet>
            <vet id="1129">Cecil Edward Hancock</vet>
            <vet id="1118">Brian MacConnell</vet>
            <vet id="1226">Joseph Preston Hawkins</vet>
            <vet id="1386">Glennis Marie Boyce</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="31/12/1939" img="wup.jpg">
            <text>the second section of the 1st Canadian Infantry Division arrives in the United Kingdom</text>
            <vet id="1384">Gordon Bannerman</vet>
            <vet id="2271">John A Cathie</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="02/01/1940" img="q4m.jpg">
            <text>the awarding of Distinguished Flying Cross (each) to two Canadians serving in the Royal Air Force, Pilot-Officer S.R. Henderson and Wing-Commander J.F. Griffiths, is announced.  They are the first Canadians to be decorated during the Second World War</text>
            <vet id="1135">Norman Dawber</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="08/02/1940" img="hqp.jpg">
            <text>the third Canadian Contingent arrives in Great Britain</text>
            <vet id="2271">John Cathie</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="14/02/1940" img="ps4.jpg">
            <text>No.110 (Army Co-Operation) Squadron sails from Halifax for Britain where it arrives on 25 February, the first Canadian air force squadron to reach Great Britain</text>
            <vet id="1294">William Kondra</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="15/04/1940" img="5pw.jpg">
            <text>No. 1 Initial Training School is opened in Toronto to provide the first training for British Commonwealth Air Training Plan students</text>
            <vet id="1536">Eric Stanley Hawley</vet>
            <vet id="1102">Harold Emery Bronson</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="29/04/1940" img="cvb.jpg">
            <text>No. 1 Air Navigation School was formed at Trenton, Ontario, to provide navigation training for British Commonwealth Air Training Plan students</text>
            <vet id="1404">Donald Stevenson</vet>
            <vet id="1111">Geraldine Muter</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="21/05/1940" img="uya.jpg">
            <text>the first members of No. 112 (Army Co-Operation) Squadron, based in Winnipeg, sail from Canada for Liverpool where they arrive eight days later as the second Royal Canadian Air Force squadron overseas</text>
            <vet id="1315">William Gelineau</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="24/05/1940" img="lcf.jpg">
            <text>HMS ships St. Laurent, Restigouche and Skeena sail from Halifax for Britain to join the Allied naval defence forces</text>
            <vet id="1397">Jack Smallwood</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="27/05/1940" img="ped.jpg">
            <text>No. 1 Air Observer School is opened in Malton, Ontario, to train British Commonwealth Air Training Plan students in air observation duties</text>
            <vet id="1502">Ray Sowerby</vet>
            <vet id="1129">Cecil Edward Hancock</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="06/06/1940" img="nac.jpg">
            <text>Canadian warships come under fire for the first time when HMCS St. Laurent and HMCS Restigouche encounter German warships at St. Valery en Caux</text>
            <vet id="1325">Harold Harden</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="08/06/1940" img="tep.jpg">
            <text>No. 1 (Fighter) Squadron sails from Halifax for Great Britain</text>
            <vet id="2695">Lorne Yule</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="10/06/1940" img="qbl.jpg">
            <text>the Canadian government declares war on Italy</text>
            <vet id="1291">Paul-Emile Lamouche</vet>
            <vet id="1380">William Adelman</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="11/06/1940" img="2e1.jpg">
            <text>HMCS St. Laurent and HMCS Restigouche evacuate military personnel from Le Havre, France, exchanging gunfire with German artillery batteries in the process</text>
            <vet id="1477">Donald Green</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="16/06/1940" img="l2l.jpg">
            <text>Canadian troops board transport vessels in St. Malo and Brest to leave France for England after the aborted attempt to support the British and French armies</text>
            <vet id="1092">Edward Borland</vet>
            <vet id="2528">Victor Guerin</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="22/06/1940" img="3sg.jpg">
            <text>the last class of Royal Canadian Navy Volunteer Reserve officers graduate from HMCS Stone Frigate</text>
            <vet id="2529">Frederick Gray</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="25/06/1940" img="inm.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Fraser is lost after colliding with a British warship, HMS Calcutta in the Bay of Biscay</text>
            <vet id="1220">C James Alward</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="02/07/1940" img="2mp.jpg">
            <text>861 German and Italian prisoners of war are rescued by HMCS St. Laurent after their transport ship was torpedoed on its way to Canada</text>
            <vet id="1325">Harold Harden</vet>
            <vet id="1321">Robert Kerr</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="09/07/1940" img="2u4.jpg">
            <text>Les Fusiliers Mont-Royal and The Cameron Highlanders of Ottawa arrive in Iceland to complete the Canadian >Z= Force stationed there</text>
            <vet id="1317">Jean Marie Ademare Milot</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="17/07/1940" img="kgx.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Skeena rescues the crew of a torpedoed merchant ship, the SS Manipor, in the waters north of Scotland</text>
            <vet id="1397">Jack Smallwood</vet>
            <vet id="1070">Frank Aldred</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="13/08/1940" img="5vv.jpg">
            <text>the Canadian Armoured Corps is authorized</text>
            <vet id="1316">Robert Routledge</vet>
            <vet id="1345">James Duncan Ritchie</vet>
            <vet id="2298">Gordon Wright</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="20/10/1940" img="m5a.jpg">
            <text>HMS Windflower, the first corvette built in Canada, is commissioned into the Royal Navy with a Canadian crew.  She is turned over to the Royal Canadian Navy in 1941</text>
            <vet id="2525">Georges Charrier</vet>
            <vet id="1119">Donald McIntosh</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="22/10/1940" img="kzs.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Margaree is lost in a collision with SS Port Fairy in the North Atlantic</text>
            <vet id="1493">Ron Rhine</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="25/10/1940" img="vkc.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Bras D'Or founders in the North Atlantic</text>
            <vet id="1119">Donald McIntosh</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="31/10/1940" img="cyw.jpg">
            <text>AZ@ Force, with the exception of The Cameron Highlanders of Ottawa, sails from Iceland for Great Britain</text>
            <vet id="1141">Charles Scott</vet>
            <vet id="1139">John Rankin Stephens</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="09/11/1940" img="5ux.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Collingwood, the first corvette built in Canada for the RCN, is commissioned</text>
            <vet id="1077">Harvey Burns</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="24/11/1940" img="wxm.jpg">
            <text>the first draft of British Commonwealth Air Training Plan graduates arrive in England for service</text>
            <vet id="1111">Geraldine Muter</vet>
            <vet id="1798">David Macdonald</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="04/12/1940" img="cxs.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Prince Henry is commissioned as an Armed Merchant Cruiser</text>
            <vet id="1070">Frank Aldred</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="13/12/1940" img="mvi.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Royal Roads is commissioned as a training establishment for Probationary Sub-Lieutenants</text>
            <vet id="1418">Eric Gordon Jensen</vet>
            <vet id="2137">Louis Henry Howard</vet>
            <vet id="2248">Ruby Somers</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="25/12/1940" img="1ny.jpg">
            <text>1st Canadian Corps is formed in the United Kingdom under the command of Lieutenant-General A.G.L. McNaughton</text>
            <vet id="2193">Leslie Eugene Clarke</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="28/12/1940" img="qla.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Prince David is commissioned as an Armed Merchant Cruiser</text>
            <vet id="1324">Fred Linnington</vet>
            <vet id="1161">George Evans</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="07/01/1941" img="pkd.jpg">
            <text>a Commonwealth agreement of 17 December 1939 provides for the future establishment of purely Canadian air force units for newly-trained Canadians to join in Europe</text>
            <vet id="1118">Brian MacConnell</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="09/02/1941" img="3vi.jpg">
            <text>the 5th Canadian Motorcycle Regiment, CASF, (BCD) is converted and redesignated The British Columbia Dragoons</text>
            <vet id="1045">Helen Jean Crawley</vet>
            <vet id="1321">Robert Kerr</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="24/03/1941" img="0pv.jpg">
            <text>the Rush-Bagot Agreement of 1817, which restricted the number of naval vessels allowed on the Great Lakes, is modified to allow both American and Canadian naval vessels to operate on the Great Lakes in greater numbers</text>
            <vet id="2285">Warren Urquhart</vet>
            <vet id="2529">Frederick Lawrence Gray</vet>
            <vet id="1066">Carol Duffus</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="25/03/1941" img="i5y.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Otter burns and sinks in the approaches to Halifax</text>
            <vet id="1119">Donald McIntosh</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="25/05/1941" img="52k.jpg">
            <text>seven Royal Canadian Navy corvettes arrive in St. John's, Newfoundland, to begin operations as the Newfoundland Escort Force</text>
            <vet id="1216">Murray Copot</vet>
            <vet id="2387">Edwin Badger</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="13/06/1941" img="x51.jpg">
            <text>Newfoundland's sea defences are brought under Canadian control with the appointment of Commodore L.W. Murray, RCN, as the commander of Newfoundland Force</text>
            <vet id="2378">Lawrence Weldon</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="14/06/1941" img="mum.jpg">
            <text>warships of the Newfoundland Escort Force begin convoy escort operations in the North Atlantic Ocean</text>
            <vet id="1429">John Potter</vet>
            <vet id="1141">Charles Scott</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="26/06/1941" img="umr.jpg">
            <text>the Canadian government announces its intention to form a Canadian Women's Army Corps</text>
            <vet id="1074">Corinne Sevigny</vet>
            <vet id="1062">Elizabeth Dimock</vet>
            <vet id="2177">Alice Marie Samuel</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="30/06/1941" img="pvp.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Wasaga is commissioned, becoming the first Canadian-built Bangor-class minesweeper</text>
            <vet id="1341">Ralph Taylor</vet>
            <vet id="1495">Bruce Findlay</vet>
            <vet id="2436">Alfred Carpenter</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="02/07/1941" img="rra.jpg">
            <text>the Canadian Women's Auxiliary Air Force is authorized, later becoming the Royal Canadian Air Force (Women’s Division)</text>
            <vet id="1163">Margaret Brownlee</vet>
            <vet id="1217">Ella Curtis</vet>
            <vet id="1386">Glennis Boyce</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="09/08/1941" img="gzu.jpg">
            <text>HMC Ships Assiniboine and Restigouche escort HMS Prince of Wales, with Prime Minister Winston Churchill aboard, into Placentia Bay, Newfoundland</text>
            <vet id="1821">Harold MacLauchlin</vet>
            <vet id="2137">Louis Henry Howard</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="13/08/1941" img="i5s.jpg">
            <text>the Canadian Women’s Army Corps is authorized</text>
            <vet id="2177">Alice Marie Samuel</vet>
            <vet id="1298">Grace Breau-Theriault</vet>
            <vet id="1049">Olive Peat</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="10/09/1941" img="po5.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Chambly and HMCS Moose Jaw sink the German submarine U-501 off the coast of Greenland.  This is the first U-boat kill made by the Royal Canadian Navy</text>
            <vet id="1314">Jim Peters</vet>
            <vet id="1161">George Evans</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="19/09/1941" img="u5h.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Levis (a corvette) is torpedoed and sunk in the North Atlantic</text>
            <vet id="1119">Donald McIntosh</vet>
            <vet id="1161">George Evans</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="22/09/1941" img="i3z.jpg">
            <text>the University Air Training Squadrons are formed</text>
            <vet id="1118">Brian MacConnell</vet>
            <vet id="1059">Ernest Bone</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="27/10/1941" img="cxn.jpg">
            <text>AC@ Force (Canadian troops under the command of Brigadier J.K. Lawson) sails from Vancouver for Hong Kong</text>
            <vet id="2266">Clyde Bougie</vet>
            <vet id="1541">Arthur Gillan</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="10/11/1941" img="xrg.jpg">
            <text>the RCAF is awarded its first George Cross when LAC K.M. Gravell is posthumously awarded the decoration for the attempt to rescue his pilot from their crashed Tiger Moth aircraft</text>
            <vet id="1229">Douglas Drew</vet>
            <vet id="1102">Harold Bronson</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="13/11/1941" img="vgf.jpg">
            <text>the 1st Armoured Car Regiment (Royal Canadian Dragoons) sails from Canada for Britain as part of the 5th Canadian Armoured Division</text>
            <vet id="1517">Arthur Robert Henry Lyon</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="26/11/1941" img="nac.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Halifax is commissioned into the RCN</text>
            <vet id="1325">Harold Harden</vet>
            <vet id="1314">Jim Peters</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="07/12/1941" img="lmc.jpg">
            <text>Canada declares war on Romania, Hungary, Finland and Japan</text>
            <vet id="2291">Godfrey Schaupmeyer</vet>
            <vet id="1448">Otto Hemmerling</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="07/12/1941" img="ksu.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Windflower is lost after a collision with SS Zypenburg on the Grand Banks of Newfoundland</text>
            <vet id="1216">Murray Copot</vet>
            <vet id="1483">Henry Mason</vet>
            <vet id="1271">Leonard Whiffen</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="08/12/1941" img="0iw.jpg">
            <text>the United States, Great Britain and other nations declare war on Japan</text>
            <vet id="2310">Victor Wong</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="19/12/1941" img="euj.jpg">
            <text>gallantry shown by Company Sergeant-Major J.R. Osborn, Royal Winnipeg Grenadiers, in action against the Japanese at Hong Kong on this date led to the posthumous award of the Victoria Cross</text>
            <vet id="2270">John Bylik</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="25/12/1941" img="r04.jpg">
            <text>Hong Kong surrenders to the Japanese forces</text>
            <vet id="1049">Olive Peat</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="03/02/1942" img="l3r.jpg">
            <text>the Canadian Women's Auxiliary Air Force is renamed the Royal Canadian Air Force (Women's Division)</text>
            <vet id="1386">Glennis Boyce</vet>
            <vet id="2384">Catherine Anderson</vet>
            <vet id="1465">Ruby Foley</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="11/02/1942" img="wi1.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Spikenard is torpedoed and sunk in the North Atlantic</text>
            <vet id="1161">George Evans</vet>
            <vet id="1119">Donald McIntosh</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="12/02/1942" img="ewr.jpg">
            <text>nine Canadian squadrons (four bomber, four fighter and one coastal) take part in the chase of three German warships in the AChannel Dash@</text>
            <vet id="1070">Frank Aldred</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/03/1942" img="uak.jpg">
            <text>the Canadian Women's Army Corps is granted full Army status as "a Corps of the Active Militia of Canada"</text>
            <vet id="1224">Doris Wallace</vet>
            <vet id="2177">Alice Samuel</vet>
            <vet id="2499">Joan Manning</vet>
            <vet id="2211">Doreen Newton</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="04/03/1942" img="irh.jpg">
            <text>the first Canadian 'Cruiser' tanks arrive in England</text>
            <vet id="2241">John Leach</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="18/03/1942" img="1hw.jpg">
            <text>No.413 Squadron begins its transfer from the Shetland Isles to Ceylon to strengthen Allied air defences in the Pacific</text>
            <vet id="2395">Ian Herd</vet>
            <vet id="1068">Bob Farquharson</vet>
            <vet id="1125">Ed Pearson</vet>
            <vet id="1494">Lewis Chow</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="04/04/1942" img="mmk.jpg">
            <text>Squadron Leader L.J. Birchall and his crew, flying a PBY-5 flying boat, spot a Japanese naval force heading for the island of Ceylon.  Their warning allowed the island's defenders to prepare for the Japanese attempt to take the island, an attack which fails.  Birchall is later known as "The Saviour of Ceylon"</text>
            <vet id="2395">Ian Herd</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="05/04/1942" img="mlp.jpg">
            <text>at least fifteen Canadian members of the Royal Canadian Air Force and the Royal Air Force help the Ceylonese defend the island against the Japanese attempt to conquer it</text>
            <vet id="2395">Ian Herd</vet>
            <vet id="1125">Ed Pearson</vet>
            <vet id="2228">Donovan Woelfle</vet>
            <vet id="2193">Leslie Clarke</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="13/04/1942" img="qqs.jpg">
            <text>No. 417 (Spitfire) Squadron, Royal Canadian Air Force, is transferred from Great Britain to Egypt to support the Allied operations in the Middle East</text>
            <vet id="1229">Douglas Drew</vet>
            <vet id="1337">Geoffrey Jell</vet>
            <vet id="1067">Hubert Gray</vet>
            <vet id="2459">Oscar Fiteni</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="24/07/1942" img="myb.jpg">
            <text>HMCS St. Croix sinks the German submarine U-90 while on patrol in the North Atlantic Ocean</text>
            <vet id="1119">Donald McIntosh</vet>
            <vet id="2325">Leonard Bookbinder</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="31/07/1942" img="qpl.jpg">
            <text>the Women's Royal Canadian Naval Service is authorized</text>
            <vet id="1066">Carol Duffus</vet>
            <vet id="1327">Olive Henderson</vet>
            <vet id="2248">Ruby Somers</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="31/07/1942" img="ewr.jpg">
            <text>HMC Ships Wetaskiwin and Skeena sink the German submarine U-588 while on patrol in the North Atlantic Ocean</text>
            <vet id="1397">Jack Smallwood</vet>
            <vet id="1070">Frank Aldred</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="06/08/1942" img="4ly.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Assiniboine sinks the German submarine U-210 while on patrol in the North Atlantic Ocean</text>
            <vet id="1821">Harold MacLauchlin</vet>
            <vet id="2298">Gordon Wright</vet>
            <vet id="1312">Norman Silver</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="19/08/1942" img="opx.jpg">
            <text>a primarily Canadian force conducts a disastrous large-scale raid on the French coastal town of Dieppe</text>
            <vet id="1225">Douglas Warren</vet>
            <vet id="1423">Jacques Nadeau</vet>
            <vet id="1042">George Burrows</vet>
            <vet id="1085">Leonard Allbon</vet>
            <vet id="1231">Jean Marcel D'Aoust</vet>
            <vet id="1412">Armond Emond</vet>
            <vet id="2515">Roland Gravel</vet>
            <vet id="1058">Douglas Annis</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="20/08/1942" img="cxn.jpg">
            <text>HMC Ships Prince Robert, Prince Henry, Prince David, Dawson and Vancouver leave Esquimalt, British Columbia, to commence operations in the Bering Sea</text>
            <vet id="1070">Frank Aldred</vet>
            <vet id="2137">Louis Henry Howard</vet>
            <vet id="1541">Arthur Gillan</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="28/08/1942" img="5mb.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Oakville works with American aircraft to sink the German submarine U-94 in the Caribbean Sea</text>
            <vet id="1161">George Evans</vet>
            <vet id="1070">Frank Aldred</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="07/09/1942" img="mz2.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Raccoon (an armed yacht) is torpedoed and sunk, with the loss of all hands, in the Gulf of St. Lawrence</text>
            <vet id="1154">John Covan</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="11/09/1942" img="vkc.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Charlottetown (corvette) is torpedoed and sunk in the St. Lawrence</text>
            <vet id="1119">Donald McIntosh</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="13/09/1942" img="1ax.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Ottawa is torpedoed and sunk in the North Atlantic</text>
            <vet id="1138">Adeline Bowland</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="16/09/1942" img="5ux.jpg">
            <text>the first of sixteen Royal Canadian Navy corvettes sails for the Mediterranean Sea to take part in the North African landings (Operation Torch)</text>
            <vet id="1077">Harvey Burns</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="28/09/1942" img="hqt.jpg">
            <text>a No.111 Squadron aircraft, Royal Canadian Air Force, flown by S/L K.A. Boomer, destroys a Japanese ARufe@ seaplane over Kiska.  This is the only air combat fought by the RCAF in the North American theatre</text>
            <vet id="1135">Norman Dawber</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="15/10/1942" img="isp.jpg">
            <text>the Northwest Staging Route is formed as a unit to help connect Alaska and the Yukon by air with supply centres</text>
            <vet id="1506">Philip Zeman</vet>
            <vet id="1219">Bruce Agnew</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="21/10/1942" img="wow.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Royal Roads becomes the Royal Canadian Naval College and commences training cadets</text>
            <vet id="1066">Carol Duffus</vet>
            <vet id="1034">James Brown</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="29/10/1942" img="5rp.jpg">
            <text>the Canadian Intelligence Corps is authorized</text>
            <vet id="1082">Margarita Trull</vet>
            <vet id="1494">Lewis Chow</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="16/12/1942" img="qxx.jpg">
            <text>the active service battalion of the 12th Manitoba Dragoons is redesignated the "18th Armoured Car Regiment (12th Manitoba Dragoons)"</text>
            <vet id="1517">Arthur Robert Henry Lyon</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="29/12/1942" img="ksu.jpg">
            <text>HMC Ships St. Laurent, Chilliwack, Battleford and Napanee sink the German submarine U-356 in the mid-Atlantic</text>
            <vet id="1483">Henry Mason</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="3-4 January 1943" img="ylwfajesabcgzylkdrzp.jpg">
            <text>six bombers from No. 427 Squadron, Royal Canadian Air Force, carry out No.6 (RCAF) Bomber Group's first operation, laying mines near the Frisian Islands</text>
            <vet id="2212">Clinton Hayward</vet>
            <vet id="1102">Harold Bronson</vet>
            <vet id="2460">Weldon Moffatt</vet>
            <vet id="1067">Hubert Gray</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="04/01/1943" img="5tt.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Prince Henry is recommissioned as Landing Ship Infantry (Medium)</text>
            <vet id="1070">Frank Aldred</vet>
            <vet id="1080">Cyril Roach</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="05/01/1943" img="qfg.jpg">
            <text>a Canadian Army detachment arrives in North Africa</text>
            <vet id="1209">Lawrence Wagg</vet>
            <vet id="1062">Elizabeth Dimock</vet>
            <vet id="1337">Geoffrey Jell</vet>
            <vet id="1323">Andre-Paul Turin</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="13/01/1943" img="ekh.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Ville de Quebec sinks the German submarine U-224 in the western Mediterranean Sea</text>
            <vet id="1060">J.A. Rene Brunette</vet>
            <vet id="1154">John Covan</vet>
            <vet id="2387">Edwin Badger</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="19/01/1943" img="guf.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Port Arthur sinks the Italian Submarine Tritone in the Mediterranean Sea</text>
            <vet id="1077">Harvey Burns</vet>
            <vet id="2285">Warren Urquhart</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="02/02/1943" img="1xz.jpg">
            <text>the second group of Canadian troops arrive in North Africa</text>
            <vet id="1323">Andre-Paul Turin</vet>
            <vet id="2459">Oscar Fiteni</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="06/02/1943" img="gcq.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Louisbourg is torpedoed and sunk by enemy aircraft in an attack on a convoy in the Mediterranean Sea</text>
            <vet id="1138">Adeline Bowland</vet>
            <vet id="1161">George Evans</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="08/02/1943" img="mgf.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Regina sinks the Italian submarine Avorio in the Mediterranean Sea</text>
            <vet id="1119">Donald McIntosh</vet>
            <vet id="2529">Frederick Gray</vet>
            <vet id="1429">John Potter</vet>
            <vet id="1314">Jim Peters</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="22/02/1943" img="j2y.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Weyburn strikes a mine and sinks off Tangier</text>
            <vet id="2436">Alfred Carpenter</vet>
            <vet id="1398">James Smitherman</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="04/03/1943" img="w20.jpg">
            <text>HMC Ships Shediac and St. Croix sink the German submarine     U-87 in the North Atlantic</text>
            <vet id="1060">J.A. Brunette</vet>
            <vet id="1477">Donald Green</vet>
            <vet id="2298">Gordon Wright</vet>
            <vet id="2387">Edwin Badger</vet>
            <vet id="1320">Ernest Randle</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="22/04/1943" img="pkd.jpg">
            <text>the Air Cadet Corps is made a part of the Royal Canadian Air Force</text>
            <vet id="1225">Douglas Warren</vet>
            <vet id="1111">Geraldine Muter</vet>
            <vet id="1118">Brian MacConnell</vet>
            <vet id="2512">Romuald Pepin</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="30/04/1943" img="iep.jpg">
            <text>the Flag Officer Atlantic Coast, Royal Canadian Navy, takes over control of all shipping movements in the western North Atlantic under the title of Commander-in-Chief Canadian North West Atlantic</text>
            <vet id="2228">Donovan Woelfle</vet>
            <vet id="1139">John Stephen</vet>
            <vet id="1081">Jack Stapleton</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="13/05/1943" img="dez.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Drumheller, HMS Lagan and an aircraft from the Royal Canadian Air Force's 423 Squadron combine to sink the German submarine U-753 in the Atlantic Ocean</text>
            <vet id="2298">Gordon Wright</vet>
            <vet id="2387">Edwin Badger</vet>
            <vet id="1320">Ernest Randle</vet>
            <vet id="1811">Fraser Muir</vet>
            <vet id="2327">Robert O'Conner</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/06/1943" img="ybn.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Conestoga is commissioned in Galt, Ontario, as the Women's Royal Canadian Naval Service training establishment</text>
            <vet id="1066">Carol Duffus</vet>
            <vet id="1327">Olive Henderson</vet>
            <vet id="2248">Ruby Somers</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="06/06/1943" img="1il.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Prince Robert is recommissioned as an anti-aircraft cruiser</text>
            <vet id="1150">Thomas Atherton</vet>
            <vet id="1161">George Evans</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="16/06/1943" img="uqs.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Waskesiu is commissioned into the Royal Canadian Navy, becoming the first of sixty RCN frigates built in Canada</text>
            <vet id="2270">John Bilyk</vet>
            <vet id="1060">J.A Brunette</vet>
            <vet id="1452">Frank Dion</vet>
            <vet id="1527">Frank Moore</vet>
            <vet id="1821">Harold Maclauchlan</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="24/06/1943" img="j2y.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Sault Ste. Marie is commissioned as the first Algerine-class minesweeper produced for the Royal Canadian Navy</text>
            <vet id="1341">Ralph Taylor</vet>
            <vet id="1495">Bruce Findlay</vet>
            <vet id="2436">Alfred Carpenter</vet>
            <vet id="1398">James Smitherman</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="04/07/1943" img="nkr.jpg">
            <text>Canadian vessels of the 29th and 65th Motor Torpedo Boat Flotillas conduct raids on the French coast near Cherbourg</text>
            <vet id="1493">Ron Rhine</vet>
            <vet id="1398">James Smitherman</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="10/07/1943" img="smf.jpg">
            <text>Canadian landing craft drop soldiers of the 1st Canadian Division off on the coast of Sicily during the Allied invasion known as Operation Husky</text>
            <vet id="2271">John Cathie</vet>
            <vet id="2205">Leraine Munn</vet>
            <vet id="1371">Charles Ross</vet>
            <vet id="1466">Brian Murphy</vet>
            <vet id="2333">Maurice White</vet>
            <vet id="1322">Leonidas Lemaire</vet>
            <vet id="1058">Douglas Annis</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="12/07/1943" img="zey.jpg">
            <text>Flying Officer J.H. Turnbull, a No. 600 Royal Air Force Squadron Beaufighter pilot, shoots down three German Ju-88 bombers over Sicily</text>
            <vet id="1357">Alan Smith</vet>
            <vet id="2327">Robert O'Conner</vet>
            <vet id="2458">Wendell Harper</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="04/08/1943" img="53f.jpg">
            <text>a Sunderland flying boat from No. 423 Squadron, Royal Canadian Air Force, sinks the German submarine U-489</text>
            <vet id="1811">Fraser Muir</vet>
            <vet id="2327">Robert O'Conner</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="15/08/1943" img="i22.jpg">
            <text>American and Canadian forces occupy the island of Kiska in the Aleutians</text>
            <vet id="1201">Robert Atkins</vet>
            <vet id="1312">Norman Silver</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="17/08/1943" img="1t5.jpg">
            <text>the campaign in Sicily is successfully completed with the capture of the town of Messina</text>
            <vet id="1371">Charles Ross</vet>
            <vet id="2271">John Cathie</vet>
            <vet id="1322">Leonidas Lemaire</vet>
            <vet id="1058">Douglas Annis</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="03/09/1943" img="0nw.jpg">
            <text>Italy is invaded by Allied troops</text>
            <vet id="1466">Brian Murphy</vet>
            <vet id="2333">Maurice White</vet>
            <vet id="2205">Leraine Munn</vet>
            <vet id="1371">Charles Ross</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="06/09/1943" img="jxj.jpg">
            <text>beginning on this date and over the next four weeks Royal Canadian Air Force aircraft destroy four U-boats in the Atlantic Ocean</text>
            <vet id="2288">Ross Hamilton</vet>
            <vet id="2298">Gordon Wright</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="07/09/1943" img="vjf.jpg">
            <text>HMS Nabob (an aircraft carrier) is commissioned into the Royal Navy with a Canadian crew and a Royal Air Force complement</text>
            <vet id="1398">James Smitherman</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="20/09/1943" img="205.jpg">
            <text>HMCS St. Croix (a destroyer) is torpedoed and sunk south of Iceland, the first victim of an acoustic torpedo</text>
            <vet id="1220">C Alward</vet>
            <vet id="1070">Frank Aldred</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="21/10/1943" img="guf.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Chedabucto collides with the cable ship Lord Kelvin in the Gulf of St. Lawrence.  She is later beached and becomes a total loss</text>
            <vet id="2285">Warren Urquhart</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="20/11/1943" img="kgx.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Snowberry, Calgary and Nene sink U-536 in the North Atlantic</text>
            <vet id="1070">Frank Aldred</vet>
            <vet id="1161">George Evans</vet>
            <vet id="1397">Jack Smallwood</vet>
            <vet id="1060">J. A Brunette</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="20/12/1943" img="1kz.jpg">
            <text>Canadian troops begin their attack on the Italian town of Ortona, an attack successfully completed on 28 December</text>
            <vet id="1345">James Ritchie</vet>
            <vet id="1488">Arthur Brown</vet>
            <vet id="2333">Maurice White</vet>
            <vet id="1466">Brian Murphy</vet>
            <vet id="1515">Rod McNeill</vet>
            <vet id="2286">Bill Teleske</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="20/12/1943" img="gl4.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Prince David is recommissioned as a Landing Ship Infantry (Medium)</text>
            <vet id="1080">Cyril Roach</vet>
            <vet id="1070">Frank Aldred</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="23/12/1943" img="uqs.jpg">
            <text>the River Class frigate, HMCS New Glasgow, is commissioned into the Royal Canadian Navy</text>
            <vet id="1060">J.A. Brunette</vet>
            <vet id="1452">Frank Dion</vet>
            <vet id="1821">Harold MacLauchlan</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="04/01/1944" img="uho.jpg">
            <text>the Battle of the Moro River in Italy comes to an end</text>
            <vet id="2286">Bill Teleske</vet>
            <vet id="1466">Brian Murphy</vet>
            <vet id="1515">Rod McNeill</vet>
            <vet id="1488">Arthur Brown</vet>
            <vet id="2295">Rudy Deutsch</vet>
            <vet id="1071">Bernard Finestone</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="08/01/1944" img="lcf.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Camrose and HMS Bayntun sink the German submarine U-757 in the North Atlantic</text>
            <vet id="2288">Ross Hamilton</vet>
            <vet id="1161">George Evans</vet>
            <vet id="2325">Leonard Bookbinder</vet>
            <vet id="1397">Jack Smallwood</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/02/1944" img="f4s.jpg">
            <text>the Royal Canadian Electrical and Mechanical Engineers are authorized to form</text>
            <vet id="2317">Norm Jenkins</vet>
            <vet id="1527">Frank Moore</vet>
            <vet id="1532">James Fox</vet>
            <vet id="2371">Bill Baluk</vet>
            <vet id="1534">Stephen Bandurka</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="05/02/1944" img="qpk.jpg">
            <text>HMS Puncher, an aircraft carrier, is commissioned into the Royal Navy at Vancouver with a Canadian crew, but a British air complement</text>
            <vet id="1297">Norman Wrigglesworth</vet>
            <vet id="2449">Richard Clements</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="08/02/1944" img="w3y.jpg">
            <text>Canadian troops participate in Operation Veritable in the Reichswald Forest</text>
            <vet id="1702">Glenn Price</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="18/02/1944" img="2rp.jpg">
            <text>sixteen Canadian minesweepers, in four divisions of four ships, begin to leave St. John's for British waters to take part in the invasion of Normandy</text>
            <vet id="1341">Ralph Taylor</vet>
            <vet id="1495">Bruce Findlay</vet>
            <vet id="2436">Alfred Carpenter</vet>
            <vet id="1077">Harvey Burns</vet>
            <vet id="2449">Richard Clements</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="19/02/1944" img="5vv.jpg">
            <text>Motor Torpedo boats of the 29th and 65th (Canadian) Flotillas begin to be commissioned (continues until 31 March)</text>
            <vet id="1493">Ron Rhine</vet>
            <vet id="1398">James Smitherman</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="24/02/1944" img="ybi.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Waskesiu sinks the German submarine U-257 in the North Atlantic</text>
            <vet id="1161">George Evans</vet>
            <vet id="2325">Leonard Bookbinder</vet>
            <vet id="1397">Jack Smallwood</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="06/03/1944" img="myb.jpg">
            <text>HMC Ships St. Catharines, Chilliwack, Gatineau, Fennel and Chaudiere assist Royal Naval warships in the sinking of the German submarine U-744 in the North Atlantic</text>
            <vet id="1161">George Evans</vet>
            <vet id="2325">Leonard Bookbinder</vet>
            <vet id="1397">Jack Smallwood</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="10/03/1944" img="jxj.jpg">
            <text>a Sunderland aircraft from No.422 Squadron attacks and destroys the German submarine U-625</text>
            <vet id="2288">Ross Hamilton</vet>
            <vet id="2526">Mark Boivin</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="10/03/1944" img="2e1.jpg">
            <text>HMC Ships St. Laurent, Owen Sound and Swansea assist Royal Navy warships sink the German submarine U-845 in the North Atlantic</text>
            <vet id="1060">J.A. Brunette</vet>
            <vet id="1070">Frank Aldred</vet>
            <vet id="1477">Donald Green</vet>
            <vet id="2298">Gordon Wright</vet>
            <vet id="1176">Rex Fendick</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="22/03/1944" img="5ke.jpg">
            <text>the Canadian Army reaches a peak strength of 495,804 soldiers and support personnel</text>
            <vet id="2519">Marcel Caron</vet>
            <vet id="1074">Corinne Sevigney</vet>
            <vet id="1530">Eric Saunders</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="14/04/1944" img="khr.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Swansea and HMS Pelican combine to sink the German submarine U-448 in the North Atlantic</text>
            <vet id="1060">J.A Brunette</vet>
            <vet id="1314">Jim Peters</vet>
            <vet id="2387">Edwin Badger</vet>
            <vet id="1398">James Smitherman</vet>
            <vet id="2496">Clarence Sweeney</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="17/04/1944" img="fbs.jpg">
            <text>a Canso aircraft from No. 162 Squadron, Royal Canadian Air Force, sink the German submarine U-432 southwest of Iceland</text>
            <vet id="2526">Mark Boivin</vet>
            <vet id="2288">Ross Hamilton</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="29/04/1944" img="axl.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Athabaskan and Haida fight two German destroyers off Ile de Bas, France, and destroy one of them.  Athabaskan was torpedoed and sunk</text>
            <vet id="1483">Henry Mason</vet>
            <vet id="1069">Tom Rappel</vet>
            <vet id="1154">John Covan</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="07/05/1944" img="kbe.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Valleyfield, a frigate, is torpedoed and sunk by the German submarine U-548 in the Atlantic Ocean with a loss of 125 sailors</text>
            <vet id="1139">John Stephen</vet>
            <vet id="1095">Stirling Squarebriggs</vet>
            <vet id="2496">Clarence Sweeney</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="11/05/1944" img="rrj.jpg">
            <text>Allied troops make final push in Battle of Monte Cassino</text>
            <vet id="1291">Paul-Emile Lamouche</vet>
            <vet id="1380">William Adelman</vet>
            <vet id="1322">Leonidas Lemaire</vet>
            <vet id="2286">Bill Teleske</vet>
            <vet id="2686">Bruce Bullock</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="24/05/1944" img="2ah.jpg">
            <text>1st Canadian Division breaks through the Hitler Line</text>
            <vet id="1515">Rod McNeill</vet>
            <vet id="1473">Nigel Taylor</vet>
            <vet id="2286">Bill Teleske</vet>
            <vet id="2356">Roy Page</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="05/06/1944" img="j2y.jpg">
            <text>sixteen Royal Canadian Navy minesweepers help clear the English Channel in preparation for the D-Day landings</text>
            <vet id="1341">Ralph Taylor</vet>
            <vet id="1495">Bruce Findlay</vet>
            <vet id="2436">Alfred Carpenter</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="06/06/1944" img="hwp.jpg">
            <text>approximately one hundred and ten Canadian warships participate in the Allied landings in Normandy</text>
            <vet id="1375">Okill Stuart</vet>
            <vet id="1043">Jan de Vries</vet>
            <vet id="1226">Joseph Hawkins</vet>
            <vet id="1376">George Mann</vet>
            <vet id="1371">Charles Ross</vet>
            <vet id="2169">Leo Pikulski</vet>
            <vet id="2318">Joseph Sullivan</vet>
            <vet id="2384">Catherine Anderson</vet>
            <vet id="1252">Charles Owens</vet>
            <vet id="2381">Alfred Warford</vet>
            <vet id="1199">Fred Allison</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="09/06/1944" img="uqs.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Haida, HMCS Huron and other destroyers from the 10th Destroyer Flotilla sink the German destroyers ZH1 and Z32 in the English Channel</text>
            <vet id="1069">Tom Rappel</vet>
            <vet id="1060">J.A Brunette</vet>
            <vet id="2298">Gordon Wright</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="24/06/1944" img="gnj.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Haida, HMS Eskimo and a Royal Air Force patrol aircraft sink the German submarine U-971 in the English Channel</text>
            <vet id="1069">Tom Rappel</vet>
            <vet id="2526">Mark Boivin</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="24/06/1944" img="ndumhotsllqeheidlvhc.jpg">
            <text>Flight Lieutenant David Hornell, a Canso pilot with 162 Squadron, Royal Canadian Air Force, sinks the German submarine U-1225.  Hornell's aircraft is also brought down and Hornell dies as a result of his injuries.  He is awarded a posthumous Victoria Cross</text>
            <vet id="2526">Mark Boivin</vet>
            <vet id="2288">Ross Hamilton</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="27/06/1944" img="rjn.jpg">
            <text>No. 143 (Typhoon) Wing aircraft, while still based in England, begin using new airstrips in Normandy to rearm and refuel</text>
            <vet id="1135">Norman Dawber</vet>
            <vet id="1147">John Slater</vet>
            <vet id="2369">Archie Stover</vet>
            <vet id="1176">Rex Fendick</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="06/07/1944" img="ees.jpg">
            <text>HMC Ships Ottawa and Kootenay, along with HMS Statice, sink the German submarine U-678 while on patrol in the English Channel</text>
            <vet id="2298">Gordon Wright</vet>
            <vet id="1314">Jim Peters</vet>
            <vet id="1320">Ernest Randle</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="18/07/1944" img="lg2.jpg">
            <text>Canadian 3rd Division advances through the city of Caen as part of Operation Greenwood</text>
            <vet id="2243">Fred Bryant</vet>
            <vet id="2220">Allan MacDonald</vet>
            <vet id="2318">Joseph Sullivan</vet>
            <vet id="2381">Alfred Warford</vet>
            <vet id="1252">Charles Owens</vet>
            <vet id="2273">Sol Zulauf</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="19/07/1944" img="xjo.jpg">
            <text>Canadian troops begin engagements on Verrieres Ridge, suffering large casualties</text>
            <vet id="1142">Kenneth Wootton</vet>
            <vet id="2220">Allan MacDonald</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="08/08/1944" img="mum.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Regina is torpedoed and sunk by the German submarine U-667 off the coast of France</text>
            <vet id="1429">John Potter</vet>
            <vet id="1314">Jim Peters</vet>
            <vet id="1119">Donald MacIntosh</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="15/08/1944" img="w3u.jpg">
            <text>HMC Ships Prince David and Prince Henry participate in the Allied landing in southern France, codenamed Operation Dragoon</text>
            <vet id="1070">Frank Aldred</vet>
            <vet id="2333">Maurice White</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="18/08/1944" img="pct.jpg">
            <text>HMC Ships Ottawa, Kootenay and Chaudiere sink the German submarine U-621 while on patrol in the Bay of Biscay</text>
            <vet id="1314">Jim Peters</vet>
            <vet id="2496">Clarence Sweeney</vet>
            <vet id="1060">J.A Brunette</vet>
            <vet id="1220">C Alward</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="18/08/1944" img="t2r.jpg">
            <text>Major David V. Currie, with the 29th Armoured Reconnaissance Regiment (South Alberta Regiment), is awarded the Victoria Cross for his work in the Falaise Pocket</text>
            <vet id="1142">Kenneth Wootton</vet>
            <vet id="1501">Douglas Storey</vet>
            <vet id="2220">Allan MacDonald</vet>
            <vet id="2169">Leo Pikulski</vet>
            <vet id="2318">Jospeh Sullivan</vet>
            <vet id="1252">Charles Owens</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="20/08/1944" img="bzt.jpg">
            <text>HMC Ships Ottawa, Kootenay and Chaudiere sink the German submarine U-984 while on patrol in the English Channel B their second combined victory in three days</text>
            <vet id="2601">John Kubis</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="21/08/1944" img="5r0.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Alberni is torpedoed and sunk by the German submarine U-480 in the English Channel</text>
            <vet id="1216">Murray Copot</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="22/08/1944" img="3cg.jpg">
            <text>HMS Nabob, a British aircraft carrier with a Royal Canadian Navy crew, is torpedoed in the North Sea and severely damaged</text>
            <vet id="1138">Adeline Bowland</vet>
            <vet id="1119">Donald MacIntosh</vet>
            <vet id="1297">Norman Wrigglesworth</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/09/1944" img="sqb.jpg">
            <text>Dieppe is occupied by Canadian troops</text>
            <vet id="1092">Edward Borland</vet>
            <vet id="2374">Vernon Barr</vet>
            <vet id="2329">William Rawluk</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="01/09/1944" img="dez.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Saint John and HMCS Swansea sink the German submarine U-247 off Land's End, England</text>
            <vet id="1320">Ernest Randle</vet>
            <vet id="1527">Frank Moore</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="09/09/1944" img="lus.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Dunver and HMCS Hespeler sink the German submarine U-484 in Hebridean waters</text>
            <vet id="1452">Frank Dion</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="17/09/1944" img="azu.jpg">
            <text>No.437 (Dakota) Squadron participates in Operation Market Garden, the airborne landings at Eindhoven, by towing gliders and dropping supplies</text>
            <vet id="1145">Anatole Cote</vet>
            <vet id="1158">Walter Haydon</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="30/09/1944" img="5ry.jpg">
            <text>Calais is captured by Canadian forces</text>
            <vet id="1797">John Charlwood</vet>
            <vet id="2173">Herb Harris</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="05/10/1944" img="pkd.jpg">
            <text>pilots from No.401 Squadron, RCAF, destroy a German Me-262, becoming the first jet-propelled aircraft shot down by the Royal Air Force or the Royal Canadian Air Force</text>
            <vet id="1118">Brian MacConnell</vet>
            <vet id="1165">Ed Green</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="06/10/1944" img="ps4.jpg">
            <text>No.6 (RCAF) Group, Bomber Command, deploys its largest sortie of the war with 523 aircraft involved</text>
            <vet id="1307">Malcolm MacConnell</vet>
            <vet id="1294">William Kondra</vet>
            <vet id="1481">Kenneth France</vet>
            <vet id="2319">Fred Guest</vet>
            <vet id="1357">Allan Smith</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="08/10/1944" img="wi1.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Mulgrave strikes a mine off Le Havre, is beached and becomes a total loss</text>
            <vet id="1483">Henry Mason</vet>
            <vet id="1161">George Evans</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="14/10/1944" img="31q.jpg">
            <text>within a period of sixteen hours No.6 (RCAF) Group, Bomber Command, flies a total of 501 Lancaster and Halifax bombers against targets in Duisburg, Germany</text>
            <vet id="2293">Steve Boczar</vet>
            <vet id="2371">Bill Baluk</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="16/10/1944" img="vjf.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Annan sinks the German submarine U-1006 south of the Faeroes</text>
            <vet id="2387">Edwin Badger</vet>
            <vet id="1398">James Smitherman</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="17-18 October 1944" img="vdq.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Prince Henry and HMCS Prince David engage in landing liberation forces in Greece</text>
            <vet id="1477">Donald Green</vet>
            <vet id="1070">Frank Aldred</vet>
            <vet id="2356">Roy Page</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="??" img="zba.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Uganda (later Quebec) is commissioned, becoming</text>
            <vet id="1290">Bill Hembroff</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="25/10/1944" img="m5a.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Skeena becomes stranded near Reykjavik, Iceland, becoming a total loss</text>
            <vet id="2525">George Charrier</vet>
            <vet id="1397">Jack Smallwood</vet>
            <vet id="1070">Frank Aldred</vet>
            <vet id="2193">Leslie Clarke</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="08/11/1944" img="dwt.jpg">
            <text>end of the Battle of the Scheldt</text>
            <vet id="1061">Bill Davis</vet>
            <vet id="1107">Arthur Webster</vet>
            <vet id="1270">David Havard</vet>
            <vet id="1371">Charles Ross</vet>
            <vet id="2374">Vernon Barr</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="15/11/1944" img="tl0.jpg">
            <text>the Aircraft Detection Corps of civilian volunteer observers is disbanded</text>
            <vet id="1158">Walter Hayman</vet>
            <vet id="2480">Cyril Hammond</vet>
            <vet id="1340">Gordon Partridge</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="25/11/1944" img="uqs.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Shawinigan is torpedoed by a German submarine in Cabot Strait and sunk with all hands</text>
            <vet id="1060">J.A Brunette</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="10/12/1944" img="ivhukbgzvslsoplcttex.jpg">
            <text>Canadian troops storm the Lamone River defences in Italy</text>
            <vet id="1333">Raymond Lewis</vet>
            <vet id="1515">Rod McNeill</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="24/12/1944" img="w20.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Clayoquot is torpedoed by a U-boat and sinks in the Halifax approaches</text>
            <vet id="1060">J.A Brunette</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="27/12/1944" img="a42.jpg">
            <text>HMCS St. Thomas sinks the German submarine U-877 in the North Atlantic</text>
            <vet id="2298">Gordon Wright</vet>
            <vet id="1452">Frank Dion</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="29/12/1944" img="3bx.jpg">
            <text>Flight-Lieutenant R.J. Audet, No.411 Squadron, Royal Canadian Air Force, shoots down five German fighters during a patrol in the Rhine area</text>
            <vet id="2681">Gordon Redcliffe</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="30/12/1944" img="uhd.jpg">
            <text>Second-Lieutenant C.J.W. Taylor, No.407 Squadron, Royal Canadian Air Force, sinks the German submarine U-772 with depth charges</text>
            <vet id="1500">Albert Sanderson</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="09/01/1945" img="qpk.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Ehkoli, a former Royal Canadian Navy patrol boat, is recommissioned in the RCN as a survey vessel</text>
            <vet id="2449">Richard Clements?</vet>
            <vet id="1081">Jack Stapleton</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="15/01/1945" img="evb.jpg">
            <text>Nos.1 and 3 Training Commands, Royal Canadian Air Force, are disbanded and replaced by No.1 Air Command with headquarters at Trenton, Ontario</text>
            <vet id="1226">Joseph Hawkins</vet>
            <vet id="1465">Ruby Foley</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="05/02/1945" img="2ck.jpg">
            <text>No.9 (Transport) Group, Royal Canadian Air Force, is formed to control air transport within the air force</text>
            <vet id="2366">Harold Ward</vet>
            <vet id="2359">Jim Venables</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="08/02/1945" img="e2a.jpg">
            <text>First Canadian Army opens an offensive at the north end of the German Siegfried Line southeast of Nijmegen in order to clear the area between the Maas and Rhine rivers</text>
            <vet id="1073">John Forbes</vet>
            <vet id="1838">Bruce Cox</vet>
            <vet id="1062">Elizabeth Dimock</vet>
            <vet id="1256">Wilbergt Prentice</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="13/02/1945" img="fiykluaiakfpkuxzffbv.jpg">
            <text>Canadian troops capture the town of Cleve in Germany</text>
            <vet id="2513">Emile Turcot</vet>
            <vet id="2533">Gerald Derick</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="14/02/1945" img="wi1.jpg">
            <text>five Motor Torpedo Boats of the Canadian 29th Flotilla burn in Ostende harbour</text>
            <vet id="1161">George Evans</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="16/02/1945" img="jsj.jpg">
            <text>HMCS St. John sinks the German submarine U-309 off the northeast coast of Scotland</text>
            <vet id="1320">Ernest Randle</vet>
            <vet id="1527">Frank Moore</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="22/02/1945" img="ksu.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Trentonian is torpedoed and sunk by a German submarine in the English Channel</text>
            <vet id="1139">John Stephen</vet>
            <vet id="1483">Henry Mason</vet>
            <vet id="1070">Frank Aldred</vet>
            <vet id="2298">Gordon Wright</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="09/03/1945" img="ibt.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Uganda arrives in Sydney, Australia, to join the British Pacific Fleet</text>
            <vet id="2137">Louis Howard</vet>
            <vet id="2737">Terence Elworthy</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="15/03/1945" img="213.jpg">
            <text>the First Canadian Corps takes over the sector along the Waal River in Holland upon its arrival from the Italian theatre of war.  As a result, both Canadian corps now form part of the First Canadian Army</text>
            <vet id="1384">Gordon Bannerman</vet>
            <vet id="2271">John Cathie</vet>
            <vet id="2499">Joan Manning</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="17/03/1945" img="ewr.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Guysborough is torpedoed and sunk by a German U-boat off Ushant</text>
            <vet id="1070">Frank Aldred</vet>
            <vet id="1483">Henry Mason</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="20/03/1945" img="ees.jpg">
            <text>HMCS New Glasgow sinks the German submarine U-1003 off Lough Foyle, Northern Ireland</text>
            <vet id="2298">Gordon Wright</vet>
            <vet id="1452">Frank Dion</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="24/03/1945" img="zim.jpg">
            <text>Corporal F.G. Topham, Royal Canadian Army Medical Corps, is awarded the Victoria Cross for his actions in support of 1st Canadian Parachute Battalion east of the Rhine River, Germany</text>
            <vet id="2369">Archie Stover</vet>
            <vet id="2160">Hewitt Quick</vet>
            <vet id="2230">Joan Johnson nee Cobb</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="31/03/1945" img="wow.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Conestoga, the Women's Royal Canadian Naval Service training establishment, is paid off</text>
            <vet id="1066">Carol Duffus</vet>
            <vet id="1327">Olive Henderson</vet>
            <vet id="2248">Ruby Somers</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="03/04/1945" img="2u4.jpg">
            <text>the First Canadian Army crosses the Rhine and captures the town of Zevenaar, and reaches the town of Zutphen</text>
            <vet id="1317">Jean Marie Milot</vet>
            <vet id="1079">John Springer</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="04/04/1945" img="lls.jpg">
            <text>the First Canadian Army clears out the town of Almelo</text>
            <vet id="1096">Hubert Lalonde</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="15/04/1945" img="b0i.jpg">
            <text>the First Canadian Army reaches the Dutch coast near Leeuwarden</text>
            <vet id="1517">Arthur Lyon</vet>
            <vet id="1043">Jan de Vries</vet>
            <vet id="1224">Doris Wallace</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="16/04/1945" img="4zr.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Esquimalt is torpoeded and sunk in the waters off of Halifax</text>
            <vet id="2137">Louis Howard</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="26/04/1945" img="ycn.jpg">
            <text>HMCS Ontario, a cruiser, is commissioned</text>
            <vet id="1216">Murray Copot</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="04/05/1945" img="usj.jpg">
            <text>the cruiser HMCS Uganda sails with an American task force to bombard Japanese airfields as part of the Okinawa campaign</text>
            <vet id="2520">Geoffrey Knowles</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="05/05/1945" img="wwd.jpg">
            <text>units of the First Canadian Army accept the surrender of German forces at Bad Zwischenahn, Germany</text>
            <vet id="2523">Jean-Paul Bertrand</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="07/05/1945" img="wak.jpg">
            <text>All German military forces surrender to the Allied Forces in Europe</text>
            <vet id="2374">Vernon Barr</vet>
            <vet id="1515">Rod McNeill</vet>
            <vet id="1735">Rex Rose</vet>
        </event>

        <event date="02/08/1945" img="wgx.jpg">
            <text>the prefix ‘Royal’ is granted for the Canadian Armoured Corps by the King</text>
            <vet id="1092">Edward Borland</vet>
            <vet id="1473">Nigel Taylor</vet>
        </event>

    </events>
    
</timelineData>